1
00:06:56,750 --> 00:07:01,754
- Got any biscuits over there?
- Here's some cornbread.

2
00:07:04,382 --> 00:07:06,092
I am cold.

3
00:07:06,259 --> 00:07:09,053
- Still with us, Brett?
- Right.

4
00:07:09,221 --> 00:07:14,308
- I feel dead.
- Anybody ever telI you you Iook dead?

5
00:07:17,729 --> 00:07:21,273
Oh, yeah. I forgot something.

6
00:07:21,441 --> 00:07:25,486
Before we dock,
we ought to discuss the bonus situation.

7
00:07:25,654 --> 00:07:28,823
Brett and l think we deserve full shares.

8
00:07:28,990 --> 00:07:33,702
Mr Parker and I feel the bonus situation
has never been equitable.

9
00:07:33,870 --> 00:07:37,123
You get what you're contracted for,
like everybody else.

10
00:07:37,290 --> 00:07:39,542
But everybody else gets more than us.

11
00:07:39,709 --> 00:07:42,336
DalIas, Mother wants to talk to you.

12
00:07:42,504 --> 00:07:46,465
I saw it. YelIow light's for my eyes onIy.

13
00:07:46,716 --> 00:07:49,343
Get dressed, huh? Parker?

14
00:07:49,511 --> 00:07:52,847
I haven't finished my coffee.
It's the only good thing we got.

15
00:08:49,070 --> 00:08:50,654
Morning, Mother.

16
00:09:21,394 --> 00:09:23,979
- Right?
- OK.

17
00:09:24,147 --> 00:09:26,357
Plug us in.

18
00:09:27,442 --> 00:09:29,526
Thank you.

19
00:09:32,948 --> 00:09:36,325
- Where is Earth?
- You shouId know.

20
00:09:37,202 --> 00:09:39,495
It's not our system.

21
00:09:39,663 --> 00:09:41,288
Scan.

22
00:09:44,626 --> 00:09:46,502
I can't believe this.

23
00:09:46,670 --> 00:09:49,338
Contact traffic controI.

24
00:09:50,048 --> 00:09:53,175
This is commercial towing vehicle
<i>Nostromo,</i>

25
00:09:53,343 --> 00:09:58,514
out of the Solomons,
registration number 1 80924609,

26
00:09:58,682 --> 00:10:03,143
calling Antarctica traffic controI.
Do you read me?

27
00:10:03,311 --> 00:10:06,438
CommerciaI towing vehicle <i>Nostromo</i>,
out of the Solomons,

28
00:10:06,606 --> 00:10:11,527
registration number 1 80924609.

29
00:10:13,196 --> 00:10:14,822
- Nothing.
- Keep trying.

30
00:10:14,948 --> 00:10:19,868
CalIing Antarctica traffic control.
Do you read me, Antarctica?

31
00:10:20,036 --> 00:10:24,498
I've found it. Just short of Zeta II Reticuli.

32
00:10:24,666 --> 00:10:29,545
- We haven't reached the outer rim yet.
- That's hard to beIieve.

33
00:10:29,713 --> 00:10:32,589
What the helI are we doing out here?

34
00:10:34,009 --> 00:10:37,011
Don't know.
What the helI are you talking about?

35
00:10:37,178 --> 00:10:40,514
- That's not our system.
- I know that.

36
00:10:40,682 --> 00:10:46,729
Ever notice how they never come down
here? This is where the work is, right?

37
00:10:46,896 --> 00:10:53,360
Same reason we get a half share to their
one. Our time is their time. Same old shit.

38
00:10:53,528 --> 00:10:55,863
I think l know why they don't come down.

39
00:10:56,031 --> 00:10:58,699
It's because of you.
You have no personality.

40
00:11:06,041 --> 00:11:11,462
- You happen to be in my seat. Can l have it?
- Of course. Sorry.

41
00:11:16,801 --> 00:11:19,428
What's happening now, baby?

42
00:11:20,638 --> 00:11:26,060
Some of you may have figured out we're
not home yet. We're onIy halfway there.

43
00:11:27,062 --> 00:11:30,606
- What?
- Mother's interrupted our course.

44
00:11:30,774 --> 00:11:31,774
Why?

45
00:11:31,941 --> 00:11:36,487
She's programmed to do that
should certain conditions arise. They have.

46
00:11:36,654 --> 00:11:41,366
It seems she has intercepted
a transmission of unknown origin.

47
00:11:41,534 --> 00:11:45,454
- She got us up to check it out.
- A transmission? Out here?

48
00:11:45,622 --> 00:11:47,498
What kind of transmission?

49
00:11:47,665 --> 00:11:51,376
Acoustical beacon
that repeats at intervaIs of 1 2 seconds.

50
00:11:51,544 --> 00:11:53,253
- SOS?
- I don't know.

51
00:11:53,421 --> 00:11:56,298
- Human?
- Unknown.

52
00:11:56,466 --> 00:12:00,260
- So what?
- We are obligated under Section...

53
00:12:00,428 --> 00:12:05,724
- This is a commerciaI ship, not a rescue ship.
- Right.

54
00:12:05,892 --> 00:12:08,727
It's not in my contract, this kind of duty.

55
00:12:08,895 --> 00:12:13,565
And what about money? Give me
some money, l'd be happy to oblige.

56
00:12:13,733 --> 00:12:16,443
Let's go over the bonus situation.

57
00:12:16,611 --> 00:12:19,154
I'm sorry, can I say something?

58
00:12:19,322 --> 00:12:23,283
There is a clause which states
"Any systematised transmission

59
00:12:23,451 --> 00:12:26,745
indicating intelIigent origin
must be investigated...

60
00:12:26,913 --> 00:12:29,164
I wanna go home and party.

61
00:12:29,332 --> 00:12:31,625
Will you just Iisten to the man?

62
00:12:33,628 --> 00:12:37,506
..on penalty of total forfeiture of shares."

63
00:12:37,674 --> 00:12:39,049
No money.

64
00:12:39,676 --> 00:12:42,136
You got that?

65
00:12:42,303 --> 00:12:45,013
- WeIl, yeah.
- We're going in.

66
00:12:45,181 --> 00:12:46,932
We're going in.

67
00:12:54,107 --> 00:12:58,068
Approaching orbitaI apogee. Mark.

68
00:13:01,489 --> 00:13:03,073
Equatorial orbit naiIed.

69
00:13:18,464 --> 00:13:20,215
DOR's in line.

70
00:13:20,383 --> 00:13:24,219
- Status on the Iifters?
- Give me an AC pressure reading.

71
00:13:30,643 --> 00:13:33,353
48 seconds and counting.

72
00:13:36,024 --> 00:13:38,609
Prepare to disengage from pIatform.

73
00:13:38,776 --> 00:13:40,777
20 seconds.

74
00:13:40,945 --> 00:13:43,488
1 8, 1 7...

75
00:13:43,656 --> 00:13:50,537
1 3, 1 2, 1 1 , 1 0, 9, 8, 7,

76
00:13:50,705 --> 00:13:56,335
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1 .

77
00:13:56,502 --> 00:13:57,878
Lock.

78
00:13:58,046 --> 00:13:59,880
Disengage.

79
00:14:04,969 --> 00:14:06,178
CIear.

80
00:14:11,809 --> 00:14:14,811
Money's safe.
Let's take her down.

81
00:14:22,487 --> 00:14:26,448
- Roll 92 degrees, port yaw.
- Prime the port.

82
00:14:55,561 --> 00:14:58,397
I'm not getting anything.

83
00:15:05,071 --> 00:15:07,155
Turbulence.

84
00:15:15,248 --> 00:15:18,417
Locked and floating.
You can drop us any time now.

85
00:15:18,584 --> 00:15:23,463
Initial damping's going off.
Hold on, there'll be a little bump.

86
00:15:29,929 --> 00:15:32,264
What the helI was that?

87
00:15:32,432 --> 00:15:34,850
Pressure drop. Must have lost a shield.

88
00:15:35,018 --> 00:15:36,685
Let's go with it.

89
00:15:36,853 --> 00:15:40,355
I'm still not getting anything.

90
00:15:46,195 --> 00:15:48,739
Dropping off now.

91
00:15:48,906 --> 00:15:50,949
StiIl dropping.

92
00:15:52,285 --> 00:15:54,578
There we are, we've got it.

93
00:15:54,746 --> 00:15:56,788
Take her down.

94
00:16:03,463 --> 00:16:05,589
Navigation Iights on.

95
00:16:39,582 --> 00:16:42,793
9, 8, 7...

96
00:16:42,960 --> 00:16:48,507
6, 5, 4, 3, 2,

97
00:16:48,674 --> 00:16:50,509
1 .

98
00:16:50,676 --> 00:16:52,719
Kill drive engines.

99
00:17:12,240 --> 00:17:14,866
What the helI happened?

100
00:17:16,244 --> 00:17:18,078
Give me an answer.

101
00:17:18,246 --> 00:17:22,207
- Is the hull breached?
- I don't see anything. We still have pressure.

102
00:17:22,375 --> 00:17:25,961
- Push the screen.
- Why?

103
00:17:33,761 --> 00:17:38,890
Secondary load-sharing unit is out.

104
00:17:39,058 --> 00:17:41,977
Three of the four cells are gone.

105
00:17:44,397 --> 00:17:47,566
- Is that it?
- No, hold on.

106
00:17:47,733 --> 00:17:53,113
We can't fix it out here anyway
and we need to reroute a coupIe of ducts.

107
00:17:53,281 --> 00:17:54,573
Dry-dock time.

108
00:17:54,740 --> 00:17:56,867
TeIl him to dry-dock.

109
00:17:57,034 --> 00:18:01,163
We can't fix it out here.
We've gotta reroute aIl these ducts.

110
00:18:01,330 --> 00:18:03,748
To do that, we've got to dry-dock.

111
00:18:04,208 --> 00:18:05,834
What eIse?

112
00:18:06,002 --> 00:18:10,422
Some fragments caked up. We've got
to cIean it out and repressurise it.

113
00:18:10,590 --> 00:18:13,133
How Iong before we're functional?

114
00:18:13,301 --> 00:18:16,636
- Look...
- 1 7 hours, tell her.

115
00:18:17,722 --> 00:18:20,474
At least 25 hours.

116
00:18:20,641 --> 00:18:22,934
Get started. I'll be right down.

117
00:18:23,102 --> 00:18:26,605
- Why's she coming down here?
- She better stay the fuck out of my way.

118
00:18:26,772 --> 00:18:29,357
I'd like to see what she's gonna do
when she gets here.

119
00:18:39,785 --> 00:18:41,828
Any response yet?

120
00:18:41,996 --> 00:18:47,125
AbsoIutely nothing, except
the same transmission every 1 2 seconds.

121
00:18:47,293 --> 00:18:50,045
All the other channels are dead.

122
00:18:54,967 --> 00:18:57,135
Kick on the floods.

123
00:19:11,776 --> 00:19:14,402
We can't go anywhere in this.

124
00:19:15,613 --> 00:19:18,031
Mother says the sun rises in 20 minutes.

125
00:19:18,199 --> 00:19:24,120
- How far to the source of transmission?
- Northeast. Just under 2,000 metres.

126
00:19:24,288 --> 00:19:26,581
WaIking distance?

127
00:19:28,501 --> 00:19:32,462
- Can you give me an atmospheric?
- Yes.

128
00:19:38,803 --> 00:19:40,929
It's almost primordiaI.

129
00:19:41,514 --> 00:19:46,434
Inert nitrogen, high concentration
of carbon dioxide crystals, methane...

130
00:19:46,602 --> 00:19:49,604
- I'm working on the trace elements.
- Anything else?

131
00:19:49,772 --> 00:19:53,692
There's rock, lava base.

132
00:19:56,112 --> 00:19:59,030
Deep cold, welI below the Iine.

133
00:20:00,449 --> 00:20:03,201
I'Il volunteer to be in the first group
to go out.

134
00:20:03,369 --> 00:20:05,996
That figures.

135
00:20:06,163 --> 00:20:10,208
- You, too, Lambert.
- SweIl.

136
00:20:10,376 --> 00:20:14,129
You'd better break out the weapons.

137
00:21:27,119 --> 00:21:33,041
- I can't see a goddamn thing.
- Ash, are you receiving?

138
00:21:37,838 --> 00:21:40,215
Good contact on my board.

139
00:21:40,383 --> 00:21:44,511
CIear and free. Keep the line open.
Let's go.

140
00:21:58,859 --> 00:22:01,778
Hey, Ripley.

141
00:22:01,946 --> 00:22:05,532
I want to ask you a question.

142
00:22:05,700 --> 00:22:08,993
If they find what they're after,
do we get fuIl shares?

143
00:22:09,161 --> 00:22:13,289
Don't worry,
you'lI get whatever's coming to you.

144
00:22:13,457 --> 00:22:17,502
I'm not doing any more work
untiI we get this straightened out.

145
00:22:17,670 --> 00:22:21,923
Brett, you're guaranteed by law
to get a share.

146
00:22:22,091 --> 00:22:24,926
- What?
- Why don't you just fuck off?

147
00:22:25,094 --> 00:22:28,513
- What?
- What did you say?

148
00:22:28,681 --> 00:22:33,059
If you have any trouble,
I'Il be on the bridge.

149
00:22:33,227 --> 00:22:36,312
Come back here.

150
00:22:41,277 --> 00:22:44,904
- Son of a bitch.
- What's the matter?

151
00:22:53,873 --> 00:22:56,332
Can't see a goddamn thing.

152
00:22:56,500 --> 00:22:58,501
Quit griping.

153
00:22:58,669 --> 00:23:01,337
- I like griping.
- Knock it off.

154
00:23:13,934 --> 00:23:15,810
How's it going?

155
00:23:17,438 --> 00:23:21,191
- All right.
- You put that transmission through ECIU?

156
00:23:21,358 --> 00:23:24,277
No. Mother hasn't identified it yet.

157
00:23:24,445 --> 00:23:27,864
- Mind if I give it a shot?
- Please do.

158
00:24:44,149 --> 00:24:47,777
- Ash, can you see this?
- I can.

159
00:24:50,906 --> 00:24:53,783
I've never seen anything like it.

160
00:25:01,792 --> 00:25:04,168
It's very bizarre.

161
00:25:18,392 --> 00:25:20,351
All right.

162
00:25:20,519 --> 00:25:23,563
Moving on to second position.

163
00:25:23,731 --> 00:25:25,773
What is it?

164
00:25:28,027 --> 00:25:29,986
Let's get outta here.

165
00:25:30,154 --> 00:25:33,656
We've got this far. We have to go on.

166
00:25:37,786 --> 00:25:40,288
Will you say that again?

167
00:25:40,456 --> 00:25:41,456
Shit.

168
00:25:42,833 --> 00:25:46,794
As you can see, it's hard to describe.

169
00:25:46,962 --> 00:25:49,547
I'm going back to the consoIe.

170
00:26:42,559 --> 00:26:43,935
DalIas?

171
00:27:43,412 --> 00:27:46,873
Come on down here.
There's something different.

172
00:27:47,040 --> 00:27:53,004
I don't know what it is, but if we can
get up that walI, we can find out.

173
00:29:04,326 --> 00:29:07,662
Alien life form.

174
00:29:07,830 --> 00:29:10,832
It looks like it's been dead a long time.

175
00:29:10,999 --> 00:29:13,501
FossiIised.

176
00:29:13,669 --> 00:29:16,963
Looks like it's grown out of the chair.

177
00:29:32,646 --> 00:29:34,772
Bones are bent outward.

178
00:29:34,940 --> 00:29:37,942
Like he exploded from inside.

179
00:29:42,447 --> 00:29:46,075
Wonder what happened
to the rest of the crew.

180
00:29:50,080 --> 00:29:52,790
Let's get the helI outta here.

181
00:30:04,177 --> 00:30:05,595
Hey, Dallas.

182
00:30:05,762 --> 00:30:08,931
Lambert, come on over here.

183
00:30:09,933 --> 00:30:11,601
Come on.

184
00:30:19,818 --> 00:30:23,779
- What have you got?
- See what you make of this.

185
00:30:31,246 --> 00:30:35,416
Ash, that transmission.
Mother's deciphered part of it.

186
00:30:35,584 --> 00:30:38,336
- It doesn't look like an SOS.
- What is it, then?

187
00:30:38,503 --> 00:30:41,756
It looks like a warning.

188
00:30:41,924 --> 00:30:45,968
- I'm gonna go out after them.
- What's the point?

189
00:30:47,429 --> 00:30:53,184
By the time it takes to get there,
they'lI know if it's a warning or not.

190
00:31:20,295 --> 00:31:23,005
Are you OK down there?

191
00:31:26,510 --> 00:31:32,640
- Can you see anything?
- A cave of some sort, but l...

192
00:31:35,227 --> 00:31:38,604
It's Iike the goddamn tropics in here.

193
00:31:41,108 --> 00:31:43,734
What the helI is this?

194
00:32:20,313 --> 00:32:23,399
The pit is completely enclosed.

195
00:32:23,567 --> 00:32:29,280
It's fulI of Ieathery objects,
like eggs or something.

196
00:32:47,632 --> 00:32:53,554
There's a layer of mist covering the eggs
that reacts when broken.

197
00:32:57,392 --> 00:33:00,269
Kane? Are you all right?

198
00:33:00,437 --> 00:33:02,521
I'm OK.

199
00:33:05,317 --> 00:33:07,693
I'm OK. l just slipped.

200
00:33:27,756 --> 00:33:30,883
It appears to be completely sealed.

201
00:33:56,118 --> 00:33:59,745
Wait, there's movement.

202
00:33:59,913 --> 00:34:03,582
It seems to have organic life.

203
00:35:08,648 --> 00:35:11,108
- Are you there, RipIey?
- I'm here.

204
00:35:17,407 --> 00:35:20,701
- I'm at the inner Iock hatch.
- Right.

205
00:35:30,378 --> 00:35:33,214
Are you there?
We're clean, let us in.

206
00:35:33,381 --> 00:35:37,051
- What happened to Kane?
- Something attached itself to him.

207
00:35:37,219 --> 00:35:39,720
What kind of thing?

208
00:35:39,888 --> 00:35:42,056
An organism. Open the hatch.

209
00:35:42,224 --> 00:35:46,560
If we let it in, the ship could be infected.
You know the quarantine procedure.

210
00:35:46,728 --> 00:35:50,397
- 24 hours for decontamination.
- He couId die. Open the hatch.

211
00:35:50,565 --> 00:35:53,359
If we break quarantine, we could aIl die.

212
00:35:53,526 --> 00:35:57,863
Can you open the goddamn hatch?
We have to get him inside.

213
00:35:59,407 --> 00:36:01,325
No, I can't do that.

214
00:36:01,493 --> 00:36:03,244
If you were in my position
you'd do the same.

215
00:36:03,411 --> 00:36:06,330
This is an order.
Open that hatch, do you hear me?

216
00:36:06,498 --> 00:36:07,790
Yes.

217
00:36:07,958 --> 00:36:12,711
- This is an order! Do you hear me?
- I read you. The answer is negative.

218
00:36:16,258 --> 00:36:18,676
Inner hatch open.

219
00:36:45,620 --> 00:36:47,329
My God.

220
00:36:57,799 --> 00:36:59,967
What the helI is that?

221
00:37:02,012 --> 00:37:03,637
How is he?

222
00:37:06,391 --> 00:37:09,226
How are we gonna get that off him?

223
00:37:09,394 --> 00:37:14,064
- How do we get it off?
- Just a minute. l'll get some instruments.

224
00:37:21,031 --> 00:37:24,908
Right. If l make an incision here

225
00:37:25,076 --> 00:37:28,370
to try and remove
one of the digits from his face...

226
00:37:28,538 --> 00:37:30,414
You're gonna do what?

227
00:37:30,582 --> 00:37:33,584
Finger. I'll try and get this finger off.

228
00:37:33,752 --> 00:37:36,503
Get this cIeating on there...

229
00:37:39,507 --> 00:37:42,509
- It's tearing his scalp.
- I know.

230
00:37:43,595 --> 00:37:46,513
It's not coming off
without tearing his face off with it.

231
00:37:47,515 --> 00:37:49,975
We'lI have to take a look at him inside.

232
00:37:52,228 --> 00:37:55,105
How come they don't freeze him?

233
00:37:55,273 --> 00:37:58,233
How come you guys don't freeze him?

234
00:38:13,875 --> 00:38:16,502
You can take your mask off.

235
00:38:34,729 --> 00:38:40,234
- What's it got down his throat?
- I suggest it's feeding him oxygen.

236
00:38:40,401 --> 00:38:45,239
ParaIyses him, puts him in a coma,
then keeps him aIive.

237
00:38:45,406 --> 00:38:48,200
What the helI is that?

238
00:38:48,368 --> 00:38:51,995
- We've got to get it off him.
- Just a minute.

239
00:38:52,163 --> 00:38:54,665
Let's not be too hasty.

240
00:38:54,833 --> 00:38:58,627
We don't know anything about it.

241
00:38:58,795 --> 00:39:05,300
We're assuming it's feeding him oxygen.
If we remove it, it could kiIl him.

242
00:39:07,554 --> 00:39:10,430
I'Il take that chance.
Let's cut it off him now.

243
00:39:10,598 --> 00:39:14,101
- You take responsibility?
- Yes. Get him out of there.

244
00:39:15,937 --> 00:39:18,147
Where do you want to do this?

245
00:39:18,314 --> 00:39:21,316
We'lI make an incision
just below the knuckIe.

246
00:39:21,484 --> 00:39:23,569
Right here?

247
00:39:31,828 --> 00:39:34,121
Good God.

248
00:39:37,292 --> 00:39:40,627
That crap's gonna eat through the huIl.

249
00:39:42,130 --> 00:39:45,883
I think it's going to eat through
the goddamn hulI. Come on.

250
00:39:47,635 --> 00:39:49,720
This way.

251
00:39:57,645 --> 00:39:59,813
Next deck.

252
00:40:17,123 --> 00:40:19,208
There it is.

253
00:40:20,835 --> 00:40:22,878
Don't get under it.

254
00:40:28,551 --> 00:40:30,761
Looks like it's stopping.

255
00:40:33,681 --> 00:40:35,515
Take a look at this.

256
00:40:35,683 --> 00:40:39,061
Brett, give me your pen, quick.

257
00:40:39,229 --> 00:40:41,271
Come on.

258
00:40:46,444 --> 00:40:49,071
Don't get any on your arm.

259
00:40:55,453 --> 00:40:57,579
It's stopped.

260
00:40:57,747 --> 00:41:01,833
I haven't seen anything like that,
except molecular acid.

261
00:41:02,001 --> 00:41:05,128
It must be using it for bIood.

262
00:41:05,296 --> 00:41:09,174
It's got a wonderful defence mechanism.
You don't dare kill it.

263
00:41:09,342 --> 00:41:11,385
What about Kane?

264
00:41:13,388 --> 00:41:15,597
Here's your pen back.

265
00:41:15,765 --> 00:41:20,394
- What do we do now?
- Leave Kane to Ash. You get back to work.

266
00:41:32,991 --> 00:41:34,116
Okay.

267
00:41:35,451 --> 00:41:37,577
Try it.

268
00:41:42,417 --> 00:41:46,336
- Damn it. I feIt sure that was it.
- Try it again.

269
00:41:47,714 --> 00:41:51,758
Feel Iike I've been in this pIace a month.

270
00:41:51,926 --> 00:41:55,887
We shouldn't have Ianded here
in the first place.

271
00:41:56,055 --> 00:42:00,309
Shouldn't have landed
on this damn ball, I know that.

272
00:42:00,476 --> 00:42:04,646
The sooner we patch this up,
the sooner we can go home.

273
00:42:04,814 --> 00:42:06,732
This place gives me the creeps.

274
00:43:10,296 --> 00:43:12,923
It's amazing. What is it?

275
00:43:14,425 --> 00:43:16,510
I'd say it's...

276
00:43:17,845 --> 00:43:20,097
I don't know yet.

277
00:43:24,227 --> 00:43:27,396
- Do you want something?
- Yes, I...

278
00:43:29,857 --> 00:43:32,692
A little taIk. How's Kane?

279
00:43:32,860 --> 00:43:35,237
He's holding. No changes.

280
00:43:35,405 --> 00:43:38,407
And our guest?

281
00:43:43,121 --> 00:43:46,498
As l said, I'm stilI collating.

282
00:43:46,666 --> 00:43:52,129
But l have confirmed that he's got
an outer layer of protein poIysaccharides.

283
00:43:52,296 --> 00:43:58,844
He has a funny habit of shedding his cells
and replacing them with polarised siIicone,

284
00:43:59,011 --> 00:44:05,016
which gives him a proIonged resistance
to adverse environmentaI conditions.

285
00:44:05,184 --> 00:44:07,102
Is that enough?

286
00:44:07,270 --> 00:44:09,479
Plenty. What does it mean?

287
00:44:09,647 --> 00:44:14,025
- Please don't do that. Thank you.
- I'm sorry.

288
00:44:14,193 --> 00:44:20,574
It's an interesting combination of eIements,
making him a tough Iittle son of a bitch.

289
00:44:20,741 --> 00:44:23,034
And you Iet him in.

290
00:44:23,202 --> 00:44:25,579
I was obeying a direct order.

291
00:44:26,289 --> 00:44:31,918
When DaIlas and Kane are off the ship,
I'm senior officer.

292
00:44:32,086 --> 00:44:34,129
Oh, yes. I forgot.

293
00:44:35,006 --> 00:44:39,092
You also forgot the Science Division's
basic quarantine law.

294
00:44:39,260 --> 00:44:43,472
- That I didn't forget.
- I see. You just broke it.

295
00:44:43,639 --> 00:44:47,058
What wouId you have done with Kane?

296
00:44:47,226 --> 00:44:50,479
You knew his onIy chance
was to get him in here.

297
00:44:50,646 --> 00:44:54,900
Unfortunately, by breaking quarantine,
you risk everybody's life.

298
00:44:55,067 --> 00:44:57,486
Maybe I should have left him outside.

299
00:44:57,653 --> 00:45:02,073
Maybe I've jeopardised the rest of us,
but it was a risk I was wilIing to take.

300
00:45:02,241 --> 00:45:06,119
It's a pretty big risk for a science officer.

301
00:45:06,287 --> 00:45:09,915
It's not exactly out of the manual.

302
00:45:11,209 --> 00:45:14,711
I take my responsibilities
as seriousIy as you.

303
00:45:15,963 --> 00:45:19,799
You do your job
and let me do mine.

304
00:45:56,379 --> 00:45:58,672
- Where's Dallas?
- In the shuttle.

305
00:46:04,679 --> 00:46:05,679
DalIas.

306
00:46:05,846 --> 00:46:08,014
You should have a look at Kane.

307
00:46:08,182 --> 00:46:11,351
- Why?
- Something's happened.

308
00:46:11,519 --> 00:46:14,354
- Serious?
- Interesting.

309
00:46:19,360 --> 00:46:23,196
RipIey, meet me in the infirmary right away.

310
00:46:25,908 --> 00:46:29,119
- Where is it?
- I don't know.

311
00:46:29,287 --> 00:46:33,873
- We have to try and find it.
- Let's check it.

312
00:46:58,774 --> 00:47:01,401
Please be careful.

313
00:47:42,151 --> 00:47:44,444
Sorry.

314
00:48:16,727 --> 00:48:19,813
Not in the corner.

315
00:48:19,980 --> 00:48:23,983
Have one of these. Just in case.

316
00:48:36,414 --> 00:48:38,790
Kane? DaIlas?

317
00:48:43,879 --> 00:48:45,505
Are you OK?

318
00:48:45,673 --> 00:48:49,926
- I didn't see it. Was it in the overhead?
- It was up there somewhere.

319
00:48:50,094 --> 00:48:54,264
- My God.
- Cover the damn thing, wilI you?

320
00:48:54,432 --> 00:48:58,977
- It's alive.
- That's a reflex action.

321
00:49:00,771 --> 00:49:02,731
We've got to have a Iook at this.

322
00:49:15,369 --> 00:49:17,495
Excuse me.

323
00:49:23,085 --> 00:49:27,714
- It seems dead enough.
- Good. Let's get rid of it.

324
00:49:27,882 --> 00:49:33,678
For God's sake, this is the first time
we've encountered a species like this.

325
00:49:33,846 --> 00:49:36,681
It has to go back,
tests have to be made...

326
00:49:36,849 --> 00:49:41,644
Are you kidding? This thing bled acid.
Who knows what it will do when it's dead?

327
00:49:41,812 --> 00:49:44,898
I think it's safe to assume it isn't a zombie.

328
00:49:45,065 --> 00:49:47,776
DalIas, it has to go back.

329
00:49:47,943 --> 00:49:53,114
I'd soon as not burn it at the stake,
but you're the science officer.

330
00:49:53,282 --> 00:49:55,617
- It's your decision.
- Dallas.

331
00:49:56,076 --> 00:49:59,954
- You won't make me change my mind...
- I'm not trying to change your mind.

332
00:50:00,122 --> 00:50:02,749
I just want you to listen...

333
00:50:04,794 --> 00:50:08,922
- How can you leave that decision to him?
- I just run the ship.

334
00:50:09,089 --> 00:50:11,925
Anything scientific, Ash has the final word.

335
00:50:12,092 --> 00:50:15,303
- How does that happen?
- That's what the company wants.

336
00:50:15,471 --> 00:50:20,809
- Since when is that standard procedure?
- Standard procedure is to do what they say.

337
00:50:21,769 --> 00:50:26,439
- Did you ever ship out with Ash before?
- I went out five times with another officer.

338
00:50:26,607 --> 00:50:30,693
They repIaced him two days before
we left Thedus with Ash.

339
00:50:30,861 --> 00:50:35,240
- I don't trust him.
- I don't trust anybody.

340
00:50:35,407 --> 00:50:39,118
- How are the repairs going?
- They're pretty much finished.

341
00:50:39,286 --> 00:50:42,080
- Why didn't you tell me?
- There's stiIl some things to do.

342
00:50:42,248 --> 00:50:43,915
Like what?

343
00:50:44,083 --> 00:50:48,002
We're bIind on B and C decks,
the reserve power system's bIown...

344
00:50:48,170 --> 00:50:50,797
That's horseshit.
We can take off without that.

345
00:50:50,965 --> 00:50:55,260
- You think that's a good idea?
- I just wanna get the helI outta here.

346
00:51:19,618 --> 00:51:22,161
Dust in the intakes.
Number two's overheating.

347
00:51:22,329 --> 00:51:24,664
Spit on it for two minutes!

348
00:51:25,541 --> 00:51:29,502
We're hot and we're getting hotter.

349
00:51:31,338 --> 00:51:34,048
Engine room, red clip status.

350
00:51:34,967 --> 00:51:38,887
- One kilometre on ascension.
- Engage artificial gravity.

351
00:51:39,054 --> 00:51:42,599
- Engaged.
- I'm aItering the vector now.

352
00:51:46,896 --> 00:51:48,980
Inhibit CNG.

353
00:51:52,026 --> 00:51:55,904
- Struts retract.
- Struts retracted.

354
00:52:18,260 --> 00:52:19,802
WaIk in the park.

355
00:52:19,970 --> 00:52:23,056
When we fix something,
it stays fixed, eh, Brett?

356
00:52:23,223 --> 00:52:24,265
Right.

357
00:52:39,782 --> 00:52:43,993
We should freeze him. lf he's got a disease,
why don't we stop it there?

358
00:52:44,161 --> 00:52:47,246
- We can get to a doctor back home.
- Right.

359
00:52:47,414 --> 00:52:51,542
Whenever he says anything,
you say "Right". You know that?

360
00:52:51,710 --> 00:52:53,378
Right.

361
00:52:53,545 --> 00:52:57,840
Your staff just foIlows you around
and says "Right"! Like a parrot.

362
00:52:58,008 --> 00:53:01,469
- Shape up. What are you, a parrot?
- Right.

363
00:53:01,637 --> 00:53:03,763
Knock it off.

364
00:53:03,931 --> 00:53:07,892
- Kane wilI have to go into quarantine.
- And so are we.

365
00:53:08,060 --> 00:53:12,563
- How about something to lower your spirits?
- Thrill me, will you?

366
00:53:12,731 --> 00:53:16,776
According to my calcuIations,
based on time spent...

367
00:53:16,944 --> 00:53:20,029
- The short version. How far to Earth?
- Ten months.

368
00:53:20,197 --> 00:53:22,240
- Oh, God.
- Right.

369
00:53:23,283 --> 00:53:24,325
Yes?

370
00:53:24,493 --> 00:53:27,996
- I think you should see Kane.
- Has his condition changed?

371
00:53:28,163 --> 00:53:30,456
- It's simpler if you come.
- We're on our way.

372
00:53:33,210 --> 00:53:35,294
Right.

373
00:53:38,257 --> 00:53:40,758
How are you feelin'?

374
00:53:43,512 --> 00:53:47,932
- How are you doing?
- Terrific. Next silly question?

375
00:53:51,395 --> 00:53:53,479
Thank you.

376
00:53:55,524 --> 00:53:59,277
Do you remember anything
about the planet?

377
00:54:00,946 --> 00:54:04,282
What's the last thing you do remember?

378
00:54:10,456 --> 00:54:15,168
I remember some horrible dream
about smothering and...

379
00:54:17,796 --> 00:54:19,589
Anyway, where are we?

380
00:54:19,757 --> 00:54:22,008
- Right here.
- We're on our way home.

381
00:54:22,176 --> 00:54:25,303
Back to the old freezerinos.

382
00:54:26,388 --> 00:54:30,516
- I've got to have something to eat first.
- I need something myself.

383
00:54:31,310 --> 00:54:34,187
One more meal before bedtime. l'm buying.

384
00:54:34,354 --> 00:54:36,564
That's a break.

385
00:54:57,085 --> 00:55:01,631
First thing l'm going to do when I get back
is to get some decent food.

386
00:55:01,799 --> 00:55:07,303
I can dig it. I've eaten worse food than this,
but then l've tasted better.

387
00:55:07,471 --> 00:55:10,473
You pound down the stuff
like there's no tomorrow.

388
00:55:10,641 --> 00:55:15,102
I'd rather be eating something else,
but right now l'm thinking food.

389
00:55:15,270 --> 00:55:18,898
You should know,
you know what it's made of.

390
00:55:19,066 --> 00:55:23,110
I don't wanna taIk about what it's made of.
I'm eating this.

391
00:55:24,488 --> 00:55:28,741
What's the matter?
The food ain't that bad.

392
00:55:29,868 --> 00:55:31,953
What's wrong?

393
00:55:34,498 --> 00:55:36,624
What? What?

394
00:55:36,792 --> 00:55:38,835
This is serious.

395
00:55:48,720 --> 00:55:50,972
Get the spoon.

396
00:55:53,308 --> 00:55:56,227
- Get it into his mouth.
- I'm trying.

397
00:56:25,549 --> 00:56:27,633
Oh, God!

398
00:56:35,767 --> 00:56:37,810
Don't touch it. Don't touch it.

399
00:56:56,663 --> 00:56:59,123
- Dallas?
- Yeah.

400
00:56:59,291 --> 00:57:03,002
- Anything?
- No. You?

401
00:57:03,170 --> 00:57:05,212
Nothing.

402
00:57:05,380 --> 00:57:07,882
- Did you see anything?
- No.

403
00:57:43,001 --> 00:57:45,503
Inner hatch sealed.

404
00:57:48,548 --> 00:57:51,050
Anybody want to say anything?

405
00:58:26,920 --> 00:58:30,589
This is just an ordinary prod,
like a cattle prod.

406
00:58:30,757 --> 00:58:35,469
It's got a portabIe battery.
It's insuIated from here to here.

407
00:58:35,637 --> 00:58:39,598
Just make damn sure
nobody puts their hand on the end of it.

408
00:58:42,144 --> 00:58:46,439
It shouldn't damage the bastard
unless its skin is thinner than ours.

409
00:58:46,606 --> 00:58:50,526
But it wilI give him a little incentive.

410
00:58:50,694 --> 00:58:52,778
Now we just have to find him.

411
00:58:52,946 --> 00:58:59,785
I've designed this tracking device.
You just set it to search for a moving object.

412
00:59:01,329 --> 00:59:05,833
Hasn't got much range, but within
a certain distance, it gives off a signaI.

413
00:59:06,001 --> 00:59:09,003
What does it key on?

414
00:59:09,171 --> 00:59:12,965
Micro changes in air density.

415
00:59:13,133 --> 00:59:15,342
Gimme a demo.

416
00:59:17,637 --> 00:59:20,639
See? And again...

417
00:59:20,807 --> 00:59:23,017
Gotcha.

418
00:59:23,185 --> 00:59:28,814
Two teams. Ash, Lambert and l.
RipIey, you take Parker and Brett.

419
00:59:30,650 --> 00:59:34,945
Anyone see this thing, you catch it
in the net that Parker is hoIding.

420
00:59:35,113 --> 00:59:37,865
Parker, I don't want any heroics
out of you, all right?

421
00:59:38,033 --> 00:59:41,077
Catch it, put it in the airIock, get rid of it.

422
00:59:41,244 --> 00:59:47,666
The channels are open on alI decks.
I want you to keep in touch at all times.

423
00:59:47,834 --> 00:59:49,877
Let's go.

424
01:00:03,391 --> 01:00:05,976
I thought you fixed 1 2 moduIe.

425
01:00:06,144 --> 01:00:09,855
We did. I don't understand it.

426
01:00:12,359 --> 01:00:15,361
The circuits must have burned out.

427
01:00:27,082 --> 01:00:30,459
- What have we got here?
- Hold your light over here.

428
01:00:30,627 --> 01:00:32,628
That's it.

429
01:00:32,796 --> 01:00:35,881
I don't know if this will work.

430
01:00:38,134 --> 01:00:40,719
- Put this in there.
- Right.

431
01:00:45,225 --> 01:00:47,601
Check the insulation.

432
01:00:47,769 --> 01:00:49,812
Shit...

433
01:01:11,918 --> 01:01:14,837
According to this, it's within five metres.

434
01:01:23,346 --> 01:01:26,765
Micro changes in air density, my ass.

435
01:01:31,521 --> 01:01:33,814
It's within five metres.

436
01:01:33,982 --> 01:01:35,983
Be careful.

437
01:02:05,138 --> 01:02:10,643
- Don't creep up on me with that thing.
- You guys stick together.

438
01:02:27,994 --> 01:02:29,370
What?

439
01:02:29,537 --> 01:02:31,705
It's in this locker.

440
01:02:31,873 --> 01:02:33,499
In where?

441
01:02:33,667 --> 01:02:35,709
Here, take it.

442
01:02:38,004 --> 01:02:40,047
I got it.

443
01:02:42,717 --> 01:02:44,134
Wait.

444
01:02:44,928 --> 01:02:47,513
All right, when I say.

445
01:02:50,684 --> 01:02:53,686
- All right. Now.
- Easy.

446
01:02:59,359 --> 01:03:02,778
- Don't let him go!
- What the helI are you doing?

447
01:03:02,946 --> 01:03:05,030
It's the cat.

448
01:03:11,371 --> 01:03:15,874
We had to bag it. Now we might
pick it up on the tracker again.

449
01:03:18,294 --> 01:03:20,838
Go and get it, man.

450
01:03:21,006 --> 01:03:24,383
You get him, we'll go on.

451
01:03:34,310 --> 01:03:36,729
Here, kitty.

452
01:03:36,896 --> 01:03:38,564
Here, kitty, kitty.

453
01:03:40,191 --> 01:03:42,901
Kitty crap. Jones?

454
01:03:46,072 --> 01:03:47,948
Jonesy?

455
01:03:48,116 --> 01:03:49,908
Here, Jonesy.

456
01:03:57,751 --> 01:03:59,126
Jonesy?

457
01:04:04,924 --> 01:04:07,301
Here, kitty.

458
01:04:13,808 --> 01:04:15,434
Here, Jonesy.

459
01:04:27,614 --> 01:04:29,198
Jonesy.

460
01:04:41,294 --> 01:04:42,836
Here, kitty, kitty.

461
01:06:10,717 --> 01:06:12,134
Kitty, kitty, kitty.

462
01:06:14,637 --> 01:06:16,263
Here, Jonesy.

463
01:06:17,223 --> 01:06:18,849
Jonesy.

464
01:06:21,394 --> 01:06:22,728
Kitty, kitty.

465
01:07:12,278 --> 01:07:13,820
Jonesy?

466
01:07:22,413 --> 01:07:26,458
Come on, Jonesy.
Come on, baby. That's a kitty.

467
01:07:26,626 --> 01:07:28,710
Come on, baby.

468
01:07:30,004 --> 01:07:31,922
That's a kitty.

469
01:07:33,633 --> 01:07:36,802
I'm not gonna hurt you. Come on.

470
01:08:14,674 --> 01:08:17,592
Whatever it was, it was big.

471
01:08:20,680 --> 01:08:22,306
You sure it took him into the air shaft?

472
01:08:22,473 --> 01:08:25,058
Disappeared into one of the cooIing ducts.

473
01:08:25,226 --> 01:08:29,229
No question.
It's using the air ducts to move around.

474
01:08:31,983 --> 01:08:34,484
Could he want Brett aIive?

475
01:08:35,695 --> 01:08:37,863
- What?
- Could Brett be alive?

476
01:08:38,031 --> 01:08:41,116
No. I mean, l don't think so.

477
01:08:41,284 --> 01:08:44,786
This air shaft may work to our advantage.

478
01:08:44,954 --> 01:08:52,085
It comes out in the main airIock.
There's only one big opening aIong the way.

479
01:08:52,253 --> 01:08:58,383
We can cover that up and then we drive it
into the airlock and zap it into outer space.

480
01:08:58,551 --> 01:09:00,886
The son of a bitch is huge.

481
01:09:01,054 --> 01:09:03,305
It's Iike a man. It's big.

482
01:09:03,473 --> 01:09:05,349
Kane's son.

483
01:09:06,726 --> 01:09:11,313
Come on, Ash. The science department
should be able to help. How can we drive it?

484
01:09:11,481 --> 01:09:15,567
It's adapted welI to our atmosphere,
considering its nutritionaI needs.

485
01:09:15,735 --> 01:09:17,736
But we don't know about temperature.

486
01:09:17,904 --> 01:09:24,826
- OK, temperature. What if we change it?
- Let's try it. Most animals retreat from fire.

487
01:09:24,994 --> 01:09:29,748
Fire, yeah. Parker, can you rig
three or four incinerator units?

488
01:09:30,792 --> 01:09:33,377
Give me 20 minutes, l'lI do it.

489
01:09:33,544 --> 01:09:35,796
- Who gets to go into the vent?
- I do.

490
01:09:36,756 --> 01:09:38,507
No.

491
01:09:38,674 --> 01:09:43,178
You and Ash, take the main airlock.

492
01:09:43,346 --> 01:09:47,974
Parker, Lambert, you cover up
that maintenance opening.

493
01:11:26,282 --> 01:11:29,951
- I'm at the first junction.
- I'm right here.

494
01:11:30,119 --> 01:11:32,204
- Parker?
- Yeah.

495
01:11:32,371 --> 01:11:36,208
- Lambert?
- In position. I'm trying to get a reading.

496
01:11:36,375 --> 01:11:39,044
- The airIock is open.
- Okay, RipIey.

497
01:11:39,212 --> 01:11:40,837
Ready.

498
01:11:51,224 --> 01:11:53,975
I've got a reading on you now.

499
01:12:30,972 --> 01:12:33,807
Open the hatch to the third junction.

500
01:12:50,741 --> 01:12:52,325
OK, I'm through.

501
01:12:52,493 --> 01:12:54,077
- Ripley?
- Yes.

502
01:12:54,245 --> 01:12:57,122
CIose alI the hatches behind me.

503
01:12:57,290 --> 01:12:59,332
I'm moving on.

504
01:13:13,973 --> 01:13:16,725
DalIas, hold on. I think l got it.

505
01:13:16,892 --> 01:13:20,061
- Yes, I've got it.
- Where?

506
01:13:21,564 --> 01:13:24,524
It's somewhere around the third junction.

507
01:13:24,692 --> 01:13:27,152
OK. Moving on.

508
01:13:46,505 --> 01:13:50,925
It is right around there.
You'lI have to be carefuI.

509
01:14:00,519 --> 01:14:07,942
All right. l've reached the third junction
and l'm going down.

510
01:14:26,462 --> 01:14:29,631
What the helI's the matter with that box?

511
01:14:30,383 --> 01:14:33,927
DalIas, hold your position for a minute.

512
01:14:34,887 --> 01:14:37,639
- I've Iost the signal!
- What?

513
01:14:37,807 --> 01:14:38,973
You sure?

514
01:14:39,141 --> 01:14:44,229
Are you sure it's not there?
It's got to be around there.

515
01:14:47,400 --> 01:14:51,236
Check that out.
You may be getting interference.

516
01:14:51,404 --> 01:14:54,489
Are you sure there's no sign of it?
It is there.

517
01:14:56,409 --> 01:14:58,785
It's gotta be around there.

518
01:14:59,703 --> 01:15:01,162
DalIas?

519
01:15:05,584 --> 01:15:07,627
All right.

520
01:15:13,592 --> 01:15:16,136
Am l clear? l wanna get outta here.

521
01:15:17,805 --> 01:15:20,932
Oh, God! It's moving right towards you.

522
01:15:29,108 --> 01:15:32,986
Move, get out of there! Move!

523
01:15:34,280 --> 01:15:37,449
Move, DaIlas! Get out!

524
01:15:39,201 --> 01:15:42,120
No, the other way!

525
01:15:44,206 --> 01:15:45,748
DalIas?

526
01:15:45,916 --> 01:15:48,960
- No.
- Take it easy. DalIas?

527
01:15:55,050 --> 01:15:57,969
We found this Iaying there.

528
01:15:58,929 --> 01:16:00,805
No bIood.

529
01:16:01,432 --> 01:16:03,475
No DalIas.

530
01:16:04,477 --> 01:16:06,561
Nothing.

531
01:16:10,983 --> 01:16:15,653
- I don't hear anybody sayin' nothing.
- I'm thinking.

532
01:16:17,323 --> 01:16:23,620
Unless somebody has a better idea,
we'll proceed with DaIlas's plan.

533
01:16:23,787 --> 01:16:29,542
What? And end up Iike the others?
You're out of your mind.

534
01:16:29,710 --> 01:16:34,005
- You got a better idea?
- I say that we abandon the ship.

535
01:16:34,173 --> 01:16:41,054
We get the shuttIe and get the heIl out
of here, and hope somebody picks us up.

536
01:16:41,222 --> 01:16:45,433
- The shuttle won't take four.
- Then why don't we draw straws?

537
01:16:45,601 --> 01:16:48,561
I'm not drawing any straws.
I'm for kilIing it now.

538
01:16:48,729 --> 01:16:54,108
OK. Let's talk about killing it.
It's in the air shafts...

539
01:16:54,276 --> 01:16:57,070
Will you Iisten to me? Shut up!

540
01:16:57,238 --> 01:17:00,698
Let's hear it. Let's hear it.

541
01:17:00,866 --> 01:17:04,369
- It's using the air shafts.
- We don't know that...

542
01:17:04,537 --> 01:17:08,623
That's the only way.
We'lI move in pairs.

543
01:17:08,791 --> 01:17:12,377
We'lI go step by step
and cut off every buIkhead and vent

544
01:17:12,545 --> 01:17:16,673
untiI we have it cornered,
then we'Il blow it the fuck out into space.

545
01:17:16,840 --> 01:17:18,883
Is that acceptable to you?

546
01:17:19,051 --> 01:17:20,635
If it means killing it, yeah.

547
01:17:20,803 --> 01:17:23,221
ObviousIy it means killing it.

548
01:17:24,390 --> 01:17:26,224
But we have to stick together.

549
01:17:27,434 --> 01:17:32,438
- How are our weapons?
- Fine. This one needs refuelling.

550
01:17:32,606 --> 01:17:34,899
Will you get it, please?

551
01:17:35,067 --> 01:17:38,695
- Ash, go with him.
- I can manage.

552
01:17:38,862 --> 01:17:40,905
Don't follow me.

553
01:17:44,243 --> 01:17:45,702
Ash?

554
01:17:47,746 --> 01:17:50,832
Any suggestions from you or Mother?

555
01:17:52,126 --> 01:17:54,544
We're stiIl colIating.

556
01:17:55,754 --> 01:17:59,966
You're what? You're still colIating?

557
01:18:01,552 --> 01:18:04,304
I find that hard to believe.

558
01:18:05,806 --> 01:18:10,518
- What wouId you like me to do?
- Just what you've been doing. Nothing.

559
01:18:10,686 --> 01:18:16,608
I've got access to Mother now,
and l'll get my own answers, thank you.

560
01:18:17,693 --> 01:18:19,777
All right.

561
01:20:10,097 --> 01:20:13,975
There is an explanation for this.

562
01:20:14,143 --> 01:20:17,770
I don't wanna hear
your goddamn expIanation.

563
01:20:41,462 --> 01:20:44,547
Parker? Lambert?

564
01:20:52,931 --> 01:20:53,973
Ash.

565
01:20:54,892 --> 01:20:56,058
Open the door.

566
01:21:05,611 --> 01:21:07,153
Ash.

567
01:21:11,408 --> 01:21:14,118
Will you open the door?

568
01:21:17,956 --> 01:21:19,999
Let me by.

569
01:22:41,039 --> 01:22:43,541
What the helI are you doing?

570
01:23:00,726 --> 01:23:03,603
Get her up.

571
01:23:16,950 --> 01:23:18,826
It's an android!

572
01:23:33,759 --> 01:23:35,760
Jesus...

573
01:23:38,805 --> 01:23:42,099
It's a robot.
Ash is a goddamn robot.

574
01:23:43,810 --> 01:23:45,937
God.

575
01:23:52,486 --> 01:23:54,445
Holy shit.

576
01:23:55,864 --> 01:23:57,698
Help me get this fucking thing off.

577
01:24:05,374 --> 01:24:07,583
God... Jesus...

578
01:24:07,751 --> 01:24:09,961
Oh, God.

579
01:24:13,632 --> 01:24:16,592
How come the company
sent us a goddamn robot?

580
01:24:16,760 --> 01:24:20,596
They must have wanted the alien
for the weapons division.

581
01:24:20,764 --> 01:24:23,265
He's been protecting it all along.

582
01:24:23,433 --> 01:24:27,853
- WiIl you plug it in?
- I don't know...

583
01:24:28,021 --> 01:24:31,482
Because he may know how to kiIl it.

584
01:24:58,135 --> 01:25:00,594
Ash, can you hear me?

585
01:25:03,765 --> 01:25:05,099
Ash!

586
01:25:13,066 --> 01:25:15,568
I can hear you.

587
01:25:19,865 --> 01:25:22,283
What was your special order?

588
01:25:22,451 --> 01:25:25,494
You read it. l thought it was cIear.

589
01:25:25,662 --> 01:25:31,375
- What was it?
- Bring back Iife form, priority one.

590
01:25:31,543 --> 01:25:34,462
All other priorities rescinded.

591
01:25:37,215 --> 01:25:41,886
The damn company.
What about our lives, you son of a bitch?

592
01:25:42,053 --> 01:25:45,848
I repeat, all other priorities are rescinded.

593
01:25:46,016 --> 01:25:50,519
How do we kill it?
There's gotta be a way of kilIing it.

594
01:25:50,687 --> 01:25:53,814
- How do we do it?
- You can't.

595
01:25:54,733 --> 01:25:56,525
That's bulIshit.

596
01:25:56,693 --> 01:26:01,781
You stilI don't understand
what you're dealing with, do you?

597
01:26:01,948 --> 01:26:04,575
The perfect organism.

598
01:26:07,120 --> 01:26:11,916
Its structural perfection
is matched onIy by its hostility.

599
01:26:12,083 --> 01:26:14,168
You admire it.

600
01:26:17,297 --> 01:26:20,007
I admire its purity.

601
01:26:23,261 --> 01:26:25,554
A survivor,

602
01:26:27,474 --> 01:26:33,312
uncIouded by conscience, remorse,

603
01:26:33,480 --> 01:26:35,815
or delusions of morality.

604
01:26:37,609 --> 01:26:41,904
I've heard enough of this
and l'm asking you to pulI the pIug.

605
01:26:42,072 --> 01:26:44,865
Last word.

606
01:26:47,869 --> 01:26:52,039
I can't lie to you about your chances, but...

607
01:26:54,918 --> 01:26:57,962
you have my sympathies.

608
01:26:59,881 --> 01:27:05,928
We're gonna blow up the ship.
We'lI take our chances in the shuttIe.

609
01:27:06,096 --> 01:27:08,639
- Blow up the ship.
- Good.

610
01:27:08,807 --> 01:27:10,850
Come on.

611
01:27:37,294 --> 01:27:39,837
When we throw the switches,
how Iong do we have?

612
01:27:40,005 --> 01:27:41,881
- Ten minutes.
- No bullshit.

613
01:27:42,048 --> 01:27:46,969
Or we won't need no rocket
to fly through space.

614
01:27:47,137 --> 01:27:51,140
We'lI need coolant
for the air support system.

615
01:28:02,402 --> 01:28:07,156
You two get all the coolant you can carry.
I'Il get the shuttle ready.

616
01:28:07,324 --> 01:28:10,534
I'Il give you about seven minutes.

617
01:28:10,702 --> 01:28:16,916
Come back up here, I'll shut the switches off
and we'Il blow this fucker off into space.

618
01:28:17,083 --> 01:28:18,834
- Ready?
- Take care of yourseIf.

619
01:28:19,002 --> 01:28:21,253
Seven minutes.

620
01:28:58,249 --> 01:29:00,376
Take it easy.

621
01:29:04,547 --> 01:29:55,055
Jones?

622
01:30:29,215 --> 01:30:31,258
Okay, check the bottIes.

623
01:30:44,814 --> 01:30:46,356
Jones.

624
01:30:51,321 --> 01:30:53,739
- How are you doing?
- Fine.

625
01:30:56,451 --> 01:30:58,535
OK, go ahead.

626
01:30:59,913 --> 01:31:01,538
Jones?

627
01:31:07,462 --> 01:31:09,463
Kitty, kitty, kitty.

628
01:31:09,631 --> 01:31:11,799
Come here, Jones.

629
01:31:11,966 --> 01:31:13,383
Jones.

630
01:31:18,306 --> 01:31:21,100
Come here, boy.

631
01:31:22,352 --> 01:31:24,436
Nice kitty.

632
01:31:24,896 --> 01:31:26,188
Jones?

633
01:31:27,899 --> 01:31:29,274
Jones.

634
01:31:33,613 --> 01:31:36,615
Come here, sweetheart.

635
01:31:37,492 --> 01:31:59,930
Jones.

636
01:32:00,098 --> 01:32:02,391
Goddamn it.

637
01:32:05,603 --> 01:32:07,688
Now l've got you.

638
01:32:13,361 --> 01:32:16,321
Come on, sweetheart. Nice kitty.

639
01:32:38,136 --> 01:32:41,054
Oh, my God...

640
01:32:41,848 --> 01:32:44,975
- Get out of the way.
- I can't.

641
01:32:45,143 --> 01:32:47,978
Get out of the way! It's gonna kilI us!

642
01:32:48,146 --> 01:32:49,980
I can't!

643
01:32:50,148 --> 01:32:53,358
- For Christ sake, get out of the way!
- Parker? Lambert?

644
01:33:04,037 --> 01:33:06,288
Get out of the way!

645
01:33:09,209 --> 01:33:11,460
Lambert? Lambert.

646
01:33:41,908 --> 01:33:44,284
Get ready to roIl!

647
01:34:21,906 --> 01:34:23,365
Parker?

648
01:35:57,210 --> 01:35:58,752
Danger.

649
01:35:58,920 --> 01:36:03,799
The emergency destruct system
is now activated.

650
01:36:03,966 --> 01:36:09,846
The ship will detonate
in T minus ten minutes.

651
01:36:10,014 --> 01:36:18,271
The option to override automatic detonation
expires in T minus five minutes.

652
01:37:17,206 --> 01:37:26,089
The option to override automatic detonation
expires in T minus three minutes.

653
01:38:00,458 --> 01:38:09,758
The option to override automatic detonation
expires in T minus one minute.

654
01:38:16,682 --> 01:38:19,392
29, 28,

655
01:38:19,560 --> 01:38:20,685
27,

656
01:38:20,853 --> 01:38:23,563
26, 25,

657
01:38:23,731 --> 01:38:25,398
24,

658
01:38:25,566 --> 01:38:28,151
23, 22,

659
01:38:28,319 --> 01:38:31,238
21 , 20 seconds.

660
01:38:31,405 --> 01:38:33,823
1 9, 1 8,

661
01:38:33,991 --> 01:38:36,576
1 7, 1 6,

662
01:38:36,744 --> 01:38:40,247
1 5, 1 4, 1 3,

663
01:38:40,414 --> 01:38:41,957
1 2,

664
01:38:42,124 --> 01:38:44,626
1 1 , 1 0 seconds.

665
01:38:44,794 --> 01:38:46,711
9, 8,

666
01:38:46,879 --> 01:38:49,756
7, 6,

667
01:38:49,924 --> 01:38:52,717
5, 4,

668
01:38:52,885 --> 01:38:55,512
3, 2,

669
01:38:55,680 --> 01:38:57,222
1 .

670
01:38:57,390 --> 01:39:03,395
The option to override detonation procedure
has now expired.

671
01:39:04,689 --> 01:39:08,608
Mother! I've turned
the cooIing unit back on.

672
01:39:08,776 --> 01:39:10,694
Mother!

673
01:39:10,861 --> 01:39:18,034
The ship will automaticaIly destruct
in T minus five minutes.

674
01:39:19,537 --> 01:39:21,579
You bitch!

675
01:39:40,391 --> 01:39:42,475
Goddamn it.

676
01:41:13,109 --> 01:41:14,651
Jones.

677
01:42:00,156 --> 01:42:04,826
You now have one minute
to abandon ship.

678
01:42:04,994 --> 01:42:10,874
The ship will automaticaIly destruct
in T minus one minute.

679
01:42:35,483 --> 01:42:39,235
T minus 30 seconds.

680
01:42:39,403 --> 01:42:42,238
29, 28,

681
01:42:42,406 --> 01:42:44,407
27, 26,

682
01:42:44,575 --> 01:42:47,535
25, 24,

683
01:42:47,703 --> 01:42:50,538
23, 22,

684
01:42:50,706 --> 01:42:53,541
21 , 20 seconds.

685
01:42:53,709 --> 01:42:55,418
1 9, 1 8,

686
01:42:55,586 --> 01:42:58,880
1 7, 1 6,

687
01:42:59,048 --> 01:43:00,590
1 5, 1 4,

688
01:43:00,758 --> 01:43:04,010
1 3, 1 2, 1 1 ,

689
01:43:04,178 --> 01:43:05,428
1 0 seconds.

690
01:43:05,596 --> 01:43:08,056
9, 8,

691
01:43:08,224 --> 01:43:10,391
7, 6,

692
01:43:10,559 --> 01:43:12,560
5, 4,

693
01:43:12,728 --> 01:43:15,563
3, 2, 1 .

694
01:44:04,196 --> 01:44:06,698
I got you,

695
01:44:08,200 --> 01:44:10,576
you son of a bitch.

696
01:44:54,788 --> 01:44:56,873
It's all right.

697
01:45:21,523 --> 01:45:24,400
All right, it's nice to see you, too.

698
01:45:26,487 --> 01:45:28,404
It's OK.

699
01:49:59,593 --> 01:50:00,676
Come on.

700
01:50:00,844 --> 01:50:13,606
You are my lucky star.

701
01:50:15,317 --> 01:50:19,195
Lucky, Iucky, lucky.

702
01:50:19,363 --> 01:50:21,113
OK.

703
01:50:29,456 --> 01:50:30,706
Come on.

704
01:50:30,874 --> 01:50:36,504
You are my lucky star.

705
01:50:37,756 --> 01:50:40,966
You are...

706
01:50:42,719 --> 01:50:44,845
my lucky star.

707
01:50:45,389 --> 01:50:49,558
You are my lucky star.

708
01:50:49,726 --> 01:50:53,562
You are my lucky...

709
01:52:40,504 --> 01:52:44,507
FinaI report
of the commercial starship <i>Nostromo</i>.

710
01:52:44,674 --> 01:52:47,468
Third Officer reporting.

711
01:52:47,636 --> 01:52:50,679
The other members of the crew -

712
01:52:50,847 --> 01:52:59,730
Kane, Lambert, Parker, Brett, Ash
and Captain DalIas - are dead.

713
01:53:00,440 --> 01:53:03,025
Cargo and ship destroyed.

714
01:53:04,236 --> 01:53:07,947
I should reach the frontier
in about six weeks.

715
01:53:08,114 --> 01:53:11,784
With a little luck,
the network wiIl pick me up.

716
01:53:11,952 --> 01:53:17,289
This is Ripley,
last survivor of the <i>Nostromo</i>,

717
01:53:17,457 --> 01:53:19,500
signing off.

718
01:53:26,508 --> 01:53:28,592
Come on, cat.

719
01:56:33,069 --> 01:56:34,069
[ENGLISH - US]

