(Subtitles by J Basto, in English)>>
(lyrics from the web)>>
(synchrinized for Les.Miserables.2012.DVDSCR-EDAW2013)>>
Les Misérables (2012),  IMDb 8.1/10, nom 8 Oscars>>
Music by Claude-Michel Schönberg,  english lyrics by Herbert Kretzmer.
Filmed in UK (mostly) and France>>
Hugh Jackman (b.1968, AUS) as Jean Valjean, the ex-con then Mayor>>
Russell Crowe (b.1964, NZ) as Javert, the inspector>>
Anne Hathaway (b.1982, US) as Fantine, the factory worker>>
Amanda Seyfried (b.1985, US) as Cosette, the daughter of Fantine>>
In 19th-century France, Jean Valjean,>>
has been hunted by the ruthless policeman Javert>>
After he breaks parole, agrees to care>>
for factory worker Fantine's daughter, Cosette.
The fateful decision changes their lives forever.
(Jean Valjean)>>
(Javert)>>
1."Look Down" (Chain Gang, Javert, Valjean)>>
Look down, look down Don't look 'em in the eye>>
Look down, look down, You're here until you die>>
No God above and Hell alone below>>
Look down, look down, There's 20 years to go>>
I've done no wrong! Sweet Jesus, hear my prayer!
Look down look down, Sweet Jesus doesn't care>>
I know she'll wait, I know that she'll be true!
Look down, look down, They've all forgotten you>>
When I get free ya won't see me. Here for dust!
Look down, look down You'll always be a slave>>
Look down, look down, You're standing in your grave>>
Retreat the flag!
2."On Parole"  Valjean, Javert>>
Now prisoner 24601 Your time is up, and your parole's begun>>
You know what that means.
Yes, it means I'm free.
I stole a loaf of bread.
My sister's child was close to death and we were starving.
You will starve again unless you learn the meaning of the law.
I know the meaning of those 19 years>>
A slave of the law>>
5 years for what you did>>
The rest because you tried to run Yes, 24601.
My name is Jean Valjean>>
And I am Javert Do not forget my name!
Do not forget me, 24601!
Look down, look down, You'll always be a slave>>
Look down, look down, You're standing in your grave>>
Nor forgive them For what they've done.
They are the guilty - everyone.
The day begins... And now let's see>>
What this new world will do for me!
No work here>>
Valjean, as a dangerous man, you will be in parole forever>>
Failure to report means immediate arrest Be in 30 days>>
Let me see your papers>>
(Bishop of Digne) Come in, Sir, for you are weary,>>
And the night is cold out there.
Though our lives are very humble>>
What we have, we have to share.
There is wine here to revive you>>
There is bread to make you strong,>>
There's a bed to rest till morning,>>
Rest from pain, and rest from wrong.
3."Valjean Arrested and Forgiven" (Policemen, Bishop of Digne)>>
Get in there. Put it down. Stay there.
Monseigneut! We have your silver. We caught this man>>
I didn't notice that you gave him this?
That is right.
But my friend you left so early>>
Surely something slipped your mind>>
You forgot I gave these also Would you leave the best behind?
Messieurs, you may release him For this man has spoken true>>
I commend you for your duty And God's blessing go with you.
4."Valjean's Soliloquy" (Valjean)>>
What have I done? Sweet Jesus, what have I done?
Become a thief in the night, Become a dog on the run>>
And have I fallen so far, And is the hour so late>>
That nothing remains but the cry of my hate,>>
The cries in the dark that nobody hears,>>
Here where I stand at the turning of the years?
If there's another way to go I missed it 20 long years ago>>
My life was a war that could never be won>>
They gave me a number and murdered Valjean>>
When they chained me and left me for dead>>
Just for stealing a mouthful of bread>>
Yet why did I allow this man>>
To touch my soul and teach me love?
He treated me like any other He gave me his trust>>
He called me brother My life he claims for God above>>
Can such things be?
For I had come to hate the world>>
This world that always hated me>>
Take an eye for an eye!
Turn your heart into stone!
This is all I have lived for!
This is all I have known!
One word from him and I'd be back>>
Beneath the lash, upon the rack>>
Instead he offers me my freedom>>
I feel my shame inside me like a knife>>
He told me that I have a soul,>>
How does he know?
What spirit comes to move my life?
Is there another way to go?
I am reaching, but I fall>>
And the night is closing in>>
And I stare into the void>>
To the whirlpool of my sin>>
I'll escape now from that world>>
From the world of Jean Valjean>>
Jean Valjean is nothing now>>
Another story must begin!
5."At the End of the Day" (Factory Women, Fantine, Valjean)>>
At the end of the day you're another day older>>
And that's all you can say for the life of the poor>>
It's a struggle, it's a war>>
And there's nothing that anyone's giving>>
One more day standing about, what is it for?
One day less to be living.
At the end of the day you're another day colder>>
And the shirt on your back doesn't keep out the chill>>
And the righteous hurry past>>
They don't hear the little ones crying>>
And the winter is coming on fast, ready to kill>>
One day nearer to dying!
At the end of the day there's another day dawning>>
And the sun in the morning is waiting to rise>>
Like the waves crash on the sand Like a storm that'll break any second>>
There's a hunger in the land>>
There's a reckoning still to be reckoned and there's gonna be hell to pay>>
At the end of the day!
At the end of the day you get nothing for nothing>>
Sitting flat on your butt doesn't buy any bread>>
There are children back at home And the children have got to be fed>>
And you're lucky to be in a job And in a bed!
And we're counting our blessings!
Have you seen how the foreman is fuming today?
With his terrible breath and his wandering hands?
It's because little Fantine won't give him his way>>
Take a look at his trousers, you'll see where he stands!
And the boss, he never knows That the foreman is always in heat>>
If Fantine doesn't look out Watch how she goes>>
She'll be out on the street!
At the end of the day it's another day over>>
With enough in your pocket to last for a week>>
Pay the landlord, pay the shop Keep on grafting as long as you're able>>
Keep on grafting till you drop Or it's back to the crumbs off the table>>
You've got to pay your way At the end of the day!
And what have we here, little innocent sister?
Come on Fantine, let's have all the news!
Ooh..."Dear Fantine you must send us more money...>>
Your child needs a doctor...There's no time to lose...">>
Give that letter to me It is none of your business>>
With a husband at home And a bit on the side!
Is there anyone here Who can swear before God>>
She has nothing to fear? She has nothing to hide?
What is this fighting all about? Someone tear these two apart!
This is a factory, not a circus!
Now, come on ladies, settle down>>
I am the Mayor of this town I run a business of repute>>
Deal with this, foreman! And be as patient as you can.
Now someone say how this began!
At the end of the day She's the one who began it!
There's a kid that she's hiding In some little town>>
There's a man she has to pay You can guess how she picks up the extra>>
You can bet she's earning her keep Sleeping around>>
And the boss wouldn't like it!
Yes it's true there's a child And the child is my daughter>>
And her father abandoned us leaving us flat>>
Now she lives with an innkeeper man and his wife>>
And I pay for the child What's the matter with that?
At the end of the day She'll be nothing but trouble>>
And there's trouble for all When there's trouble for one!
While we're earning our daily bread She's the one with her hands in the butter>>
You must send the slut away Or we're all gonna end in the gutter>>
And it's us who'll have to pay At the end of the day!
I might have known the bitch could bite>>
I might have known the cat had claws>>
I might have guessed your little secret>>
Ah yes, the virtuous Fantine>>
Who keeps herself so pure and clean You'd be the cause I had no doubt>>
Of any trouble hereabout You play a virgin in the light>>
But need no urgin' in the night.
She's been laughing at you While she's having her men>>
She'll be nothing but trouble again and again You must sack her today>>
Sack the girl today!
Right my girl. On your way!
6."The Runaway Cart" (Townspeople)>>
Can this be true? I don't belive what I see,>>
A man your age to be as strong as you are...>>
A memory stirs, you make me think of a man>>
From years ago, a man who broke his parole, he disappeared...>>
Say what you must, don't leave it there.
Forgive me sir, I would not dare>>
7."Lovely Ladies" (Sailors, Fantine, Whores)>>
I smell women Smell 'em in the air>>
Think I'll drop my anchor In that harbor over there>>
Lovely ladies Smell 'em through the smoke>>
Seven months at sea And now I'm hungry for a poke>>
Even stokers need a little stoke!
Lovely ladies Waiting for a bite>>
Waiting for the customers Who only come at night>>
Lovely ladies Ready for the call>>
Standing up or lying down Or any way at all>>
Bargain prices up against the wall>>
What pretty hair! What pretty locks you got there>>
What luck you got. It's worth a centime, my dear>>
I'll take the lot>>
Don't touch me! Leave me alone!
Let's make a price.
I'll give you all of 10 francs, Just think of that!
It pays a debt>>
Just think of that>>
What can I do? It pays a debt.
10 francs may save my poor Cosette!
Lovely ladies Waiting in the dark>>
Ready for a thick one Or a quick one in the park>>
Long time short time Any time, my dear>>
Cost a little extra if you want to take all year!
Quick and cheap is underneath the pier!
Give me the dirt, who's that bit over there?
A bit of skirt. She's the one sold her hair.
She's got a kid. Sends her all that she can>>
I might have known There is always some man>>
Lovely lady, come along and join us! Lovely lady!
Come on dearie, why all the fuss?
You're no grander than the rest of us>>
Life has dropped you at the bottom of the heap>>
Join your sisters Make money in your sleep!
That's right dearie, show him what you've got!
That's right dearie, let him have the lot>>
Old men, young men, take 'em as they come>>
Harbor rats and alley cats and every kind of scum>>
Poor men, rich men, leaders of the land>>
See them with their trousers off they're never quite as grand>>
All it takes is money in your hand!
Lovely ladies Going for a song>>
Got a lot of callers But they never stay for long>>
Come on, Captain, you can wear your shoes>>
Don't it make a change To have a girl who can't refuse>>
Easy money Lying on a bed>>
Just as well they never see The hate that's in your head>>
Don't they know they're making love To one already dead!
8."I Dreamed a Dream" (Fantine)>>
There was a time when men were kind,>>
And their voices were soft,>>
And their words inviting.
There was a time when love was blind,>>
And the world was a song,>>
And the song was exciting.
There was a time...>>
when it all went wrong...>>
I dreamed a dream in time gone by,>>
When hope was high and life worth living.
I dreamed that love would never die,>>
I dreamed that God would be forgiving.
Then I was young and unafraid,>>
And dreams were made and used and wasted.
There was no ransom to be paid,>>
No song unsung, no wine, untasted.
But the tigers come at night,>>
With their voices soft as thunder,>>
As they tear your hope apart,>>
And they turn your dream to shame.
He slept a summer by my side,>>
He filled my days with endless wonder...>>
He took my childhood in his stride,>>
But he was gone when autumn came!
And still I dream he'll come to me,>>
That we will live the years together,>>
But there are dreams that cannot be,>>
And there are storms we cannot weather!
I had a dream my life would be>>
So different from this hell I'm living,>>
So different now from what it seemed...>>
Now life has killed the dream I dreamed...>>
9."Fantine's Arrest" (Fantine, Javert, Valjean)>>
You've got some nerve, you little slut You've got some gall.
I guarantee, I'll make you suffer>>
I beg you, don't report me sir I'll do whatever you may want>>
Tell me quickly what's the story>>
Who saw what and why and where>>
Let him give a full description Let him answer to Javert!
Javert, would you believe it I was lost here in the dark>>
When this prostitute attacked me You can see she left her mark>>
She will answer for her actions If you make a full report>>
You may rest assured, M'sieur, she will answer to the court.
There's a child who sorely needs me Please M'sieur, she's but that high>>
Holy God, is there no mercy? If I go to jail she'll die!
I have heard such protestations Every day for 20 years>>
Let's have no more explanations Save your breath and save your tears>>
`Honest work, just reward, That's the way to please the Lord.'>>
A moment of your time, Javert I do believe this woman's tale>>
M'sieur le Mayor>>
You've done your duty, let her be She needs a doctor, not a jail>>
But M'sieur Mayor! Can this be?
Where will she end? This child without a friend?
I've seen your face before>>
Show me some way to help you>>
How have you come to grief>>
In a place such as this?
M'sieur, don't mock me now, I pray>>
It's hard enough I've lost my pride>>
You let your foreman send me away>>
Yes, you were there, and turned aside>>
I never did no wrong>>
Is it true, what I have done?
My daughter's close to dying... To an innocent soul?
If there's a God above Had I only known then...>>
He'd let me die instead>>
In His name my task has just begun>>
I will take her to the hospital.
10."Who Am I? / The Trial" (Valjean)>>
He thinks that man is me without a second glance!
The stranger they have found This man could be my chance!
Why should I save his hide? Why should I right this wrong?
When I have come so far And struggled for so long?
If I speak, I am condemned.
If I stay silent, I am damned!
I am the master of hundreds of workers. They all look to me.
How can I abandon them? How would they live if I am not free?
If I speak, they are condemned.
If I stay silent, I am damned!
Who am I?
Can I condemn this man to slavery>>
Pretend I do not feel his agony>>
This innocent who bears my face Who goes to judgement in my place>>
Who am I?
Can I conceal myself for evermore?
Pretend I'm not the man I was before?
And must my name until I die Be no more than an alibi?
Must I lie?
How can I ever face my fellow men?
How can I ever face myself again?
My soul belongs to God, I know I made that bargain long ago>>
He gave me hope when hope was gone>>
He gave me strength to journey on>>
Who am I? Who am I?
Jean Valjean!
And so Your Honor, you see it's true This man bears no more guilt than you!
Who am I?
24601!
11."Come to Me (Fantine's Death)" (Fantine, Valjean)>>
Cosette, it's turned so cold>>
Cosette, it's past your bedtime>>
You've played the day away>>
And soon it will be night.
Come to me, Cosette, the light is fading>>
Don't you see the evening star appearing?
Come to me, and rest against my shoulder>>
How fast the minutes fly away and every minute colder.
Dear Fantine, Cosette will be here soon>>
Dear Fantine, she will be by your side>>
Come Cosette, my child. Where did you go?
Be at peace...>>
Be at peace evermore...>>
My Cosette...>>
Shall live in my protection>>
Take her now>>
Your child will want for nothing>>
Good M'sieur, you come from God in Heaven.
Tell her I love her.
And I'll see her when I wake...>>
12."The Confrontation" (Javert, Valjean)>>
Valjean, at last,>>
We see each other plain>>
`M'sieur le Mayor,'>>
You'll wear a different chain!
Before you say another word, Javert>>
Before you chain me up like a slave again>>
Listen to me! There is something I must do.
This woman leaves behind a suffering child.
There is none but me who can intercede,>>
In Mercy's name, 3 days are all I need.
Then I'll return, I pledge my word.
Then I'll return... You must think me mad!
I've hunted you across the years>>
A man like you can never change>>
A man such as you.
Believe of me what you will>>
There is a duty that I'm sworn to do>>
You know nothing of my life>>
All I did was steal some bread>>
You know nothing of the world>>
You would sooner see me dead>>
But not before I see this justice done>>
I am warning you Javert>>
I'm a stronger man by far>>
There is power in me yet>>
My race is not yet run>>
You know nothing of Javert>>
I was born inside a jail>>
I was born with scum like you>>
I am from the gutter too!
13."Castle on a Cloud" (Young Cosette)>>
There is a castle on a cloud,>>
I like to go there in my sleep,>>
Aren't any floors for me to sweep,>>
Not in my castle on a cloud.
There is a lady all in white,>>
Holds me and sings a lullaby,>>
She's nice to see and she's soft to touch,>>
She says "Cosette, I love you very much.">>
I know a place where no one's lost,>>
I know a place where no one cries,>>
Crying at all is not allowed,>>
Not in my castle on a cloud.
Now look who's here The little madam herself!
Pretending once again she's been `so awfully good,'>>
Better not let me catch you slacking Better not catch my eye!
10 rotten francs your mother sends me What is that going to buy?
Now take that pail My little `Mademoiselle'>>
And go and draw some water from the well!
We should never have taken you in in the first place>>
How stupid the things that we do!
Like mother like daughter, the scum of the street.
Mamma! Eponine, come my dear, Eponine, let me see you>>
You look very well in that new little blue hat>>
There's some little girls who know how to behave>>
And they know what to wear>>
And I'm saying thank heaven for that.
Still there Cosette? Your tears will do you no good!
I told you fetch some water from the well in the wood!
Please do not send me out alone>>
Not in the darkness on my own!
14."Master of the House" (Thénardier and Mme., Inn Patrons)>>
My band of soaks>>
My den of dissolutes>>
My dirty jokes, my always pissed as newts.
My sons of whores>>
Spent their lives in my inn>>
Homing pigeons homing in>>
They fly through my doors>>
And their money's as good as yours>>
Welcome, M'sieur Sit yourself down>>
And meet the best Innkeeper in town>>
As for the rest, All of 'em crooks>>
Rooking their guests And cooking the books.
Seldom do you see Honest men like me>>
A gent of good intent Who's content to be>>
Master of the house Doling out the charm>>
Ready with a handshake And an open palm>>
Tells a saucy tale Makes a little stir>>
Customers appreciate a bon-viveur>>
Glad to do a friend a favor Doesn't cost me to be nice>>
But nothing gets you nothing Everything has got a little price!
Master of the house Keeper of the zoo>>
Ready to relieve 'em Of a sou or two>>
Watering the wine Making up the weight>>
Pickin' up their knick-knacks When they can't see straight>>
Everybody loves a landlord Everybody's bosom friend>>
I do whatever pleases Jesus! Won't I bleed 'em in the end!
Master of the house Quick to catch yer eye>>
Never wants a passerby To pass him by>>
Servant to the poor Butler to the great>>
Comforter, philosopher, And lifelong mate!
Everybody's boon companion Everybody's chaperone>>
But lock up your valises Jesus! Won't I skin you to the bone!
Food beyond compare Food beyond belief>>
Mix it in a mincer And pretend it's beef>>
Kidney of a horse Liver of a cat>>
Filling up the sausages With this and that>>
Residents are more than welcome Bridal suite is occupied>>
Reasonable charges Plus some little extras on the side!
Charge 'em for the lice Extra for the mice>>
2% for looking in the mirror twice>>
Here a little slice There a little cut>>
3% for sleeping with the window shut>>
When it comes to fixing prices>>
There are a lot of tricks he knows How it all increases>>
All those bits and pieces Jesus! It's amazing how it grows!
I used to dream That I would meet a prince>>
But God Almighty, Have you seen what's happened since?
`Master of the house?' Isn't worth me spit!
`Comforter, philosopher' - and lifelong shit!
Cunning little brain Regular Voltaire>>
Thinks he's quite a lover But there's not much there>>
What a cruel trick of nature Landed me with such a louse>>
God knows how I've lasted Living with this bastard in the house!
Master of the house. Master and a half!
Comforter, philosopher Ah, don't make me laugh!
Servant to the poor. Butler to the great. Hypocrite and toady and inebriate!
Everybody bless the landlord! Everybody bless his spouse!
Everybody raise a glass>>
Everybody raise a glass to the master of the house!
Hush now. Do not be afraid of me.
Don't hide. Show me where you live>>
Tell me my chid. What is your name?
I'm called Cosette>>
Can I help you with your bucket?
I've found her wandering in the wood.
This little child, I've found her trembling in the shadows.
And I am here to help Cosette>>
I will settle any debt you may think proper>>
I will pay what I must pay>>
to take Cosette away>>
This is a duty I must>>
There is a promess I have made>>
And your mother is with God>>
Certainly is rebirthed>>
And I speek here with her voice>>
And I stand here in her place>>
And from ths day and evermore>>
Cosette shall live in my protection>>
You are very wellcome here. I will not forget our vow>>
Take a drink. Take a chair.
Cosette shall have a father now>>
16."The Bargain" (Thénardier and Mme., Valjean, Young Cosette)>>
What to do? What to say?
Shall you carry our treasure away?
What a gem! What a pearl!
Beyond rubies is our little girl!
How can we talk of debt?
Let's not haggle for darling Colette! Cosette!
Dear Fantine, gone to rest...>>
Have we done for her child what is best? I think so.
Shared our bread. Shared each bone.
Treated her like she's one of our own! Like our own, Monsieur!
Your feelings do you credit, sir And I will ease the parting blow>>
Let us not talk of bargains or bones or greed>>
Now, may I say, we are agreed?
That would quite fit the bill If she hadn't so often been ill>>
Little dear, cost us dear Medicines are expensive, M'sieur>>
Not that we begrudged a sou>>
It's no more than we Christians must do!
No more words. Here's your price.
Fifteen hundred for your sacrifice.
Come, Cosette, say goodbye>>
Let us seek out some friendlier sky.
Thank you both for Cosette>>
It won't take you too long to forget.
Farewell Cojette! Cosette.
17."Suddenly" (Valjean, new song)>>
Suddenly I'm here Suddenly it starts>>
When two anxious hearts beat as one.
Yesterday I was alone Today you walk beside me>>
Something still unclear Something not yet here>>
Has begun.
Suddenly the world Seems a different place>>
Somehow full of grace And delight.
How was I to know That so much love>>
Was held inside me?
But her past is gone Now we are long through the night.
How was I to know at last That happiness can come so fast?
Trusting me the way you do Im so afraid of failing you>>
Just a child who cannot know That danger follows where I go>>
There are shadows everywhere And memories I cannot share>>
Nevermore alone Nevermore apart>>
You have warmed my heart Like the sun.
You have brought the gift of life And love so long denied me.
Suddenly I see What I could not see>>
Something suddenly Has begun>>
18."Stars" (Javert)>>
There, out in the darkness A fugitive running>>
Fallen from God Fallen from grace>>
God be my witness I never shall yield>>
Till we come face to face>>
He knows his way in the dark Mine is the way of the Lord>>
And those who follow the path of the righteous Shall have their reward>>
And if they fall, as Lucifer fell The flame, the sword!
Stars In your multitudes>>
Scarce to be counted Filling the darkness>>
With order and light You are the sentinels>>
Silent and sure>>
Keeping watch in the night>>
You know your place in the sky>>
You hold your course and your aim>>
And each in your season Returns and returns>>
And is always the same>>
And if you fall as Lucifer fell>>
You fall in flame!
And so it has been and so it is written>>
On the doorway to paradise>>
That those who falter and those who fall>>
Must pay the price!
Lord let me find him That I may see him>>
Safe behind bars I will never rest>>
Till then This I swear>>
This I swear by the stars!
19."Look Down" (People)>>
Look down and see the beggars at your feet>>
Look down and show some mercy if you can>>
Look down and see the sweepings of the street>>
Look down, look down, Upon your fellow man!
'Ow do you do? My name's Gavroche. These are my people. Here's my patch.
Not much to look at, nothing posh Nothing that you'd call up to scratch.
This is my school, my high society Here in the slums of Saint Michele>>
We live on crumbs of humble piety Tough on the teeth, but what the hell!
Think you're poor? Think you're free?
Follow me! Follow me!
Look down and show some mercy if you can>>
Look down, look down, upon your fellow man!
There was a time we killed the king. We've tried to change the world too fast>>
Now we have got another king He's no better than the last>>
This is the land of full liberty Now when we fight, we fight for great.
Here is the thing about equality Even if we could when we're dead>>
Take your place. Take your chance Vive la France. Vive la France!
Look down and show some mercy if you can>>
Look down, look down, upon your fellow man!
When's it gonna end? When we gonna live?
Something's gotta happen now or Something's gonna give>>
It'll come, it'll come, it'll come>>
Where are the leaders of the land? Where is the king who runs this show?
Only one man - general Lamarque Speaks for the people here below.
Lamarque is ill and fading fast! Won't last the week out, so they say.
With all the anger in the land How long before the judgement day?
Before we cut the fat ones down to size?
Before the barricades arise?
Marius. Grandfather.
Have you any idea of the shame you bring on our family?
Vive la France!
20."The Robbery" (Thénardier,  Marius, Éponine, Valjean)>>
Everyone here, you know your place Brujon, Babet, Claquesous>>
You, Montparnasse, watch for the law With Eponine take care>>
You turn on the tears No mistakes, my dears>>
Please m'sieur, come this way Here's a child that ain't eaten today.
Save a life, spare a sou God rewards all the good that you do.
Wait a bit. Know that face. Ain't the world a remarkable place?
Men like me don't forget You're the bastard that borrowed Colette! Cosette!
What is this? Are you mad? No, Monsieur, you don't know what you say!
You know me, you know me. I'm a con, just like you.
It's the police! Disappear! Run for it! It's Javert!
21."Javert's Intervention" (Javert, Thénardier)>>
Another brawl in this square Another stink in the air!
Was there a witness to this? Well, let him speak to Javert!
M'sieur, the streets are not safe, But let these vermin beware>>
We'll see that justice is done!
Look upon this fine collection Crawled from underneath a stone>>
This swarm of worms and maggots Could have picked you to the bone!
I know this man over here I know his name and his trade>>
And on your witness, M'sieur, We'll see him suitably paid.
But where's the gentleman gone? And why on earth did he run?
You will have a job to find him He's not whom he seems to be>>
And the girl who stood beside him is the child he stole from me. Yeah, and me.
Could it be he's some old jailbird That the tide now washes in>>
Heard my name and started running All the elements point to him>>
In the absence of a victim, Dear Inspector, may I go?
And remember when you've nicked him, It was me who told you so!
Let the old man keep on running I will run him off his feet!
Everyone about your business! Clear this garbage off the street!
22."Éponine's Errand" (Éponine, Marius)>>
Cosette! Now I remember! Cosette! How can it be?
We were children together Look what's become of me...>>
Eponine, who was that girl? Some bourgeois two-a-penny thing!
Eponine, find her for me! What will you give me?
Anything!
Got you all excited now, But God knows what you see in her>>
Ain't you all delighted now? No, I don't want your money sir...>>
Eponine! Do this for me... Discover where she lives>>
But careful how you go Don't let your father know>>
'Ponine! I'm lost until she's found!
You see, I told you so! There's lots of things I know>>
'Ponine... she knows her way around!
23."Red & Black" (The ABC Cafe, the students)>>
The time is near>>
So near it's stirring the blood in their veins!
And yet beware>>
Don't let the wine go to your brains!
We need a sign To rally the people>>
To call them to arms To bring them in line!
Marius, wake up!
What's wrong today? You look as if you've seen a ghost.
Some wine and say what's going on!
A ghost you say... a ghost maybe She was just like a ghost to me>>
One minute there, and she was gone!
I am agog! I am aghast!
Is Marius in love at last?
I've never heard him `ooh' and `aah'>>
You talk of battles to be won>>
And here he comes like Don Ju-an>>
It's better than an o-per-a!
It is time for us all To decide who we are>>
Do we fight for the right To a night at the opera now?
Have you asked of yourselves What's the price you might pay?
Is it simply a game For rich young boys to play?
The colors of the world are changing day by day...>>
Red - the blood of angry men! Black - the dark of ages past!
Red - a world about to dawn! Black - the night that ends at last!
Had you seen here today You might know how it feels>>
To be struck to the bone In a moment of breathless delight!
Had you been there today You might also have known>>
How the world may be changed In just one burst of light!
And what was right seems wrong And what was wrong seems right!
Red.. I feel my soul on fire!
Black. My world if she's not there!
Red.. The color of desire!
Black... The color of despair!
Marius, you're no longer a child I do not doubt you mean it well>>
But now there is a higher call. Who cares about your lonely soul?
We strive toward a larger goal Our little lives don't count at all!
Red - the blood of angry men! Black - the dark of ages past!
Red - a world about to dawn! Black - the night that ends at last!
Listen everybody! Tell them that Lamarque is dead.
Lamarque is dead. It's the hour of fate.
The people's man. His death is the sign we await!
On his funeral day they will honor his name.
And the light of rebellion will be placed in their eyes.
In the death of Lamarque we will kindle our flame>>
In the 2 of the March shall oir barricades rise!
The time is here!
Let us welcome it gladly with courage and cheer>>
Let us take to the streets with no doubt in our hearts>>
But a jubilant shout>>
They will come one and all>>
They will come when we call!
24."Rue Plumet / In My Life" (Cosette, Valjean, Marius, Éponine)>>
How strange This feeling that my life's begun at last>>
This change, Can people really fall in love so fast?
What's the matter with you, Cosette?
Have you been too much on your own?
So many things unclear So many things unknown.
In my life>>
There are so many questions and answers That somehow seem wrong>>
There are times when I catch in the silence The sigh of a faraway song>>
And it sings>>
Of a world that I long to see Out of reach>>
Just a whisper away Waiting for me.
Does he know I'm alive? Do I know if he's real?
Does he see what I see? Does he feel what I feel?
In my life>>
I'm no longer alone Now the love in my life is so near>>
Find me now, find me here!
Dear Cosette, You're such a lonely child>>
How pensive, how sad you seem to me>>
Believe me, were it within my power>>
I'd fill each passing hour>>
How quiet it must be, I can see>>
With only me for company.
There's so little I know That I'm longing to know>>
Of the man that you were In a time long ago...>>
There's so little you say Of the life you have known>>
Why you keep to yourself Why we're always alone>>
So dark! So dark and deep... The secrets that you keep!
In my life>>
Please forgive what I say You are loving and gentle and good>>
But Papa, dear Papa,>>
In your eyes I am still like a child Who is lost in a wood>>
No more words No more words. It's a time that is dead>>
There are words, that are better unheard, better unsaid.
In my life>>
I'm no longer a child and I yearn For the truth that you know>>
Of the years... years ago!
You will learn>>
Truth is given by God To us all in our time, in our turn>>
In my life>>
She has burst like the music of angels The light of the sun>>
And my life seems to stop>>
As if something is over And something has scarcely begun.
Eponine You're the friend who has brought me here>>
Thanks to you I am one with the gods And Heaven is near!
And I soar through a world that is new that is free>>
Every word that he says is a dagger in me!
In my life There's been no one like him anywhere>>
Anywhere, where he is...>>
If he asked... I'd be his>>
In my life There is someone who touches my life>>
Waiting near>>
Waiting here>>
A heart full of love>>
A heart full of song I'm doing everything all wrong>>
Oh God, for shame I do not even know your name>>
Dear Mad'moiselle Won't you say? Will you tell?
A heart full of love No fear, no regret>>
My name is Marius Pontmercy And mine's Cosette>>
Cosette, I don't know what to say Then make no sound>>
I am lost I am found!
A heart full of light A night bright as day>>
A single look and then I knew I knew it too>>
These are words he'll never say Not to me...>>
His heart full of love He will never feel this way...>>
25."Plumet Attack">>
Who is this hussy?
It's your brat Eponine Don't you know your own kid>>
Why's she hanging about you?
Eponine, get on home You're not needed in this>>
We're enough here without you>>
I know this house I tell you there's nothing here for you>>
Just the old man and the girl They live ordinary lives>>
Don't interfere You've got some gall>>
Take care, young miss, You've got a lot to say!
I'm gonna scream, I'm gonna warn them here.
One little scream and you'll regret it for a year.
My God, Cosette!
You wait my girl, you'll rue this night>>
I'll make you scream, you'll scream all right>>
Must be Javert! He's found my cover at last!
I've got to get Cosette away>>
Then I'll arrange our passages to England>>
Hurry, Cosette, prepare to leave and say no more, Tonight we'll away!
Hurry, Cosette, it's time to close another door And live another day! Get dressed, we're leaving!
26."On My Own" (Éponine)>>
On My Own, Pretending he's beside me.
All alone, I walk with him till morning.
Without him, I feel his arms around me,>>
And when I lose my way I close my eyes>>
And he has found me.
In the rain, The pavement shines like silver.
All the lights Are misty in the river.
In the darkness, The trees are full of starlight,>>
And all I see is him and me for ever and forever.
And I know It's only in my mind,>>
That I'm talking to myself And not to him.
And although I know that he is blind,>>
Still I say, There's a way for us.
I love him, But when the night is over,>>
He is gone, The river's just a river.
Without him, The world around me changes.
The trees are bare and everywhere The streets are full of strangers.
I love him, But every day I'm learning,>>
All my life, I've only been pretending!
Without me, His world will go on turning,>>
The world is full of happiness that I have never known!
I love him...>>
But only on my own...>>
27."One Day More" (The Cast)>>
One day more! Another day, another destiny.
This never-ending road to Calvary;>>
These men who seem to know my crime Will surely come a second time.
One day more! I did not live until today.
How can I live when we are parted?
One day more. Tomorrow you'll be worlds away>>
And yet with you, my world has started!
One more day all on my own. Will we ever meet again?
One more day with him not caring. I was born to be with you.
What a life I might have known. And I swear I will be true!
But he never saw me there!
One more day before the storm! Do I follow where she goes?
At the barricades of freedom. Shall I join my brothers there?
When our ranks begin to form Do I stay; and do I dare?
Will you take your place with me? The time is now, the day is here>>
One day more!
One day more to revolution, We will nip it in the bud!
We'll be ready for these schoolboys, They will wet themselves with blood!
Watch 'em run amuck, Catch 'em as they fall,>>
Never know your luck When there's a free for all,>>
Here a little `dip' There a little `touch'>>
Most of them are goners So they won't miss much!
One day to a new beginning Raise the flag of freedom high!
Every man will be a king>>
There's a new world for the winning There's a new world to be won>>
Do you hear the people sing?
My place is here, I fight with you!
One day more! I will join these people's heros>>
We will follow where they go We will learn their little secrets,>>
We will know the things they know. One day more!
One day more to revolution, We will nip it in the bud!
We'll be ready for these schoolboys, Tomorrow is the judgement day>>
Tomorrow we'll discover What our God in Heaven has in store!
One more dawn One more day>>
One day more!
28."Do You Hear the People Sing?" (Students, Beggars)>>
Do you hear the people sing? Singing a song of angry men?
It is the music of a people Who will not be slaves again!
When the beating of your heart Echoes the beating of the drums>>
There is a life about to start When tomorrow comes!
Will you join in our crusade? Who will be strong and stand with me?
Beyond the barricade Is there a world you long to see?
Then join in the fight That will give you the right to be free!
Do you hear the people sing? Singing a song of angry men?
It is the music of a people Who will not be slaves again!
When the beating of your heart Echoes the beating of the drums>>
There is a life about to start When tomorrow comes!
Will you give all you can give So that our banner may advance>>
Some will fall and some will live Will you stand up and take your chance?
The blood of the martyrs Will water the meadows of France!
Do you hear the people sing? Singing a song of angry men?
It is the music of a people Who will not be slaves again!
When the beating of your heart Echoes the beating of the drums>>
There is a life about to start When tomorrow comes!
Red - the blood of angry men! Black - the dark of ages past!
Red - a world about to dawn! Black - the night that ends at last!
29."Javert's Arrival" (Javert, Enjolras)>>
Listen my friends I have done as I said>>
I have been to their lines I have counted each man.
I will tell what I can.
Better beware they have armies to spare and the danger is real>>
We will need all our cunning. to bring them to yield>>
Have faith. If you know what their movements are we'll spoil their game>>
There are ways that our people can fight we shall over come their power!
I have overheard their plans there will be no attack tonight>>
they intend to starve us out before they start a proper fight>>
concentrate their force hits us when is light.
Liar!
Good evening, dear inspector Lovely evening, my dear.
I know this man, my friends His name is Inspector Javert>>
So don't believe a word he says 'Cause nothing it's true>>
It only goes to show what little people can do!
Inspector Javert. Shoot me now or shoot me later>>
Every schoolboy to his fault Death to each and every traitor>>
I renounce your people's cause.
We keep looking forward>>
French revolution!
30."A Little Fall of Rain" (Éponine, Marius)>>
Don't you fret, M'sieur Marius>>
I don't feel any pain>>
A little fall of rain>>
Can hardly hurt me now>>
You're here, that's all I need to know>>
And you will keep me safe>>
And you will keep me close>>
And rain will make the flowers grow.
But you will live, 'Ponine - dear God above,>>
If I could close your wounds with words of love.
Just hold me now, and let it be.
Shelter me, comfort me>>
Don't you fret, M'sieur Marius>>
I don't feel any pain>>
A little fall of rain>>
Can hardly hurt me now>>
All I need to know>>
And you will keep me safe>>
And you will keep me close>>
And rain will make the flowers... grow.
You see that prisoner over there? A volunteer like you!
A spy who calls himself Javert! He's going to get it too...>>
Get in there! Get inside! Don't kill him! I know him!
Thank you M'sieur>>
Give me no thanks M'sieur There is something you can do.
If it is in my power.
Give me the spy Javert Let me take care of him!
Do what you have to do, The man belongs to you.
We meet again.
You've hungered for this all your life; Take your revenge!
How right you should kill with a knife!
Get out of here.
Valjean, take care! Clear out of here.
Once a thief, forever a thief What you want you always steal!
You would trade your life for mine. Yes, Valjean, you want a deal!
Shoot me now for all I care!
If you let me go, beware, You'll still answer to Javert!
You are wrong, and always have been wrong.
I'm a man, no worse than any man.
You are free, there are no conditions, No bargains or petitions.
There's nothing that I blame you for>>
You've done your duty, nothing more.
If I come out of this alive, you'll find me at the Rue de la Monaie at number 5>>
No doubt our paths will cross again.
Courfeyrac, you take the watch They may attack before it's light>>
Everybody keep the faith For certain we'll have to fight>>
As we are not alone For people who must rest>>
31."Drink With Me" (Marius, Students)>>
Drink with me to days gone by>>
To the life that used to be>>
At the shrine of friendship, never say die>>
Let the wine of friendship never run dry>>
Here's to you and here's to me>>
Do I care if I should die Now she goes across the sea?
Life without Cosette Means nothing at all.
Would you weep, Cosette, if I would fall?
Would you weep, Cosette, For me?
32."Bring Him Home" (Valjean)>>
God on high Hear my prayer>>
In my need You have always been there>>
He is young He's afraid>>
Let him rest Heaven blessed.
Bring him home>>
He's like the son I might have known>>
If God had granted me a son.
The summers die One by one>>
How soon they fly On and on>>
And I am old And will be gone.
Bring him peace Bring him joy>>
He is young He is only a boy>>
You can take You can give>>
Let him be Let him live>>
If I die, let me die Let him live>>
Bring him home>>
32."The Second Attack" (Death of Gavroche)>>
Do you hear the people sing Singing the song of angry men?
It is the music of a people Who will not be slaves again.
When the beating of your heart Echoes the beating of the drums>>
There is a life about to start When tomorrow comes!
Little people know, when little people fight,>>
We may look easy pickings But we've got some bite!
So never kick a dog Because he's just a pup>>
We'll fight like 20 armies And we won't give up>>
So you'd better run for cover When the pup grows......>>
33."The Final Battle" (Army officer, Students)>>
You at the barricade listen to this>>
The people of Paris sleep in their beds>>
You have no chance No chance at all>>
Why throw your lives away?
Let us die facing our foes Make them bleed while we can>>
Make 'em pay through the nose Make 'em pay for every man!
Let others rise to take our place Until the earth is free!
You're alive! I've saved you.
It's you, Javert! I knew you wouldn't wait too long>>
The faithful servant at his post once more!
This man's done no wrong, And he needs a doctor's care.
I warned you I would not give in I won't be swayed>>
Another hour yet And then I'm yours>>
And all our debts are paid.
The man of mercy comes again And talks of justice>>
Come, time is running short Look down, Javert>>
He's standing in his grave>>
34."Javert's Suicide" (Javert)>>
Who is this man? What sort of devil is he?
To have me caught in a trap And choose to let me go free?
It was his hour at last To put a seal on my fate,>>
Wipe out the past, And wash me clean off the slate.
All it would take was a flick of his knife.
Vengeance was his and he gave me back my life!
Damned if I'll live in the debt of a thief>>
Damned if I'll yield at the end of the chase>>
I am the Law and the Law is not mocked>>
I'll spit his pity right back in his face>>
There is nothing on earth that we share>>
It is either Valjean or Javert!
And my thoughts fly apart. Can this man be believed?
Shall his sins be forgiven? Shall his crimes be reprieved?
And must I now begin to doubt, Who never doubted all those years?
My heart is stone and still it trembles.
The world I have known is lost in shadow.
Is he from heaven or from hell?
And does he know That, granting me my life today,>>
This man has killed me even so?
I am reaching but I fall And the stars are black and cold>>
As I stare into the void Of a world that cannot hold>>
I'll escape now from that world From the world of Jean Valjean.
There is nowhere I can turn There is now way to go on...>>
Did you see them Going off to fight?
Children of the barricade Who didn't last the night?
Did you see them Lying where they died?
Someone used to cradle them And kiss them when they cried.
Did you see them lying side by side?
35."Empty Chairs at Empty Tables" (Marius)>>
There's a grief that can't be spoken.
There's a pain goes on and on.
Empty chairs at empty tables>>
Now my friends are dead and gone.
Here they talked of revolution>>
Here it was they lit the flame.
Here they sang about `tomorrow'>>
And tomorrow never came.
From the table in the corner>>
They could see a world reborn>>
And they rose with voices ringing I can hear them now!
The very words that they had sung>>
Became their last communion>>
On the lonely barricade at dawn.
Oh my friends, my friends forgive me>>
That I live and you are gone.
There's a grief that can't be spoken.
There's a pain goes on and on.
Phantom faces at the window.
Phantom shadows on the floor.
Empty chairs at empty tables Where my friends will meet no more.
Oh my friends, my friends, don't ask me>>
What your sacrifice was for>>
Empty chairs at empty tables Where my friends will sing no more.
36."Every Day / Heart Full of Love" (Marius, Cosette)>>
Every day you walk with stronger step>>
You walk with longer step- `The worst is over.'>>
Don't think about it, Marius! With all the years ahead of us!
I will never go away And we will be together>>
Every day.
Every day, we'll remember that night And the vow that we made:>>
A heart full of love A night full of you>>
The words are old But always true.
Cosette, Cosette! Waiting for you>>
At your feet>>
And it wasn't a dream Not a dream after all>>
M'sieur, this is a day I never can forget.
Is gratitude enough For giving me Cosette?
Your home shall be with us And not a day shall pass>>
But we will prove our love To you, whom we shall call>>
A father to us both A father to us all.
Not another word my son,>>
There's something now that must be done.
37."Valjean's Confession" (Valjean, Marius)>>
There lived a man whose hame was Jean Valjean>>
He stole some bread to save his sister's son.
For 19 winters served his time>>
In sweat he washed away his crime.
Years ago He broke parole and lived a life apart>>
How could he tell Cosette and break her heart?
It's for Cosette this must be faced If he is caught she is disgraced>>
The time has come to journey on And from this day he must be gone>>
Who am I?
You're Jean Valjean!
Monsieur, you cannot leave.
Whatever I tell my beloved Cosette She will never believe!
Tell her I have gone on a journey A long way away.
Tell her my heart was too full for farewells It is better this way.
Promise me, M'sieur, Cosette will never know... what I have spoken, why I must go.
For the sake of Cosette, it must be so.
38."Wedding Chorale" (Chorus)>>
Ring out the bells Upon this day of days!
May all the angels Of the Lord above>>
In jubilation Sing their songs of praise!
And crown this blessed time with Peace and love.
The Baron and Baroness de Thénard>>
Go away, Thénardier! Do you think I don't know who you are?
He's not fooled. Told you so.
Show M'sieur what you've come here to show. Tell the boy what you know!
Pity to disturb you at a feast like this But 500 francs surely wouldn't come amiss.
In God's name say what you have to say.
He speaks you pay!
What I saw, clear as light, Jean Valjean in the sewers one night.
Had this corpse on his back Some boy he had killed in a vicious attack.
I was there, never fear. Even found me this fine souvenir.
I know this! This was mine! This is surely some heavenly sign!
Then it's true. Then I'm right. Jean Valjean was my savior that night!
Jean Valjean, the old con. You pay up or I say where he's gone.
Where is he?
Where is he? The convent.
39."Beggars at the Feast" (Thénardier and Mme.)>>
Watch the buggers dance Watch 'em till they drop>>
Keep your wits about you And you stand on top!
Masters of the land Always get our share>>
Clear away the barricades And we're still there!
We know where the wind is blowing Money is the stuff we smell.
And when we're rich as Croesus Jesus! Won't we see you all in hell!
40."Valjean's Death" (Valjean, Fantine, Cosette, Marius, Bishop of Digne)>>
Alone I wait in the shadows I count the hours untill I sleep>>
I dreamed a dream Cosette stood by It made her weep to know I die.
Alone at the end of the day Upon this wedding night I pray>>
Take these children, my Lord, to thy embrace And show them grace.
God on high Hear my prayer>>
Take me now To thy care>>
Where You are Let me be>>
Take me now Take me there>>
Bring me home>>
M'sieur, I bless your name M'sieur, lay down your burden>>
You raised my child in love And you will be with god.
Papa, Papa, I do not understand! Are you alright? Why did you go away?
Cosette, my child, am I forgiven now? Thank God, thank God, I've lived to see this day.
It's you who must forgive a thoughtless fool It's you who must forgive a thankless man>>
It's thanks to you that I am living And again I lay down my life at your feet.
Cosette, your father is a saint.
When they wounded me He took me from the barricade>>
Carried like a babe And brought me home to you!
Now you are here Again beside me>>
Now I can die in peace For now my life is blessed...>>
You will live, Papa, you're going to live It's too soon, too soon to say goodbye!
Yes, Cosette, forbid me now to die I'll obey, I will try.
On this page I write my last confession.
Read it well When I at last am sleeping.
It's the story Of one who turned from hating.
A man who only learned to love with you and his keeping.
Come with me Where chains will never bind you>>
All your grief At last, at last behind you.
Lord in Heaven, Look down on him in mercy.
Forgive me all my trespasses And take me to your glory.
Take my hand I'll lead you to salvation.
Take my love, For love is everlasting.
And remember The truth that once was spoken>>
To love another person Is to see the face of God!
41."Do You Hear the People Sing?" (The Cast) Lost in the valley of the night?
It is the music of a people Who are climbing to the light.
For the wretched of the earth There is a flame that never dies.
Even the darkest night will end And the sun will rise.
They will live again in freedom In the garden of the Lord.
They will walk behind the plough-share, They will put away the sword.
The chain will be broken And all men will have their reward.
Will you join in our crusade? Who will be strong and stand with me?
Somewhere beyond the barricade Is there a world you long to see?
Do you hear the people sing? Say, do you hear the distant drums?
It is the future that they bring When tomorrow comes!
Will you join in our crusade? Who will be strong and stand with me?
Somewhere beyond the barricade Is there a world you long to see?
Do you hear the people sing? Say, do you hear the distant drums?
It is the future that they bring When tomorrow comes...>>
Tomorrow comes!
(b.1968, AUS) as Jean Valjean, the ex-con then Mayor>>
(b.1964, NZ) as Javert, the inspector>>
(b.1982, US) as Fantine, the factory worker>>
(b.1985, US) as Cosette, daughter of Fantine>>
(b.1982, UK) as Marius, student>>
(b.1983, US) as Enjolras, student>>
(b.1990, UK) as Eponine>>
as young Cosette>>
as Gavroche, the kid>>
(b.1966, UK) as Mme. Thenardier>>
(b.1971, UK) as Thenardier>>