Ana, take my car.
I gave you the recorder, right?
Oh, yes.
And you have all the questions?
Yes.
And you know where you're going?
Yes, I do have a GPS.
And a 4.0 GPA.
I can figure it out.
Are you wearing that?
Okay, maybe a little less talking,>>
more eating.
How about that?
Wow.
Miss Kavanagh?
May I take your coat?
Oh. Yeah. Um...>>
She's... Okay, so...>>
Mr. Grey will see you now.
Okay.
This way, please.
a conference call at 11 :15.
Right this way.
Miss Kavanagh.
Are you all right?
Christian Grey.
I'm Anastasia Steele.
Um, Miss Kavanagh has the flu, so she asked me to fill in.
I see.
So, you're studying journalism as well.
No, English Lit.
Urn...>>
Kate's my roommate.
As I said, I only have 10 minutes.
Please, have a seat, Miss Steele.
Okay.
Thank you.
Ready?
Whenever you are.
Okay. Urn...>>
So, this is for the special graduation issue>>
of the student newspaper.
Yes, I'm giving the commencement address at this year's ceremony.
You are?
Imean, urn...>>
I know.
Uh... "You are very young to have amassed such an empire.
"To what do you owe your...">>
To what do I owe my success?
Yep.
Seriously?
Yes.
Business is about people.
And I've always been good at people.
What motivates them, what incentivizes them,>>
what inspires them.
Um, maybe you're just lucky.
I've always found that the harder I work,>>
the more luck I seem to have.
The key to my success has been in identifying talented individuals>>
and harnessing their efforts.
So, you're a control freak?
Oh, I exercise control in all things, Miss Steele.
Okay. Urn...>>
"Your company is involved primarily>>
"in the telecommunications sector,>>
"yet you also invest in numerous agricultural projects,>>
"including several in Africa.
"Is that something that you feel passionate about?
"Feeding the world's poor?">>
It's smart business.
You don't agree?
I don't know enough about it.
I just wonder if>>
perhaps your heart might be a bit bigger than you want to let on?
There are some people who say that I don't have a heart at all.
Why would they say that?
Because they know me well.
Go on.
Um... "Do you have any interests outside of work?">>
I enjoy various physical pursuits.
You're unmarried.
Oh.
You were adopted at age four.
That's a matter of public record.
I'm sorry, I didn't...>>
Do you have an actual question, Miss Steele?
Yeah, sorry.
"Are you gay?">>
It's written here, I'm just...>>
No, Anastasia.
I'm not gay.
I apologize, Mr. Grey. Kate can be a little...>>
Intrusive?
Curious.
What about you?
Why don't you ask me something that you want to know?
Earlier, you said that there are some people who know you well.
Why do I get the feeling that, that is not true?
Mr. Grey, your next meeting is in the conference room.
Cancel, please. We're not finished here.
Yes, sir.
No... I'm...>>
I can go. It's fine.
I would like to know more about you.
There's really not much to know about me.
You said you're an English major?
Tell me, was it Charlotte Bronté,>>
Jane Austen, or Thomas Hardy>>
who first made you faHinlove with literature?
Hardy.
I would have guessed Jane Austen.
What are your plans after you graduate?
I'm just trying to get through finals right now.
And then?
And then I was planning on moving here, to Seattle,>>
with Kate.
We offer an excellent internship program.
I don't think I'd fit in here.
Look at me.
I am.
I hope you got everything you needed.
I... I think you only answered four questions.
Anastasia.
Christian.
Holy cow.
Urn...>>
Before you say anything...>>
You're a goddess. This is perfect.
What?
I just got his e-mail. He answered every question.
So, what was he like?
Urn...>>
He was fine.
"Fine"?
Just fine?
Um, he was really polite,>>
and he was courteous,>>
and very formal,>>
and clean.
"Clean"?
I mean, he was very smart.
And intense.
It was kind of intimidating.
I can understand the fascination.
Uh-huh.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Like what?
Okay.
I'm gonna make a sandwich. Do you want one?
No, thanks.
You have to admit, he's ridiculously hot.
I'm sure if you>>
are attracted to that sort of human, then...>>
The hot type of human?
I asked him if he was gay. That was in your questions.
Why would you do that to me?
Because whenever he's in the society pages,>>
he's never been photographed with a woman- So, naturally...>>
Well, maybe he just wants to keep his private life private, Kate.
And now you're defending him.
I'm terminating this conversation.
Too bad we don't have some original stills>>
of your hot, clean 27-year-old billionaire.
The camera loves him almost as much as you do.
Okay, I wasn't hungry, but now I am.
Thank you.
I love you.
"I declared I could not change,>>
"yet you tell me to my face>>
"I shall change soon.
"And what a distortion in yourjudgment,>>
"what a perversity in your ideas...">>
Ana. I've been looking for you. What's up?
Guess what. What?
Portland Place is going to exhibit my photographs next month.
Oh, my God.
Congratulations! That's so good!
Solo show, corazén.
Can we celebrate later? Because I'm really late for work.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You got it. But, um...>>
Hold on.
Thank you.
You're my hero.
I'll see you later.
Mom, I'm at work. Can I call you back?
Oh, no, wait. I called for a reason.
Bob broke his foot playing golf, of all things.
God. Is he okay? Is he in a lot of pain?
Who can tell with the man?
He calls the paramedics for a blister.
It means, though, we won't be able to fly in for graduation.
Really?
You don't wanna just come alone? You don't have to bring Bob.
Ah. And leave Tiger Woods to fend for himself?
You do understand. Don't you, darling?
Yeah. Yeah, it's fine.
Um, I really have to go, okay?
I love you, Ana.
I know. I love you, too.
Oh, God.
Ana.
Could you give me a hand out back?
Uh, yeah. I'll be right there.
I thought it was you.
What the...>>
What a pleasant surprise, Miss Steele.
Just "Ana.">>
You're in here.
I was in the area on business.
I needed to pick up a few things.
Are you free?
Yeah.
What can I help you with?
Do you stock cable ties?
Cable ties, yes. We do.
I can show you, if you want.
Please lead the way, Miss Steele.
Just "Ana.">>
Is that it?
Masking tape.
Are you redecorating?
No.
Um, we have two-inch and one-inch.
But the truly self-respecting handyman>>
will have both in his toolbox.
Of course he will. Mmm-hmm.
It's rare to find a connoisseur these days.
Do you want anything else?
Yes.
Rope.
That's impressive.
Are you a Girl Scout?
Urn, no.
Organized group activities aren't really my thing.
So what is your "thing"?
Urn...>>
I don't know. Books?
Okay.
Rope, tape, cable ties.
You're the complete serial killer.
Not today.
Anything else?
What would you recommend?
For a do-it-yourself er? Um...>>
Maybe coveralls, so you protect your clothes.
I could just take all my clothes off.
Okay.
No clothes.
I mean, no coveralls.
I can't think of anything else.
Well, I guess that's it, then.
Cool.
Thank you for answering Kate's questions, by the way.
She was thrilled.
I hope she's feeling better.
She is, yeah, much.
She's just having a hard time clearing a photo of you, I think.
If she'd like an original, I'm around tomorrow.
You'd be willing to do that?
Yeah.
Want me to bag for you, Ana?
Oh. Uh, no, I'm good. Thanks, though, Paul.
Okay.
I'm staying locally at the Heathman.
Call me before 10:00.
About the photos.
Oh.
Yeah, I will.
EnJOY your...>>
Thanks again for doing this, Mr. Grey.
I'm happy to help.
Uh, how about we try a few with a smile?
Or not.
You do realize that he hasn't stopped looking at you.
He asked me to go for coffee afterwards.
What?
Kate, shh.
So, is he your boyfriend?
Who?
The photographer.
José?
No.
I saw the way he was smiling at you.
No, José is more like family.
He's not my boyfriend.
And the guy at the store?
Paul?
No.
Thank you.
You seem nervous.
I find you intimidating.
You should.
Eat.
Not to mention high-handed.
I'm used to getting my own way.
That must get very boring.
Tell me about your family.
My family? Um...>>
Okay.
My dad died when I was a baby.
So, I was raised by my stepfather, Ray.
He's amazing.
And your mother?
Um, my mother is on husband number four.
She's an incurable romantic.
Are you?
Am I a romantic?
Well, I study English Lit.
So, I kind of have to be.
I thought the photo shoot went well. Right?
Kate seems to be really...>>
I'm sorry, I can't...>>
What?
I'll walk you out.
Do you have a girlfriend? Is that it?
I don't do the girlfriend thing.
What does that even... Watch it!
I'm not the man for you.
You should steer clear of me.
I have to let you go.
Goodbye, Mr. Grey.
All right, pencils down.
Please take your final exams to the back of the classroom.
Final grades will be posted in two weeks.
Hey. You all good?
Yeah. Why wouldn't I be?
We are so partying tonight.
on, my God.
This is way too much.
No, this is exactly the right amount.
You're getting it all over my face.
That's the idea.
Wow. No, Kate.
Cab's early. Let's go.
Ana, it's a package for you.
"Why didn't you tell me there was danger?
"Why didn't you warn me?
"Ladies know what to guard against>>
"because they read novels that tell them of these tricks.">>
That's a quote from Tess of the D'Urbervilles.
Oh, my God.
These must be from Christian.
Do you... I mean...>>
These are incredible.
Wow, Grey.
Kate, these are first editions.
I can't.
This is too much.
I can't accept these. I have to send them back.
That's the cab.
Okay, are you ready?
Are you ready to go? Yes. Yes, very.
Let's get out of here.
- Shots first... - Shots, shots, shots!
Hold on. Nobody hold back, either.
Did you do it all?
All right. With my eyes closed>>
and left-handed, I can get this in.
- What? - Ready?
I gotta pee. Okay.
Where ' I gotta go. you 90mg?
I gotta pee.
Anastasia?
Yeah, this is me.
I'm sending back your expensive books,>>
because I already have copies of those.
Thanks, though, for the kind gesture.
You're welcome. Where are you?
I'm in line, because I have to pee really bad.
Anastasia, have you been drinking?
Yeah.
I have, Mr. Fancy Pants.
You hit the hail on the nead.
I mean, the head right on the nail.
Listen to me. I want you to go home right now.
You're so bossy.
"Ana, let's go for coffee.">>
"No, stay away from me, Ana.
"I don't want you. Get away.">>
"Come here, come here." "Go away.">>
That's it. Tell me where you are.
I'm a long way from Seattle.
A long way from you.
Which bar? What's it called?
I don't know. I gotta go, though.
Which bar, Ana?
I told him. Right?
I'm sorry, I didn't...>>
Stay where you are. I'm coming to get you.
What?
Hello?
Hey.
Oh, thanks.
You okay?
Yeah. I'm just a little bit more drunk than...>>
Come here, stay warm.
Oh, it's cool. I'm good, José. I got it.
I don't know when I'll have the courage to do this.
Do what?
Ana. I like you. No.
You do? Very much.
Oh, my God.
Please.
One kiss.
No, no, no.
José, I don't... I'm sorry, no.
Dude, she said no!
Christian?
- Don't look at me. Ugh. - Here.
N ice touch.
I will launder this item.
Let's get you home.
I'm with Kate.
I'll have Elliot tell her.
Who's Elliot?
He's my brother. He's inside, talking to her right now.
How... I don't...>>
He was at my hotel with me.
You're still at the Heathman?
Yeah.
Come.
That's your brother?
Not by choice. Let's go.
Wait, what did Kate say?
She warned me to be on my best behavior.
More like threatened me.
She threatened you?
You're spinning.
I think I'm gonna faint.
What? Now?
Good morning, Anastasia.
How are you feeling?
Better than I deserve.
Did you put me to bed?
Mmm-hmm.
You undressed me?
I didn't have much choice.
Where did you sleep?
Oh, my God. Did we? We didn't...>>
Necrophilia is not my thing.
So we just slept, then?
It was a novelty for me, too.
You need to eat.
I had Taylor pick you up some clothes.
Who's Taylor?
My driver.
Thank you, but you didn't have to do that.
Yes, I did.
Yours were covered in vomit.
You shouldn't get drunk like that.
I'm all for testing the limits,>>
but you put yourself at risk last night.
I know.
If you were mine, you wouldn't be able to sit down for a week.
What?
I gotta go take a shower.
Why am I here, Christian?
You're here because I'm incapable of leaving you alone.
Then don't.
Why did you send me those books?
I thought I owed you an apology.
For what?
For letting you believe that I...>>
Listen to me.
I don't do romance.
My tastes are very>>
singular.
You wouldn't understand.
Enlighten me, then.
You look beautiful.
Taylor has good taste.
What are you doing later?
I'm working at the hardware store until 7:00.
I'll have Taylor pick you up then.
I would like to bite that lip.
I think I'd like that, too.
I'm not gonna touch you.
Not until I have your written consent.
What?
I'll explain later.
Come, I'll take you home.
Fuck the paperwork.
As I was saying...>>
What is it about elevators?
Hey.
Hi. You must be Ana.
You must be Elliot.
And we must be going. Elliot...>>
So awesome to meet you.
Kate's told me a lot about you.
Elliot, find your shoes. Some of us have work to attend to.
What you're doing with Mr. Warmth here,>>
I have no idea.
Laters, baby.
I'll see you tonight.
E-mail me if something changes.
My computer's broken.
Call, then. I know you have my number.
Laters, baby.
Elliot seems like a really nice guy.
Uh-uh. No, no. We're starting with you.
If you're seeing him again tonight,>>
that means that something happened.
Ana. Mmm-hmm.
Ana, you have to tell me what happened.
I have to get ready for work.
We just kissed.
Once.
Only once? That's odd.
Mmm.
"Odd" doesn't even cover it.
Uh-huh.
And a new jacket.
Hmm.
Bye.
Hi. It's Taylor, right?
Good evening, Miss Steele. Mr. Grey will be joining us there.
Good evening, Anastasia.
Wait. You're flying this?
No escaping now.
November 1 -2-2-4. Charlie Tango, ready to depart.
Roger that, Charlie Tango.
Your flight plan from Portland to Seattle is cleared.
Seattle? That's where we're going?
Would you like a drink?
Yes, please.
Wow.
Do you DEV?
Yes.
Of course you do.
What's this?
It's a non-disclosure agreement.
It means that you cannot discuss>>
anything about us with anyone.
I'm afraid my lawyer insists on it.
I'd never talk to anyone about us, anyway.
Are you gonna make love to me now?
Two things.
First, I don't make love.
I fuck.
Hard.
And the second thing?
Come.
It's just beyond this door.
What is?
MY Play room.
Like your Xbox and stuff?
It's important that you know you can leave at any time.
Why? What's in there?
I meant what I said.
The helicopter's on standby to take you whenever you wanna go.
Christian, just open the door.
Oh, my God.
It's called a flogger.
Say something, please.
Do women do this to you? Or do you...>>
No, I do this to women. With women.
Women who want me to.
You're a sadist?
I'm a dominant.
What does that mean?
It means I want you to willingly surrender yourself to me.
Why would I do that?
To please me.
To please you?
How?
I have rules.
If you follow them, I'll reward you.
If you don't, I'll punish you.
You'll punish me...>>
Like, you'd use this stuff on me?
Yes.
What would I get out of this?
Me.
If we were to do this,>>
this would be your room.
You can decorate it however you like.
You want me to move in?
Not full time. Just Friday through to Sunday.
We can negotiate the particulars.
So, uh...>>
So, I'd sleep in here with you?
No. I'd be downstairs.
I told you, I don't sleep with anyone.
What if I don't want anything to do with that?
I would understand completely.
But then we wouldn't have any sort of relationship at all?
This is the only sort of relationship I have.
Why?
It's the way I am.
When you said "negotiate,">>
what did you mean?
I already have a contract prepared. It's fairly detailed.
You would review it,>>
and we would negotiate what you are and are not willing to try.
How could I know what I'd be willing to try?
Well, when you've had sex>>
was there anything that you didn't like doing?
We have to be honest with each other for this to work, okay?
I wouldn't know.
What do you mean?
Because I haven't...>>
You're still a virgin?
I have just shown you...>>
I know. I just...>>
You've done other things, right?
No.
Where have you been?
Waiting.
Men must throw themselves at you.
Never one I've wanted.
You're biting your lip.
What are you doing?
Rectifying the situation.
I'm a situation?
Mmm.
You're energetic this morning.
You hungry?
Very.
Because I'm making pancakes.
Let's get you cleaned up.
Do you trust me?
Stay here.
Hold out your wrists.
Hold them there.
You understand?
Tell me you understand.
I won't move my arms.
Good girl.
Stay still.
Okay.
llyes-ll>>
To what?
To being mine.
No need to announce me. Christian!
Shit. What?
It's my mother.
I'm naked. Get dressed.
And there's no need to show me around.
And there's no need to hover.
He's still sleeping, Dr. Grey.
He's still sleeping?
But he never sleeps in. Certainly not at this hour.
Unless, of course, he's ill. Is he... Ah.
Sorry, Mr. Grey.
It's fine. I know how she can be.
"She"?
Well, if you're trying to avoid me,>>
the very least you can do>>
is call me by my correct name, which would be "Mum.">>
Hi.
Oh. Dear God.
Mother, Anastasia Steele.
Ana, meet my mother, Dr. Grace Trevelyan Grey.
You have no idea how delighted I am to meet you.
It's nice to meet you, too, Dr. Grey.
"Grace.">>
She's very pretty. You're very pretty.
Thank you. Mmm-hmm.
So, what happened to calling before dropping by?
And have your henchmen give me the runaround?
No, thank you. I'll take my chances.
Anyway, I was in the neighborhood,>>
and I thought perhaps we could have lunch.
I can't today. I have to drive Ana home.
It's okay. Take it. I was just showing Mother out.
Excuse me.
Anastasia... Kate, hold on.
It was a joy to meet you.
And I'm having the whole family>>
for dinner next week at my house.
Christian's sister, Mia, is back from Paris.
You must come.
We'll see, Mother.
Nice to meet you.
You, too.
Thank you.
I can't talk about it right now, Kate.
I gotta go. I'll call you back, okay?
Everything okay with the phone call?
Yeah. Nothing important.
I liked your morn.
She's excited. She's never seen me with a woman before.
It was a first.
What is it, Ana?
Urn...>>
I just...>>
How many women have stayed in here?
Fifteen.
That's a lot of women.
I told you before, if you want out...>>
I don't want out. I just...>>
I'm not exactly jumping at the opportunity>>
to get whipped and tortured in your red room of pain.
That room is much more about pleasure.
Promise you.
Would we still go out to dinner and movies?
That's not really my thing.
Try to keep an open mind.
If you agree to be my submissive,>>
I will be devoted to you.
This is what I want.
And I want it with you.
Why do I have to sleep in here?
We slept in the same bed last night.
Like normal people.
Try not to get hung up on the sleeping arrangements.
If you agree to do this,>>
you're gonna want your own room.
Why, because I'll be your sex slave?
I don't wanna do this here. Let's talk downstairs.
No. You know what?
I think I'll hold on to my free will>>
a little while longer, thank you.
Actually, you know what? I would like to go home. Can I go home?
Which one's yours?
All of them.
Let's go for a walk.
How did you start doing this?
One of my mother's friends.
I was 15.
She seduced you?
I was her submissive for six years.
Seriously?
Does your mother know that?
Of course not.
No one in my family knows about this part of me.
So, she introduced you to all this?
Mrs. Robinson?
"Mrs. Robinson.">>
I'll tell her you said that. She'll love it.
You still talk to her?
On occasion.
We're friends.
Ana.
I know how intimidating this is.
I felt the same at first.
Well, what changed your mind?
By giving up control, I felt free.
From responsibility, from making decisions.
I felt safe.
You will, too, you'll see.
I've never taken anyone in the helicopter.
I've never had sex in my own bed.
I've never slept next to anyone.
Ever.
Only you.
This is the contract.
Read it carefully.
E-mail me if you have any questions.
I told you, my computer's down.
Just consider it, okay?
I really hope you say yes.
Thanks for the ride.
Laters, baby.
Urn...>>
Okay, you're all set.
Your roommate let me in.
I just figured that you forgot to tell me about it- Do I look okay?
Tell you about what? Just sign here.
Hold on. Do you have the right apartment?
Anastasia Steele?
EnXOY ->>
Another gift, huh?
Whatever happened to flowers and chocolates?
I'm dying to hear everything.
But I have to run right now, because Elliot and I are having dinner>>
and then we're going to see a show at The Gorge.
José called for you. Twice, by the way.
Did the mail already come?
Oh. Um, no, this is...>>
These are my thesis notes. I left them at school.
Oh. All right. Well, there's yesterday's mail.
What?
I don't know.
You look different.
I feel different.
Of course you do.
Okay.
Bye!
The fundamental purpose of this contract>>
is to allow the Submissive to explore>>
her sensuality and her limits safely.
The Dominant and Submissive agree and acknowledge>>
that all that occurs under the terms of this contract>>
will be consensual, confidential,>>
and subject to the agreed limits>>
and safety procedures set out in this contract.
The Submissive will agree>>
to any sexual activity deemed fit and pleasurable by the Dominant,>>
excepting those activities outlined in Hard Limits->>
...so much. Thank you.
The Submissive will not drink to excess, smoke, or take recreational drugs,>>
or put her person into any unnecessary risk.
The Submissive will not enter into sexual relations>>
with anyone other than the Dominant.
The Submissive agrees to procure oral contraception>>
from a physician of the Dominant's choosing.
The Submissive will eat regularly>>
to maintain her health and well-being>>
from a prescribed list of foods. Appendix Four.
The Submissive will obey any instruction given by the Dominant.
She will do so eagerly and without hesitation.
The Submissive may not touch the Dominant>>
without his expressed permission to do so.
The Submissive shall always conduct herself>>
in a respectful manner to the Dominant,>>
- and she'll address him only as "Sir, " "Mr. - Grey...">>
...or such other title as the Dominant may direct.
The Dominant may flog, spank, whip, or corporaiiy punish the Submissive>>
as he sees fit, for purposes of discipline>>
or for his personal enjoyment.
The safeword "Yellow“ will be used>>
to bring to the attention of the Dominant>>
that the Submissive is close to her limit.
When the safeword "Red" is spoken,>>
the Dominanfs action will cease completely and immediately.
Does the Submissive consent to being restrained with hands bound in front?
Does the Submissive consent to being blindfolded?
Does the Submissive consent to being gagged?
How much pain is the Submissive willing to experience?
Christian.
It's been "nice" knowing me, has it?
Let me remind you how "nice" it was.
Is this what you want?
Don't make a sound.
Was this "nice"?
That was really nice.
What are you doing to me?
What about here?
Why not?
Is it breaking the rules?
Speaking of which...>>
I haven't made up my mind yet.
You're not staying?
I told you, I don't sleep with anyone.
Well, can we negotiate?
Now, that's a hell of a sack, Miss Steele.
Business meeting.
Impressive.
I've done this before.
Business meetings, I mean.
Oh.
Miss Steele. Hmm?
Your meeting.
Page one.
Strike out my old address and replace with the new one.
An oversight. Duly noted.
Page three, section 1520.
"The Submissive shall submit to any>>
"sexual activity demanded by the Dominant>>
"and shall do so without hesitation or argument.">>
Uh, turn to page five.
Appendix Three, "Soft Limits.">>
With you.
Find "anal fisting.">>
I'm all ears.
Strike it out.
Strike out "vaginal fisting," too.
Are you sure?
Yep.
Same page, “ls the use of sex toys acceptable to the Submissive?">>
Vibrators, okay. Dildos, fine.
Genital clamps?
Absolutely not.
Consider them gone.
What are butt plugs?
You must go through quite a few non-disclosure agreements.
My staff know only what I choose to tell them.
Please resume, Miss Steele.
Also on page five, there are some terms which need clarification.
"Suspension"?
Hanging on ropes from the ceiling.
For what possible reason?
For your pleasure.
Really?
And mine.
Something to consider.
No. Hard limit.
I'm good with rope,>>
leather cuffs, handcuffs.
Please lose "tape.">>
And what's "Other"?
Cable ties.
Can I just say how impressed I am>>
with your commitment to this meeting?
And in that spirit, I'm gonna throw in a sweetener.
How about once a week,>>
on a night of your choosing,>>
we go on a date?
Just like a regular couple.
Dinner, movie,>>
ice skating.
Whatever you want.
Accepted.
You're very kind.
I'll suggest it in Appendix Five.
I would like to fuck you into the middle of next week.
You're not fighting fair.
I never have.
I'll review all these changes and try to arrive at a decision.
You wanna leave?
Yes.
But your body tells me something different.
Your legs, for instance.
The way you're pressing your thighs together under the table.
And the change in your breathing.
And in your complexion.
My complexion?
You're flushed.
That could just be the wine.
It's the adrenaline.
Say I did stay.
What would happen?
First.
I would help you out of that little dress of yours.
Yes.
And I'd be pleased to discover that you're naked underneath.
Really?
Then I would bend you over.
Right here?
Yes.
On this table?
Thank you for the meeting, Mr. Grey.
This is me.
Didn't know I was a collector of classic cars, huh?
You sure I can't persuade you to stay?
Good night, Christian.
When will you know?
Soon, maybe.
Why do I think you're telling me goodbye?
Because I'm leaving.
You got your valedictory speech ready?
Oh, more or less.
Annie!
Hi!
Sorry I'm late. I had a hell of a time parking.
That's okay. You're here, that's all that matters.
You kidding me? lwouldn't miss this for the world->>
I saved you a seat next to Kate's parents.
Anywhere you want me, sweetheart.
- Okay. I'll see you after. Yeah->>
Good luck up there.
And he's also a major benefactor to our university.
Please join me in welcoming Mr. Christian Grey.
Thank you.
I am deeply moved by the great compliment accorded to me today.
He is so hot.
Oh, God. He so is.
I heard he's gay.
The goal?
To help eradicate hunger and poverty across the globe.
I myself>>
have known what it's like to be profoundly hungry.
So this is a very personal mission for me.
Megan Soliah.
Anastasia Steele.
Nancy Hines.
Congratulations. You should be very proud.
I am.
Nice tie, by the way.
It's recently become my favorite.
Do you have your answer yet?
I'm still thinking.
Anastasia, just try it my way. Please.
Okay.
What?
Congratulations. Thank you.
We did it, we did it, we did it!
Dad! Hi.
I am so proud of you, Annie.
Thank you.
And, Kate, best Valedictorian speech ever.
Oh, thank you. It was awesome.
Yeah... Ana. Hi.
Hi.
Ray, have you met Christian Grey, Ana's boyfriend?
Hi. Great pleasure to meet you.
Likewise. I really enjoyed your speech.
Thank you, sir.
Sounds like you have accomplished some pretty impressive things.
- I'll say. - Thank you.
Well, I'm gonna go find my family>>
who've been patiently waiting to embarrass me.
Bye. Come see us in Seattle, okay?
Yeah, as soon as I get an invitation.
So, how long have you two known each other?
Um... Mmm-hmm. A few weeks, now.
We actually met when Anastasia>>
interviewed me for the student newspaper.
Uh, picture, please, Mr. Grey?
Excuse us a moment.
Big smile, now.
To celebrate your graduation,>>
among other things.
Roll your eyes at me again>>
and I will take you across my knee.
Oh.
So it begins.
Mmm- Come on. I have something to show you.
What?
That's cute.
Doesn't really seem like your style, though.
It's not.
Happy graduation, Anastasia.
Christian, that's a car.
You don't miss much, do you?
Thank you, but I can't...>>
Do you like it?
Of course I like it. It's beautiful.
But I have a car.
Where's my car?
I told Taylor to fetch a decent price.
Oh, Christian, this is way too much.
Did you just roll your eyes at me?
Oh!
Do you know why I'm doing this?
Because I rolled my eyes.
And is that polite?
No.
Excuse me?
No, sir.
Do you want more?
Welcome to my world.
What are you doing?
I have a few things at the office that require my attention.
You okay?
I just thought that...>>
I enjoyed tonight.
I'll see you at my place tomorrow.
Hi, Momma.
Anastasia, what's going on?
I have left you two messages this week.
I know. I'm sorry.
I just got a little distracted.
Sorry I missed your graduation, honey. I heard it was lovely.
And your new beau?
Ray told me all about him. He sounds like quite the young man.
Of course, I would have preferred>>
to have heard about him from you.
Ana?
What's the matter?
Nothing. I'm fine.
Is he not making you happy?
He is, yeah. Most of the time, yeah.
It's complicated.
Listen, honey, if you need a break,>>
you just come right on down here.
Even if it's for a clay or two.
I have air miles, and we could talk and have girl time.
Promise me you'll think about it.
Yeah, I promise.
I promise.
I love you, Momma.
I love you, too, darling.
I gotta g0->>
Bye.
Looks like you and Grey did some celebrating last night.
Is he still asleep?
Uh... No, he couldn't stay.
Whose car keys are those, then?
Those are my keys.
Wow, Ana.
What?
Nothing. I just...>>
Make sure you're taking it at your own pace, okay?
I am, I am. I gotta go.
Where are you going?
Look at this.
I've seen it.
It's not a bad picture.
"Christian Grey with friend.">>
it says we're friends.
Well, it must be true if it's in the paper.
Mmm.
So, how'd it go with Dr. Greene?
It was fine.
But she said that I have to abstain from>>
all sexual activity for at least four weeks.
You know, after I start the pill.
What?
Just kidding.
I wanna take you to my play room.
But I haven't signed the contract.
I'm well aware.
Call it due diligence.
Okay.
You ready?
Eyes down.
Take off your shoes.
Arms above your head.
You have a beautiful body, Anastasia.
I want you unashamed ofyournakedness. Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
You're biting your lip.
You know what that does to me. Turn around.
When I tell you to come into this room,>>
this is how you'll be.
You'll wait for me,>>
kneeling by the door.
Do it now.
Hands flat on your thighs.
Good.
Hold out your hand.
Did that hurt?
No.
You see?
Most of your fear is in your head.
Come.
How does it feel?
Good, sir.
Mmm.
Quiet.
Where are we going?
Remember my mother mentioned dinner?
My sister Mia's in town.
Yeah.
You got everything you need?
Dance with me.
Good evening, Mr. Grey.
They're here.
You're here. Welcome, welcome.
Ana, Mother, you've met.
Hi. Good to see you. Come on in.
And this is my father, Garrick.
Hi, pleasure to meet you. Nice to meet you.
Is she here? You are the subject of some speculation.
Oh, my God, you exist!
It's a great apartment, and the rent's not ridiculous.
Elliot and José helped us move in.
José is Ana's friend.
Although, I think that Elliot's trying to poach him.
They've sparked quite the bromance.
He's a cool guy.
Ana, where is your family from?
My stepfather iives in Montesano, and my mom's in Georgia.
Georgia? Which part?
Savannah.
How nice.
Although, I do hear it gets rather humid in Georgia this time of year.
Oh, my God, it does.
It's stifling sometimes.
Actually, I'm going to visit her tomorrow.
Oh, how nice. Mmm-hmm.
You hear that, Christian?
Some children do visit their parents now and again.
Hey, Dad, you catch the Mariners game?
Uh, I heard it went to extra innings.
Ugh. Seattle baseball...>>
This is news to me.
When were you gonna tell me?
Who wants coffee?
Actually, I promised Ana a tour of the grounds.
Excuse us.
Christian, I cannot walk that fast in these shoes.
When were you gonna tell me about Georgia?
What? You have no right to be mad.
Yeah, but I am mad. Palm-twitchingly mad.
Ow!
You're mine.
All mine, you understand?
Christian, you are so confusing.
Ana.
What do you want?
I want you.
I'm trying, Christian.
I know you are.
Why can't we sleep in the same bed?
Why won't you let me touch you?
Why does it have to be like this?
If you would just sign the contract,>>
you wouldn't have to think about...>>
Why do you care so much about the contract, Christian?
Don't you like me the way I am?
Of course I do.
Then why are you trying to change me?
I'm not.
It's...>>
I need more. I want more.
Hearts and flowers?
That's not something I know.
Ana, please.
It's you that's changing me.
Let me touch you.
Let me.
Are they burns?
I had a rough start in life.
That's all you need to know.
Okay.
The woman that gave birth to me>>
was a crack addict>>
and a prostitute.
She died when I was four.
I remember certain things.
Terrible things.
But I don't remember her.
But sometimes,>>
I think I see her in my dreams.
Mmm.
Do you really have to go to Georgia?
Yeah, I really do.
Good morning. 12-H is down to your right.
Good morning. 2-B, oh it's just right here.
Oh! No, I'm supposed to be in coach.
Oh, you must have been upgraded.
Good morning. 12-A just down to your right.
Good morning.
Oh.
Gazpacho is very healthy, Bob.
You'll get fat with all this sitting around. You tell him, Ana.
I'm not gonna tell him that.
Yes, thank you, Ana.
I'm just saying that gazpacho is basically eating a bowl of salsa.
You should hand me some chips with my bowl of salsa here.
You can have a carrot.
What are you getting at with this?
You are damn lucky that I just happen to love you very much.
I know that.
Do you? Mmm, I do.
Oh, darling, I think we should pace ourselves.
Or at least order something to eat.
You go ahead. I'm not very hungry.
Oh. I'll just have the fruit salad.
He can wait.
Mom...>>
Holy fuck.
What? What is it?
It's Christian. He's here.
Um, in Georgia.
Oh.
"Here" here.
Mrs. Adams. Delighted to meet you.
Something to drink, sir?
Gin and tonic.
Hendrick's, if you have it.
Otherwise, Bombay Sapphire.
Cucumber with the Hendrick's, lime with the Bombay.
I like him already.
What are you doing here, Christian?
I came to see you.
I'm gonna step outside for a bit.
I broke rule seven, clause five.
Here.
We'll let it go.
Let's not talk about the contract right now.
How was your dinner?
She's a friend.
That's all.
She's a child abuser.
I confide in her.
She knows me.
What did she advise you to do?
Well, I'm here.
And now what?
I've got a room in this hotel.
Well, I hope you'll be comfortable in it.
What are you doing for breakfast tomorrow?
Where are we going?
It's a surprise.
I think I've reached my quota of surprises.
We're almost there.
Mr. Grey. Hey. I'll be your tow pilot.
How do you do? This is my girlfriend, Anastasia Steele.
We're at 3, 000 feet. Y'all ready?
Well?
Yeah, do it.
Release.
Hold on tight.
Is this more?
Oh, my God. So much more!
Oh, my God- That was incredible, Christian.
Thank you.
We aim to please, Miss Steele.
And you said you didn't do romance.
I don't.
Ana. Mmm. What?
What?
Why are you fighting this?
What are you afraid of?
Grey.
What?
When?
Tell Stephan to have the plane ready.
I'll be on the tarmac in 30 minutes.
What happened?
I have to go back to Seattle. Come, I'll take you home.
Oh, sweetheart.
I wish Christian could have stayed.
Bob was really looking forward to meeting him.
I know.
He had to get back to Seattle, though.
There was some situation at work.
I wish I could tell you that things get easier, but they don't.
You just get to know yourself better.
Thank you for everything, Momma.
Take care of yourself, sweetheart.
I will.
Did you think I wouldn't recognize you, Taylor?
How does he seem today, Taylor?
Preoccupied, I'm afraid.
Really?
Yes, ma'am.
Well, that's not gonna work.
When?
Well, then, tell them that they don't have 24 hours.
That is unacceptable. I need to know.
Just keep me informed.
Is everything okay?
Nothing that concerns you.
I can leave. Do you want me to go?
No.
No, that's the last thing I want.
I want you to be>>
in the play room in 15 minutes.
What are your safewords?
"Red" and "Yellow.">>
Remember those.
Mmm.
It sounds so sad.
Everything you play is so sad.
You said you were six when you learned.
Was it because you wanted to please your new family?
I just wanna talk.
Why won't you let me in?
We should be talking.
Like normal people?
Yeah.
Is that so wrong?
Is this because of the contract,>>
because I still haven't signed it?
Fuck the contract.
I think it's a little redundant, don't you?
So, then, the rules are redundant, too?
No. The rules stand.
And what if I break them?
Then there'll be consequences.
Punishment.
Yes.
Why do you want to punish me?
Ana...>>
Why do you wanna hurt me?
I would never do anything to you that you couldn't handle.
But why do you even wanna do anything to me at all, Christian?
If I told you, you would never look at me the same way again.
So, there is a reason.
Tell me.
Do you wanna punish me right now?
Yes. I wanna punish you right now.
What if I told you that I feel the same way about being punished>>
as you do about me touching you?
Would you still want to punish me then?
No.
But that doesn't mean I wouldn't need to.
Why?
Ana, stop. Why do you need to?
Because it's the way I am!
Because I am fifty shades of fucked up.
Show me, then.
I need you to show me>>
what you want to do to me.
Punish me.
Show me how bad it can be. I want you to show me the worst.
It's the only way I can understand.
Are you sure about this?
Yes.
Bend over.
I'm gonna hit you six times.
And you're gonna count with me.
Count, Anastasia.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
No! Don't fucking touch me.
This is what you want?
You want to see me like this?
Ana...>>
Don't come near me.
Does this give you pleasure?
Don't.
Don't you dare come near me.
Please don't hate me.
You'll never do that to me again.
I'm not what you want.
No, you're everything that I want.
I've fallen in love with you.
No.
No, Ana, you can't love me.
I need you to leave.
Please.
I'd like my car back.
Taylor already sold it.
Then I'd like the money he got for it, please.
I'll send you a check.
Okay.
Taylor will take you home.
Stop.
No!
Ana...>>
Christian.