B>>
A>>
Are you having fun, sweetheart?
Yes>>
I hope you're doing better than me, baby,>>
what are you making? - Necklace for mom.
Yeah? Let me see. Wow. Another one?
Yes>>
Honey... - That's two today.
Yeah - Yeah?
Honey! Yeah>>
Are you gonna help me get that?
I thought you and I had a day off>>
Go wash up for dinner, pumpkin. - Okay.
Mmm, smells nice. Is that take-out?
Mommy, mommy>>
No!
No, noo.
Noo Noo!
You can't fight faith.
We gotta get the fuck out of her.
What are you doing? Come on!
Fucking stop! Let's go!
Shut the fuck up!
It's cool.
Kids like me.
"Law abiding Citizen">>
Transcribed by: anreith. For inSanos>>
Nick. Bringham, what's happening?
Willis is a rowing buddy of mine>>
Where are we on his kids case?
Willis? - Yeah>>
Oh, I kicked that down the tube.
Now why did you do that?
Because the case was a dog>>
The kid was only 15 years old>>
when he commited the murder.
So you didn't want to jeapordize your>>
95% conviction rate. - It's actually 96%.
96 now? - Yes,>>
You know, if I didn't know any better>>
I'd say you were gunning for my job.
You do know better, and you know that>>
I'm aiming much higher than that.
They filed a motion to dismiss, but>>
there's no way that judge Abrams honors it.
I think that we can get him on RICO>>
All that time and that's what you come back with, Sarah?
You might wanna re-evaluate your research skills,>>
what else have we got? - She's right>>
Mr Rice? - RICO's designed for this>>
check out section 901 of the organized crime control act>>
and you should let Sarah try this case, too.
Mr Rice, last I checked I was running this room.
She's already done the leg work. I'll oversee it,>>
Helen Keller could try this case.
Okay boy-wonder, she fucks up it's on you.
(DONT FUCK IT UP)>>
"Thank you">>
Cantrell wants to see you - Alright, I'll be right there.
No. Nick. He wants to see Nick.
You're still torturing Bringham?
Let's just say I'm less impressed with his>>
Harvard degree than he is.
We can't all have gone to Fordham.
I went to Fordham night school.
You know what I learned at Fordham night school?
It's that law schools have nothing to do with law.
Guess you skipped the course on inter-office politics.
All I need is a jury to like me, isn't that what you told me?
The Shelton case, where are we?
It went sideways last night. Judge Birch.
Bad news. What now?
Let's make the deal.
They killed a little girl, Nick.
It's an imperfect system. - And we it's imperfect servants.
However, you could win this case.
Can't take that chance.
Some justice is better than no justice at all.
You need to tell the husband. - It's part of my job.
Good. Because he is waiting for you right now.
What?
Do you trust me?
Do you trust me, Clyde?
Yeah, of course.
Darby has agreed to testify against Ames.
With Darbys testimony, Ames will go to death row.
What about, what about Darby then?
Darby will plead guilty to murder.
In what degree? - Third.
He serves, what, 5 years?
At best.
I dont understand, I'm sorry.
We had a setback, Clyde. The judge ruled that>>
the DNA was inadmissable. - What?
Exclusionary rule.
The oposing council maneuvered.
You said this part of the case was clear cut>>
We had the blood on his shirt, - It's covered under the same rule>>
What about the rest of the forensic evidence?
It's not conclusive, Clyde.
Okay, thats okay. Because I saw, I saw their faces>>
I saw them do it. I mean they killed my little girl, Nick.
You blacked out, Clyde. Your testimony won't be reliable.
you get on the stand and the defense will tear you apart.
No no, the jury is going to believe me, though,>>
because its the truth. We can win>>
We can lose. And then we have nothing.
You would have wasted a whole year,>>
spent millions of dollars, and then both of them>>
can end up going free.
Both of them are guilty, especially Darby. You know that.
It's not what you know, Clyde, its what you can prove in court.
Please dont make a deal with them.
Please don't make a deal - I'm sorry, the deal is done.
I'm sorry.
I made the deal. - What?
How could you do that?
This is just how the justice system works.
Listen, I know you don't think it right now,>>
but this is a victory for us.
Your office has certified this agreement?
Yes, your honor. - Mr Reynolds?
Any great insights to share with the court today?
No, your honor. No insights.
Good, then I trust that we can move forward>>
with Mr Ames' trial unimpeded by delays>>
a trial date is imminent.
There's no cell phones in my courtroom, mr Rice.
We've been over this. - I'm sorry.
I had some exigent business I was...>>
Next time it's mine.
Ahh, you married? - Excuse me?
Are you married?
Please fuck this up. So I can destroy you.
I wish ill for no man but Ames deserves>>
to suffer for what he did.
I mean you cant fight faith, right?
Nick.
Once you make a decision, live with it. Move on.
In this job your best asset is a short memory.
Don't beat yourself up, too many other people>>
out there doing that already. Look,>>
there's some of them right now.
Isn't this when you tell me some old favel, wise tale...>>
Alright, alright. I got one.
Marcus Aurelius had a servant walk behind him>>
as he made his way to the roman time square.
And the servants only job was to whisper in his ear>>
when people praised him: "You're only a man">>
"You're only a man" Okay, man?
That's some bullshit. - That's good>>
I don't even think you know the story, man.
You're missing the point, Nick, it doesnt matter>>
what they say. - Okay. I got this now.
One at a time. One at a time.
So you'll be seeking the death penalty?
For Rupert Ames we will be. - And for Darby?
He has pled guilty to murder but he is a cooperating witness.
The DAs office has commited all of its resources>>
to ensure that justice will be served.
Did you make any kind of...>>
I just wanna say thanks for being in my corner.
It's nice when the system works, right?
Get away from me.
Come on. Move it.
Let's go.
Uh-uh, what happened? - What happened where?
What's wrong?
And you call my job boring.
C minus? - Yes>>
Well, okay, now,>>
You gonna tell me whats wrong?
Can I talk to my daughter for a little bit?
Nooo... - Please>>
First of all, this is your father speaking>>
Yeah, she didnt know that. - You never know.
I want you to stay in there as long as you can>>
Cause there's a lot of crazy ass people out here.
Language! - Your mother is a hardass.
I'm right here.
And daddy wants you to come out and be daddys little girl...>>
10 years later>>
Anybody seen my phone?
Hey, did you see my phone?
It's not strapped to your hand?
No it's not strapped to my hand.
Daddy! Not gonna have some of my french toast?
French toast, you making french toast?
I'm sorry I can't, I'm running late.
Okay.
Alright, here we go. Mmmm, taste good.
Thanks - Did this is by yourself?
You're better than your mother.
I heard that. Smells good. Here, your lifeline.
Morning baby.
You're going to your daughters recital this afternoon?
Uhm, I thought you were gonna order the DVDs.
Video is not the same, Nick.
Mom, its okay. Dad's gotta work, I know>>
See, its alright. Dad's gotta work. And what does Dad do?
Lock up bad guys. - And why does he do that?
To keep us safe. - Yeah, he wants us to be safe.
Baby, get your chello. - Alright>>
Thank you so much. - You're welcome.
What a Julia Child (cook). - Mmhhmm>>
You know she's 10 years old, right?
you know that? - I know that>>
She doesn't understand why you're never around.
This good-guy-bad-guy stuff thats just talk to her.
I can't come today.
You know you have not been to one recital>>
Enough! - Okay>>
We'll get the video, we'll sit down and watch as a family.
I love you. Alright?
Thank you for the toast. - Love you>>
Love you too - Bye>>
So how's Chip? - It's Chester>>
What happened to Chip, I liked Chip.
There is no Chip. And now there's no Chester.
He kept calling. - Sarah, thats a good thing.
I know, but I kept cancelling. My case load is crazy.
You know you dont have to go to this if you dont want to.
Yeah, I do. I... What's it like?
No biggie. Like watching somebody fall asleep.
Except the not-waking-up part? Does it bother you?
Not anymore.
Sarah. Your legs are looking real good in those heels.
What are you doing, Reynolds?
Why are you here? Your DVD player is broken?
Ames has no family. I felt like someone should be here for him.
You just getting a little press?
Breathe.
What I did out there was wrong.
I should have never been there.
But I swear to God, I didn't kill those people.
Wrong man is dying here today.
That's all.
Oh God. - Take her away.
What the hell is going on? - I dont know.
Are you okay? - Yeah>>
So, somebody killed the guy you were trying to kill.
What are we calling this?
Clear violation of his 8th amendment right:>>
cruel and unusual punishment.
Law school. - Yeah. The machine,>>
how does it work on a good day?
It's designed to be pain free.
Three drugs, administered in a specific order.
From this moment on we are assuming that>>
the machine was corrupted.
We're gonna need a list of all the people>>
with access to that machine.
My people would not do this.
I appreciate that, Warden, but>>
I'm gonna need more than a hallpass and a note from mom.
Detectives. Got something back on the machine.
Let me see that? - Right there.
"Cant fight faith". - What is it, Nick?
During the home invasion Ames accomplice said>>
to one of the victims: "Can't fight faith">>
He said the same thing to me in the courtroom, the prick.
I can't remember his name.
Have a look at this. Your guy?
Clarence James Darby - He's a beauty...>>
You got history with him? - I put him away.
Ah, 3 years. Is that the going rate for murder these days?
There was extenuating circumstances.
The only extenuating circumstance should be if he didnt do it.
Still, three years at Marion, fucking gladiator camp,>>
you expect him to come back a model citizen?
Well, if you scholars wouldnt contaminate the crime scenes,>>
I could keep them locked up longer.
Authorities have refused to comment at this point>>
foul play cannot be ruled out. The prisoner had been on death row>>
for the past 10 years>>
All we know at this point is what was supposed to be a>>
painless execution has turned into something out of a horror film.
Im Paula live on the scene...>>
Yeah? - Clarence Darby?
Who's this? - That's strike three for you,>>
Coke on the table, bitch on the floor. Away from prison.
Who the fuck is this?
Look out your window. South side.
Is this a joke? Get up.
South side.
Motherfucker. Shit.
Out of the way!
He's outdoor! Go. Go>>
Damn. - Move it, move it.
What now?
Wipe the prints off the gun. Get rid of it.
No, no, no - You fired six times, genius>>
You bring any ammunition? Lose it.
Why are you doing this? - I wanna keep you out of prison.
See the abandoned factories? Go toward them.
Why? There's a cop car there.
With a cop in it. What the fuck!
I tazered him, but he will be waking>>
up in under 90 seconds. So better move.
Rise and fucking shine, bitch>>
Wake the fuck up. Let's go. Start the fucking car.
Okay. Take it easy. - Do it. Come on.
Take it easy. Lets go, lets go!
Get it in gear, shithead. Now! Do it!
Get the fuck out.
Lets go.
Get the fuck down there.
Hey. What about my wife, my little girl?
I'll never see them again. - Fucked up, man.
Ohh, oh oh, you don't mind if I take this, do you?
My guardian angel. I am impressed.
You know why I'll never see my wife and little girl again?
What the...?
Cause you took them from me.
Remember me?
Sure you do.
You came over to my house once before.
Don't remember?
This Tetrodotoxin should be nicely in your system by now.
Isolated from the liver of the Carribean Puffer Fish.
So, it paralyzes you,>>
but leaves all the other neurological functions intact.
In other words, you cant move, but you feel everything.
It does absolutely nothing to blunt the pain.
And you're about to experience more of that>>
than you can ever fucking imagine.
???, so you dont bleed out.
You may be here a while.
Saline solution, that should keep us going.
The clamps, nice and secure.
Comfortable?
You really are shaking. Sure you're alright?
You'll love this.
Adrenalin.
Now this, is so you don't pass out.
There you go. Good.
Now what we dont want, is you swallowing your tongue>>
so bare with me.
Now this is for your penis. But we'll get to that later.
Scalpel, for your eyelids.
In case you insist on fucking shutting them.
You see, I know what it feels like to be helpless,>>
just like when I watched you slaughter my whole family.
You can't fight faith, right Darby?
Oh! And look.
I made this especially for you.
You like it? Yeah, I didn't want you to miss anything.
Now you have the best view in the house.
You hear that? Your heart is beating so fast.
Well, me too. Okay.
Now they get to watch you suffer.
They'll be the last thing you ever see.
as I cut off every single one of your fucking limbs.
See, I wasn't lying,>>
when I told you I wanted to keep you out of prison.
That was the truth.
Thanks for the car.
Okay, these are all the case files on Darby,>>
I vetted through what I could, we have crime scene photos...>>
Don't want to see them.
Okay>>
What's bothering you? - It's Darby>>
All the crimes he's committed have one thing in common,>>
there was violence, but the execution wasnt violence,>>
that was, that was intellect. - Okay.
What are you thinking?
Was just thinking maybe we shouldn't be looking at Darby.
Jesus Christ.
Rice. - Good news, councellor.
Found Darby.
I gotta say though, he's looked better.
They found him in about 25 pieces; no legs>>
no arms, eyelids were sliced off. Gruesome.
Shedding tears for Darby? - Not quite>>
So your wheel's turning. - Think motive. Who has it?
The husband. Father. What do we know about him?
He owned the warehouse where they found Darby>>
What else? - He's a tinkerer,>>
little inventionist. Gizmos. He holds two dozen patents,>>
that made him some money. He liquidated most of his wealth>>
a few years ago, to buy some industrial properties>>
around airports, chemical plants, railyards.
It doesn't add up. - No, it's weird, right?
Search them all, Sarah, see what you find.
Down on your knees!
Get down! Go! Knees!
Face down! face down!
"DADDY">>
The crazy ones scare the shit out of me.
Is this guy a lawyer?
No.
He's an engineer. "United States Code Annotated">>
Nick, look at this.
"Prosecutor Calls Death Penalty For Ames">>
We have zero evidence. You better get a confession.
Did he give you any trouble on the way in?
No. Nothing.
He wasn's too happy when we took his bracelet though.
Can I help you? - Package for the Rice family.
Oh yeah. Thanks.
Mom, the video from my recital came.
Can we watch it? Please?
No, not you. No.
Denise, we said we would wait for your father, remember?
Please? - No, not now.
Uhum. Yes>>
Mommy>>
Don't worry, he's just disarming the guy.
Letting him feel easy.
What I'm about to tell you I dont want anyone to hear.
As a prosecutor Im breaking all the rules right now,>>
and I dont give a damn. Because Im a father,>>
I have a little girl. And what you did>>
Bravo.
The world is better without Darby and Ames.
You're not gonna see a tear shed from me or anybody>>
in my office.
With that being said, I have a job to do.
I want to ask you some very simple and direct questions,>>
I suggest that you answer them in the same fashion.
Is your name Clyde Alexander Sheldon?
Yes, Sir.
And you wave your right to councel, correct?
You sure you wanna do that?
Yes.
Did you murder Clarence Darby?
I wanted him dead. He killed my wife and child.
Rupert Ames, did you murder him aswell?
Rupert Ames deserved to die.
They both deserved to die.
So, you arranged both of those murders?
Yes, I planned it, in my head,>>
over and over again, took me a long time.
Alright. I guess we are done here.
Councelor.
You might want to cancel your 12:30 lunch with judge Roberts.
Excuse me?
In fact, you might want to cancel the rest of the week>>
cause you're gonna be busy. Sit down.
We're done here. We have your confession.
Oh, you do? - And on tape.
See, in our profession we consider that a "slam dunk">>
Oh, really? I dont think so. Lets think back.
What did I say?
That I wanted to kill Clarence Darby?
Yeah, sure, what father wouldn't?
That Darby and Ames deserved to die?
I think most people would agree with that.
That I planned it over and over again,>>
in my head? Yeah.
Who wouldnt fantasize about that?
None of these are an admission of guilt, Nick.
You might wanna check the tape.
We know you did it. - Well it's not what you know,>>
it's what you can prove in court.
Didn't you tell me that once?
The only problem with your theory is that Darby's>>
body was found on your property.
One of my many properties.
An old abandoned warehouse, Nick.
Junkies, they trespass there all the time.
Isn't Darby involved in the drug trade?
That's an unsavory world. I bet you a jury would agree,>>
or perhaps someone was trying to frame me.
Go ahead. There's a lot of assholes in prison>>
that thought they were smarter than me.
Let's stop fucking around.
Nick, unless you have any hard evidence,>>
then why are we even here?
Why are we having... - What you want?
Well, thats easy.
You're the one that makes deals with murderers, yeah?
So I've come to make mine.
I will give you a confession, a real confession.
You just have to give me something in return.
Well, you are a murderer, so what might that be?
A bed.
But a nice bed.
I want a nice new one for myself.
I see.
You're gonna have to deal with that,>>
because the one I have is lumpy, Nick,>>
it's making me crazy.
Clyde, I think you got me confused with the detail>>
people, see I dont deal with prison conditions.
I believe those cots are bolted into the cells.
Well that's what wrenches are for, dumbass.
You know one of those new Duxiana beds with>>
the adjustable lumbar support>>
I've seen the commercial.
That's the one I want. - Those are nice.
Cause really, Nick, I dont think I can focus on much>>
of anything until I've had a good, revitalizing nights>>
sleep, in my therapeutic Duxiana bed.
So that's the deal.
Give me my bed, you get your confession.
Let me think about that for a second.
How about uhm...>>
Fuck no?
Hey. - What are you doing?
What do you mean what am I doing?
Why did you tell him no? - A mattress?
He doesn't make those kind of decisions.
Take your ego out of it, Nick.
Shelton's got a point, this case is shit,>>
we need a confession and a mattress for a>>
murder confession, thats a pretty good deal>>
He's playing us, Jonas. - Well then we will play him.
Nick. Call from the office. You're not answering your cell.
I need to finish up here, and then I will be home>>
as soon as I can. - Listen to me, that video>>
Nick, I have never seen anything like it.
Please, come home.
Listen, you need to calm down>>
tell her its not real. And that I love her.
Come home. Come home soon please.
Kelly, did you see his face?
No, it was covered with something, I couldnt see.
let me finish up here and I will come home.
Okay.
This motherfucker sent a DVD to my house,>>
of him killing Darby. - What?
My daughter saw it.
He recorded it, we've got him. - No, he had on a mask>>
we need that confession.
You still want to bargain with this man?
The art of the possible, Warden. Make the deal.
Back problems, Warden. The worst.
You got bigger problems than that.
It's the have-nots in here, son.
They don't know that I want to be the one have>>
Turn around.
I dont think he likes me.
Nice bed.
Thank you. It's a single.
We can't put Clyde Shelton anywhere,>>
not in a job, not in a city,>>
not even a country. So I dug a little deeper,>>
and I found something from his missing years,>>
a couple of contract payments, to Clyde,>>
from the Department of Defense.
And his real estate? - He bought 9 properties>>
under his own name, then he transfered them to>>
some corporation in Panama.
We can't get to the adresses, lack of reciprocity problems,>>
we are gonna circle back to the farmhouse.
That's a waste of time. He wanted us to find him there.
It's the industrial stuff thats curious.
Alright, I dont care what you have to do, or who>>
you piss off, if we have to invade Panama again, fine.
Clyde is hiding those properties for a reason.
Find it. - Got it.
Baby, did you leave a crack? - Yeah, I left a crack.
Night light? - Isn't she too old for that?
Yeah, I left the night light.
Look.
I told her that that video wasn't real.
Some sort of horror film she shouldn't be looking at.
She'll be okay. - And you?
- If I'm what, okay? Of course. Don't I look okay?
Nick is always okay. Always, I'm extra good.
In light of Mr Sheltons economic means and his,>>
potential flight risk, the egregious nature of both>>
Mr Ames' and Mr Darbys deaths>>
The state requestst hat bail be denied, your honor.
Seeing as you waved your right to counsel, Mr Sheldon,>>
do you have anything to say? Mr Sheldon?
Do you have anything that you'd like to say?
Yes, yes, your honor. Should I stand?
Please.
Your honor, I'm a law abiding citizen.
Just a regular guy.
I'm not a flight risk>>
This is my first alleged offense,>>
and the prosecution has not presented>>
one single piece of evidence against me.
Now, in these circumstances, unless the state has obtained>>
some new information relating to my involvement in the matter,>>
then I find it highly prejudical, even constitutionally offensive,>>
to keep me detained without bail.
It's a slippery slope, your honor,>>
Haven't we seen the result of such violations both>>
internationally and domestically, case in point,>>
would be Dave v McDonough doc #0413825>>
I am actually inclined to agree with you, Mr Shelton.
Your honor, Mr Shelton has agreed to give a confession.
Has he given it, Mr Rice? - No, your honor.
Well, then in my opinion the state has failed to>>
establish a compelling basis for its motion, and I will>>
grant bail in the amount of...>>
Your honor, I will caution you not to do that.
Thank you. - Excuse me?
No, I dont think I will excuse you.
You see, this is what I'm talking about.
You were about to let me go,>>
Are you kidding me?
This is why we're here in the first place.
You think I don't remember who you are, lady?
I would tread carefully, Mr Shelton.
Well, how carefully should I tread?
Because apparently I just killed two people.
And you were about to let me walk right out that door>>
How misguided are you?
I feed you a couple of bullshit legal presedence,>>
and you go jump on it like a bitch in heat.
- Im warning you - You folks you all hang out at the same clubs.
- You will be held in contempt of this court. - And everyday you let madmen and murderers>>
Back on the street. You're too busy treating the law>>
- One more time - like if it's a fucking assembly line>>
- One more time - Have you any idea of what justice is?
- You are now in contempt of the court - Whatever happened to right and wrong?
- Remove this man - Whatever happened to right and wrong!?
Whatever happened to the people.
Bail denied!
- Bail denied! - Whatever happened to justice?
And I bet you take it up the fucking ass!
Bitch. - Bailiff>>
See you later, Nick.
Insanity?
That's what you're building your defense on? Insanity?
Nick, I told you I would give you a confession.
And I meant it.
I saw a movie today. - You did?
My daughter, saw the same movie.
Well, you taught your daughter about good vs evil?
I dont have to.
Well that's what this movie was about.
Good conquering Evil. The righteous prospering,>>
the wicked suffering. - I didn't get that.
I'm gonna give you one more chance, Clyde.
And dont test me, cause I will run you over.
Fair enough.
You did get me my bed. A deal's a deal.
That was you on video, killing Clarence Darby.
Yes, that was me.
Fair enough. That was me, Clyde Shelton, on the video,>>
killing Clarence Darby. - Not good enough, Clyde,>>
I need specifics.
I took his fingers with bolt cutters.
His toes with tin snips.
His balls with a hack saw.
And his penis with a box cutter.
How's that for specifics?
And Ames?
Switching the canisters was easy.
Everything is automated these days, so I just>>
hacked in to the shipping companies server and>>
swapped a few numbers around so the package came to me.
Then I switched the potassium chloride>>
for something a little more... deliberate.
Well, I'm tired of hearing your bullshit.
I got everything I need.
What now? - I go home. You go to prison.
The righteous prosper and the wicked suffer.
That ought to make you feel better about the system.
What if I had another confession to make?
Call a priest.
But another confession would mean another deal, Nick, so>>
you would have to give me something in return.
You ever been to Del Friscos? They cater.
So for lunch I would love a 20 ounce porter steak,>>
medium, maybe a little charred.
With all the trimmings:>>
Pommes frites, asparagus, butter-squash.
- Fuck you and your Pommes frites.
I Tell you what. Can I have my Ipod aswell?
I'd love a little bit of music with my meal.
First rule of negotiating, Clyde,>>
you gotta have something to bargain with.
Would the life of Bill Reynolds suffice?
Open it.
Who the fuck is Bill Reynolds?
Darbys attorney.
Tell me you located him. - I've got his wife,>>
she reported him missing three days ago.
Thank you, Mrs Reynolds.
Looks like I got something to bargain with, Nick.
At the moment, Bill Reynolds is still alive.
I'll tell you exactly where he is,>>
just bring me my meal and my music,>>
at 1 o'clock exactly. 1 o'clock sharp.
1 o'clock, Nick.
Hold it right there.
It's five to 1 pm.
I dont take orders from him, or you.
Iinmates dont know the time, we tell them the time.
I dont care, we need to stick to the agreed timeline.
- Fuck him, Nick. Let him wait.
Christ, he sawed the guys dick off.
Whether you like it or not, we are on his time.
Check it again.
Steamed Asparagus.
Macaroni and cheese. - Wow>>
Porter house steak, seared, medium rare.
Napkin, Nick. - Napkin.
Oh, excuse me, waiter>>
You might wanna put 30% down for yourself, my man>>
What time is it? - 1 o'clock.
Is that right, Nick? - It's 1:08.
Well that's dissapointing, Warden.
How can you expect me not to fuck with you>>
when you cant even be honest with me>>
You have what you asked for, now where's Reynolds?
Can I have some silverware, gentlemen ?
You get a spork.
Thanks.
Come on, Clyde.
Okay. Here we go.
39 degrees, 57 minutes, 4 seconds, north.
75 degrees, 10 minutes, 22 seconds, west.
You better hurry, Nick.
By anybodys watch but the Wardens, you're already late.
Open the door.
I'll sit in front of you.
So, I suppose if I dont share this with you>>
I'm gonna get the fuck up, take my right hand,>>
and split your skull in two, how about that?
Come on over here, join me>>
There's plenty to go around.
Enjoy it. Pasta. It's good.
What about some steak? You like steak?
Big piece for you. There you go.
Good, huh?
What did you do to get in here, anyways?
I did what I had to do.
So you got a girl or something?
It's a long story.
Pilot, how much longer? - ETA 2 minutes>>
How about you? Have a girl?
Got a few broads back home. - Oh yeah?
You don't have a boyfriend in here right now?
Get the fuck out of here.
It's his. His briefcase.
Just dig.
Jesus Christ. - Reynolds! Reynolds!
He's gone. - Oxygen?
Get something to get him out.
IV lines going to his... Fuck. He's got him cuffed.
You got your keys? To the cuffs.
It's your lucky day, huh? Get some food.
Here, take a shot at this.
I need a shower, Warden.
Get him out of there!
Dunningan, what time do you have?
I'm 1:37.
Took us roughly 15 minutes to get here.
Yeah.
Reynolds air was rigged to shut off at 1:15>>
If Shelton had his lunch on time he'd still be alive.
Fuck this guy, Nick. He wants to play games,>>
we can play games too.
We need to take the gloves off.
Hey Nick, it's Sarah. Listen. Clyde murdered his cellmate.
Warden is furious, he's moving him to solitary.
That's all I know right now.
Found Reynolds.
Well, it was too late, you are here.
I had to call his wife and tell her that her husband>>
had been buried alive.
Well, justice should be harsh, Nick.
Especially for those who denied it to others.
And your cellmate, what was that about?
You murdered a man because your lunch was late.
No. No.
No, you murdered him because you couldn't keep your word.
We made a deal you and I, 1:00 pm.
Now that's an important principle I'd like you to learn, Nick.
Keeping your word. - Oh, really?
Well, what principle was at work when you>>
tortured and killed those people?
That everyone must be held accountable for their actions.
You think your wife and daughter would feel good>>
about you killing in their name?
My wife and daughter can't feel anything.
They're dead.
Hey, Nick. On Clydes real estate, judge Stansfeld shut us down.
He's looking for some legal precedent Im not sure exists.
But? - But, I think I may have>>
found a way around him, I'm gonna call in a favour>>
from a friend. - Who's your friend?
You don't name your friends or they stop doing favours.
Something else Cantrell said? - No, thats all you.
Jonas. Hi.
She's thinking just like you, Nick.
Guess you trained her well.
One day she'll have my job. - Let's get some air.
Clydes government contract payments were bothering me,>>
I pulled some old strings. We're meeting someone.
Who might that be?
Someone who does some really nasty shit>>
so we can live the american dream.
So Clyde finally lost it?
Somebody must have really pissed him off.
You worked with Shelton, is that right?
First of all, I was never here, and we never spoke.
Tell us what we're dealing with.
Shelton was a spy? - Spies are a dime a dozen.
I'm a spy.
Clyde is a brain. He's a think-tank type guy.
His specialty was low impact kinetic operations.
Just a fancy way to say that he kills people.
We kill people.
He figured out how to do it without being in the same room.
It was his gift. And he was the best.
One time we're tasking this tricky target.
We were using cruise missiles, predators,>>
we even had a B-2 bomber fly to this guys villa>>
to jade him. We're burning up millions in ordinance,>>
we're getting nowhere with this guy.
So we call Clyde. We ask him to solve our problem.
Clyde develops a kevlar thread, with a high-tech>>
ratchet made of carbon fiber.
Puts it in a necktie. Two days later,>>
Mrs Bad Guy comes home, finds Mr Bad Guy>>
dead on the bathroom tile. Choked to death.
What I'm saying is, just assume that this guy>>
can hear and see everything that you are doing.
No, we got him locked under maximum security.
If he's in jail it's because he wants to be in jail.
He's a born tactician. Every move he makes,>>
it means something.
That cellmate that he killed, you think that was random?
No.
That's a pawn being moved over the board.
And if I were you, I'd be looking for the next piece.
Anybody who had anything to do with that case,>>
he's gonna be coming after you.
So what are you saying? That we can't stop him?
Walk into his cell and put a bullet in his head.
Aside from that, no, you can't stop him.
If Clyde wants you dead, you're dead.
Hello? - Sarah, it's me.
Setup a meeting with judge Birch.
We need her to help keep Clyde on ice.
Help us with what, Nick? The man's in prison.
It's worse than we thought.
Chester's your boyfriend, right? - Chester? Yeah.
Good. Maybe stay a few days at his place.
And have Dunnigan send a patrol car to my house.
Sorry about this, Sarah.
I can't supercede the penal code. You've already got him>>
in solitary, a half-decent paralegal will have him>>
out of there by next week. - We just want to limit his options.
Give him less contact. Less access.
Even if it's just rescinding his mandatory exercise for a week.
Under what cause? - Whatever cause you want.
Wrap it around whatever piece of legal doctrine>>
that helps you rationalize it. Your honor.
So, let me get this straight. You want me to violate>>
his God-given civil rights in the name of some>>
murky sense of the greater good, is that the jist of it?
Okay. I'm game.
Just dont plan on it sticking for long. Alright?
What, you gonna take that? After all the grief>>
you've given me over cell phones?
Thats one of the benefits of being a judge, Mr Rice,>>
I can pretty much do whatever I want.
Hello?
Oh my God.
Back up.
So you're killing judges now?
In my experience, Nick, lessons not learned in blood>>
are soon forgotten.
And vengeance keeps you warm at night?
Vengeance?
That's what you think this is about? Vengeance!?
What else could it be? - No, Nick,>>
I had ten years for vengeance, if that's what I wanted.
You don't think that I watch you go to work,>>
every morning 8:00 am?
Or that I watch Ellie take Denise to school 8:15?
No, I could've slaughtered you or your family,>>
anytime I wanted, Nick. - If you even think about>>
touching my family.
If you even think about touching my family.
I do my job. I'm the best at it.
It works.
You were doing your job, the way it best served you, Nick.
The way it best served you.
That has to change. - What do you want, Clyde?
Your war with the world, It's not gonna bring anybody back.
No, Im at war with this. This, this broken thing.
This thing that brought you and I together.
This broken thing works, for people that are sane.
You think doing what you're doing is gonna change anything?
You, and whoever you have helping you, are gonna pay.
I don't think you have any idea who's helping me.
Or what I'm doing. - It's a matter of time.
You see the bodies, you see the smoke.
But the larger picture still eludes you.
Do tell.
I would like to, but I would rather show you.
I have faith in you, so I will give you one last chance.
Here's the deal:>>
Release me. And drop all charges by 6:00 am.
6:00 am, Nick. - Or what?
Or I kill everyone.
Hello? - Yeah, Sarah,>>
He has to have an accomplice. Probably somebody inside>>
the prison. We have to go through all the prisons files>>
to find some connection.
- Do you want the files run to the office?
No, there isn't time. Get everybody together,>>
and bring them to the prison. We're moving in.
Stop looking at your watch.
Anything from your friend?
This treaty with Panama is a mess. We cant access>>
anything about property holdings, but my friend found>>
this loophole for access to clients corporate expenses.
Does that help?
So match sell prices of industrial property sold in Philly,>>
up against purchases made by his corporation.
Okay. I got it.
Hey, Nick, can I ask you something?
Would you do it the same way now, would you still>>
cut a deal for Darby?
This is a job, Sarah. We have to make choices.
Did you make the right choice? - We made the right choice.
I don't know. I'm 35, Nick, and there are things,>>
possibilities that I'm not gonna have now.
And it's okay. And it was part of the deal.
Don't get me wrong, I love working for you.
But I just wanna know that I gave up those things for>>
more than just a high conviction rate.
Alright, lets just get focused. This guy is not God.
He's not the all-powerful, he's just well prepared.
We need to be equally well prepared.
Take a couple of hours, go home, come back,>>
and we'll get a fresh start. Okay?
Hey Nick. Get some rest. - Give Chester my regards.
When do I get to meet him? - Oh, he's not ready for that.
Good night, Jonas.
I don't know how this one's gonna turn out, Nick.
We're gonna stop him, that's how it's gonna turn out.
Noo! No.
Sarah.
In the past 48 hours, 6 officials from the>>
Justice Department have been killed in>>
a series of vicious and premeditated attacks.
This marks the first time in the history of the US>>
where government officials, have been, by all appearances,>>
Systematically murdered.
Nick, I'm sorry to have to do this, but we got something here.
Found this. Right outside the wall.
Radio beacon.
Sent an arming signal to the car bombs when>>
they went through the gate. - Security said they checked>>
every car before they got here.
Better check the gas stations.
Real precise stuff too.
Could have taken out a lot more if he wanted to.
What about Nicks car? - That's the weird thing.
It's clean. Haven't been touched.
I gotta go.
Jesus Christ.
Privacy. - Yes, ma'am.
So let me get this straight.
Not only do we know who did it,>>
We have him locked up and he's still killing people?
You boys sure fucked this one up.
The press is gonna kill us.
Can someone explain this to me?
We can't yet.
How did this get away from you, Jonas?
It's complicated, April.
He's very smart. He's very angry.
We assume he has an accomlice helping him on the outside.
I'm not having this conversation.
I don't care how smart he is, or who's helping him.
Release a statement saying we have suspects,>>
we're following leads, nothing alarming.
Mayor, you have my word. We are gonna stop this guy,>>
he's not gonna hurt anybody else.
I'm assigning security to each of you from now on.
Get this situation under control, gentlemen.
No phone calls, no credit cards, no computers. Just cash.
Daddy, are you coming?
Of course I am. - You better, Nick.
Need to go. - I love you, Nick.
Come on baby.
Love you, daddy - Love you too.
Nick, phone line's clear. Nobody has been tampering,>>
Good.
Should have taken my deal.
Six fucking innocent people, that's how you wanna play it?
It's okay. It's okay. I know you're angry.
That's good. That's what it takes.
That's how is has to be.
What if I said you fighting them was wrong?
What if I had said let's take them to trial.
I would say you're making progress.
And we might have lost. And Ames and Darby>>
would both go free. Don't you get that?
You didn't care, Nick. You didn't even try.
You could've walked out of court>>
with your head held high. I could've lived with that, Nick.
I keep my head high, and you will end this.
I've just gotten warmed up.
This is when it turns into a shit total fucking war.
I'm gonna pull the whole thing down.
I'm gonna bring the whole fucking diseased>>
corrupt temple down on your head.
It's gonna be biblical.
Jesus, Nick, she was a good kid.
Did we bring this all on ourselves?
Absolutely not.
You don't actually believe that, do you?
Alright, gentlemen.
Sorry, we need to get going to the press conference.
Stay sharp. We're on the move.
We alright? - It's dead.
Electrical system fried.
What's going on back there?
Dunningan, tell them to get Jonas away.
What the fuck is that?
Get down! Get down!
Jonas!
No, Nick! You can't.
Please, listen to me!
Jonas!
Jonas.
I told you to handle this.
You didn't.
Now we have a jailed psycopath who's managed>>
to bring this entire city to its knees.
One of my friends was just murdered.
More than one of my friends is gone, Mayor.
What I should do is fire you.
Right now.
I resign.
Is that your real answer? - I think that's best.
No. I'm not gonna allow that to happen.
Bring me the bible.
I wont let some criminal decide whether Philadelphia>>
has a DA or not.
As of now you're acting District Attorney.
We'll have a formal swearing in later.
For now, this will suffice. Stand up.
Put your left hand on the bible, raise your right hand,>>
Repeat after me:>>
I, Nicholas Rice>>
Do solemnly swear,>>
That I will support,>>
Obey,>>
And defend the constitution of the US>>
People aren't going to work, kids aren't going to school,>>
They're scared. And I dont blame them.
So I'm implementing the emergency provision>>
of the Philadelphia code, we will lock this city down.
Starting now noone moves in this city unrestricted.
I want a show of force for the public.
Uniforms, detectives, 12 hour shifts.
Put an armed cop on every corner.
If you have to give shotguns to the meter maids, do it.
There should be no doubt in peoples minds that the>>
city is secure and under our control.
Okay, Clyde. I get it.
Listen, that contraption that killed Cantrell,>>
it was a weaponized bomb disposal robot.
Can you believe that?
Damn thing had video, night vision, you name it.
It fired military API for christ sake.
That's anti-tank rounds, Nick.
I think he's saving you for last.
Nick, I'm serious.
Appreciate the insight.
Nick, get in front of this guy if you want to stay alive.
I may have a way.
Something a friend is helping me out with.
Your friend?
Man named Chester, I'll call you back.
Thank you, Sarah.
"Hope this helps. -C">>
"CLYDE SHELTON CORPORATE>>
It's Nick.
Give me the real estate listing of every industrial property>>
sold here in the last 10 years.
Motherfucker.
You're kidding me, right?
You're saying Clyde owns this place?
Something about it sticks out, right?
Yeah.
Uhhh, you'll do what I think you're gonna do?
What about his civil rights?
Fuck his civil rights.
Yeah!
There's gotta be something in here.
Yeah.
Remember this, from outside the house?
Un-fucking believable.
Look at this.
Watch your step.
This guy tunneled into prison?
Holy shit.
Fuck, Semtex.
Police uniforms, other disguises.
He tunneled into every cell.
Over here.
Oh shit. He wanted to be transfered to solitary.
Surprise, motherfucker.
He's not here. - Then where is he?
Nomos, what happened to your eye?
Ah, long story.
Step right here, Sir.
Lets see your ID, please. - Yeah, sure.
Turn around, Sir, extend your arms.
Something going on tonight?
The Mayor.
Look at this.
He tapped into the prison cams.
Jesus, he's got cameras everywhere.
Von Clausewitz.
"City Hall Access Card" "PHILADELPHIA CITY HALL">>
He's at City Hall.
Free to go, Sir.
Sorry for the inconvenience. - Don't worry about it.
Better be safe than sorry, right?
Get ready to evacuate the building.
We'll need a tactical unit and a bomb squad.
Bad idea. Have them come in soft.
If Shelton spots them or any of us we're fucked.
Hey.
Where's the tactical team? - Coming in soft, no sirens.
Bomb squad? - You're looking at it.
Great. Okay.
We'll take the north stairs, you take the west.
Woah, woah, woah. ID's please.
He's the fucking DA! - Good for him. ID's please.
What's going on here tonight?
Judy meeting with all the press.
What floor? - 6th floor, Caucus room.
What floor is this? - That's the 5th floor, Sir.
Directly below the Caucus room.
If we catch this motherfucker red handed,>>
we gotta take him alive.
Where is he?
What the fuck are we looking for?
Wait, wait wait. Right there.
Stand back, dont touch anything.
Wasn't exactly my first instinct.
It's napalm, basically.
This will take out this floor and the floor above.
Looks like it's triggered by this cell phone here.
What, so, an incoming call arms it?
Yeah. Maybe 30 seconds until boom time.
Jesus. - Dunningan, what are you doing?
I'm calling the Mayors security. - We can't>>
Clyde is watching. If he sees them evacuate he will detonate.
We don't tell the Mayor anything.
So, what do we do?
Wait a second.
We got something. - He's pulling up.
Thank you for coming in on short notice.
I have one simple question.
Why is Clyde Shelton still in my city?
Now I refuse to believe, that one man>>
is smarter than homeland security, the FBI,>>
the Sheriffs Department, or Philly PD.
I don't care how we do it, or what kind of>>
obscure legal justification we have to invoke.
I don't care what laws we have to bend.
I am sure there is a provision of the homeland security act>>
that we can activate.
Just get him out of here by tomorrow.
Clyde.
Nick.
I wasn't expecting company.
Yeah, would've cleaned up a little.
Never seen anybody tunnel into prison before>>
And the solitary confinement was clever.
Well that's how winners play. We convince the other guy>>
he's making all the right moves.
So did you ever catch my accomplice?
Yeah, I did. It's the end of the road for him now.
You played us, Clyde, you played us real good.
Thank you. Yup.
Im glad you finally get to appreciate>>
some of the effort I put into all of this.
Well, you set out to make a point, Clyde.
You made it. - No, people still don't get it.
They dont appreciate what I'm trying to say, Nick, but...>>
they will. Soon enough.
A man I cared about once told me that we can't>>
retract the decisions that we've made, we can only>>
affect the decisions we're going to make from here.
What, are you trying to save me now, Nick?
I'm giving you a way out. Big difference.
Stand up for those principles you've been preaching,>>
we're all held accountable Clyde, that includes you.
Why don't we do the right thing here.
I'm doing the right thing, Nick.
You just have to see it that way.
By murdering all those people, all you're doing is>>
destroying the memory of your daughter.
And causing the same pain that you're suffering from.
So what do you suggest, Nick?
Make another deal?
One final offer, is that what it is?
I don't make deals with murderers anymore, Clyde.
You taught me that.
Finally. - Finally.
Well done. Bravo.
Maybe I wasnt such a bad teacher after all.
If you go through with this, Clyde,>>
it's a decision you will have to live with>>
for the rest of your life.
I'm sorry, Nick.
Me too.
Like I said, Clyde, it's a decision you will have to>>
live with for the rest of your life.
Which I figure by now is about 25 more seconds.
"DADDY">>