The subtitles in this file must be set to correctly match the spoke dialouge.
Nants ingonyama>>
Bagithi baba>>
Sithi uhhmm ingonyama>>
Ingonyama>>
What's on the menu?
It could be ceviche>>
Stinky-oo, it's Pumbaa>>
Ingonyama>>
I got to tell you, Timon...>>
that song always gets me right here.
Yeah, Pumbaa.
Well, enough of that.
Uh, Timon, what are you doing?
I'm fast forwarding to the part where we come in.
But you can't go out of order.
Au contraire, my porcine pal.
I've got the remote.
But everyone's going to get confused.
We got to go back to the beginning of the story.
We're not in the beginning of the story.
Yes, we were-- the whole time.
Yeah, but they don't know that.
Then why don't we tell them our story?
-Aah! -Aah!
Hey, I've got an idea.
Why don't we tell them our story?
Oh, I like the sound of that.
A little backstage tour.
Take them behind the scenes for a revealing and intimate look...>>
at the story within the story.
Because what they don't know is how we really were there...>>
even though they didn't know we were there, you know?
Couldn't have said it better myself.
So, does this mean we're going back to the beginning?
Oh, no, Pumbaa, no.
We're going way back...>>
to before the beginning.
Pride Rock.
So majestic.
So powerful.
So bizarrely named.
Pumbaa, how can a rock be proud? It's a rock.
I think it's because a pride is what they call a group of lions.
Oh, sure, the lions get Pride Rock.
And what about us meerkats?
Where I come from, we didn't have nothing to be proud of.
Why...ahem.
When I was a young meerkat>>
When he was a young meerkat>>
Very nice.
Thanks.
But maybe it would be safer...>>
if I just show them where I came from.
Oh, boy! Do we get to see where you grew up?
Yeah, Pumbaa, but it ain't pretty.
Please remain seated while the camera is in motion.
Here we are.
From Pride Rock to the pit of shame.
We're so low on the food chain, we're underground.
But you don't have to take my word for it.
I'll just let my fellow meerkats do the talking.
What was that, what was what?
What was that, what was that?
Where, what, where, where, What was that?
Shh!
Quick, before the hyena come>>
Clear.
Dig a tunnel, dig, dig a tunnel>>
When you're done, you dig a bigger tunnel>>
Quick, before the hyena come>>
Dig, dig a tunnel, dig, dig a tunnel>>
You could dig and never get done>>
Dig a tunnel, dig, dig a tunnel>>
What was that?
Quick before the hyena come, dig>>
Dig a tunnel is what we do>>
Life's a tunnel, we'll dig it, too>>
Dig a tunnel is what we sing>>
Dig a tunnel is everything>>
Mud and clay is a meerkat's friend>>
Always more around every bend>>
And when you get to your tunnel's end>>
HalleIujah, let's dig again, dig>>
Dig a tunnel, dig, dig a tunnel>>
When it's done, you dig a bigger tunnel>>
What was that?
Quick, before the hyena come>>
Dig>>
Timon! Excuse me.
Have you seen my son? Has he been through here?
Timon!
Dig, dig a tunnel>>
-Uncle Max? -Aah!
Uncle Max, relax. Have you seen Timon?
No, I haven't, and what a day it's been.
No fractures, no lacerations...>>
no concussions, contusions, or injuries of any sort.
As a matter of fact...>>
there's no sign of Timon's handiwork anywhere.
That would be...>>
Timon!
Heh heh heh.
Hey, everybody.
Ha ha. Nice work, Timon.
-Way to go, tunnel klutz. -Who else could break a hole?
Four in one week-- a new record.
Not again.
What? It's called a skylight.
Ho ho.
Wow. Isn't that creative?
A skylight. Oh.
Ha ha.
I'll just have a word with him.
I--I was just trying to shed a little light...>>
on our pathetic existence.
Timon, this can't go on.
Just this month, you've pulled down four walls...>>
and collapsed two tunnel exits.
We have to look after each other.
Our survival depends on it.
What's the point? All we do is dig...>>
so we can hide, and hide so we can dig.
I want to be where we don't have to dig tunnels...>>
and live with our heads stuck in the sand.
What's so bad about dreaming of a better home?
I want to show you something.
Look, Timon.
Go on, look.
past the trees...>>
over the grasslands.
Everything the light touches...>>
belongs to someone else.
Funny. I thought you were going...>>
a whole different direction with this.
What can I say? It's nature's design.
a moveable feast...>>
feared by no one and eaten by all.
B>ut when they die, they become the grass...>>
and we eat the grass, right?
Not exactly. We can't digest grass.
We're grass intolerant.
OK, Max. Thank you.
You've been a big help.
Meerkat-- it's what's for dinner.
Thank you, Uncle Max.
Uhh.
I think uncle Max dislodged one too many rocks with his skull.
But he's right, Timon.
Oh, I just know there's a way for you to fit in here.
All right, who's on sentry duty?
That's it.
That's it-- my son on sentry duty.
Timon the sentry.
Timon the sentry?
Why don't you save the hyenas the trouble and kill me now?
Just kill me now.
He has a point.
All you have to do is watch for hyenas and yell if you see one.
Look at Iron Joe.
Don't close your eyes! Don't look away!
Somebody's got to guard us!
Somebody's gotta protect us!
Well, now I'm convinced.
Listen, it's outside...>>
up in the breeze, under the wide open sky.
Isn't that what you want?
Or maybe you would rather have him...>>
go back on the digging crew.
No!
Good, then we all agree.
Timon, listen to Uncle Max.
He'll teach you everything you need to know.
And, honey, try to make this one work.
Scurry, sniff, flinch!
Good. Now...>>
what do we do if we see a hyena?
Scream, "Mommy"?
That's right, mister...>>
because the world out there is fraught with danger.
Fraught, I tell you!
Oh, boy. It's the fraught fest.
...rip us limb from limb.
Bravo, Uncle Max.
Way to sell it to the cheap seats.
Applaud now, sonny boy...>>
but try clapping when you don't have any hands.
Scurry, sniff, flinch.
Huh.
I like the sound of that.
Scurry, sniff, flinch.
There's more to life than panic>>
And bein' some other guy's snack, yuck>>
I may be delicious organic>>
But this little entree's fighting back>>
I'm gonna put digging tunnels behind me>>
And live at a new altitude>>
I'm gonna reach for the stars to remind me>>
That meerkats are not merely food>>
For once I'll be>>
Lookin' out for me>>
Yeah, I'll tell you what I want>>
This cat is movin' on>>
He's a bon vivant who's missin' out on bon>>
I'd be a bigger cheese far from the desert scene>>
A little cooling breeze, a little patch of green>>
And I'll be snoozing in my hammock>>
By a rippling stream>>
Many miles from any tunnel and the digging team>>
Looking after number one will be my only creed>>
That's all I need>>
I've always been good at running away>>
Well, now I'm gonna run to show>>
I've always been seen as the uItimate prey>>
But now my status ain't so quo>>
A dream sublime>>
It's hyena time--oh!
Oh, look, it's dinner and a show.
And I thought beans were the only musical food.
Well, hi to you, too.
Ohh!
Ow. OK.
This is no time for horseplay, Timon.
Hyenas!
Whoa, look at them scramble.
-Aah! Ohh! -Uhh!
Scrambled...>>
Aah!
And a little bit runny.
Hyenas!
Get in here.
What are you, a meshugginah?
Whoa!
Stumpy? Flinchy? Swifty?
Oh, what a relief.
Where's Uncle Max?
Aah!
Max! Run for your life!
Play dead!
¡Andale!
Almost there!
Suede is the look for this fall.
Hey, what's going on?
Pumbaa, you're sitting on the remote.
Huh? Oh, sorry. I thought it was a brownie.
You've got it, Max!
Aww!
Max!
I flinched when I should've scurried.
Ha ha! Oh, man.
It just never gets old, does it?
Ooh, the classics never do, honey.
I, uh...>>
I guess I owe everyone an apology.
All right, so I made a teensy mistake.
Like we all haven't broken into song on sentry duty before.
Ha ha ha. Come on.
Let me have a show of hands.
OK.
Maybe it's a little too soon...>>
but l'm sure we're all going to laugh about this someday.
Trust me.
I did trust you.
Ohh.
Aw, sweetie...>>
I'm never going to fit in here.
Nobody even likes me.
Sure they do, honey. Sure they do.
Besides you, Ma.
I have to find my place, but it isn't here.
Yes, it is. We just haven't found it yet.
But we will.
Stop with the hair already. My place is out there, Mom.
Oh, I may not know exactly where or how far, but I got to go.
Ma.
Well, I hope you find what you're looking for, honey.
Ooh. Ooh, I love you. Mmm!
I love you, Ma.
Oh, Timmy.
My Timmy.
Mmm. Mmm!
Mom...>>
-Ooh... -Choking. Not breathing.
Ooh!
Mmm, mmm, mmm!
And people wonder why I have issues.
Oh, I'll be OK.
Oh, I know you will. You will.
Be careful!
I will.
Don't talk to strangers!
I know, Ma!
Remember, wash behind your ears!
Ma, I'm not a kid anymore!
Never go swimming without a buddy!
Got it.
Oy.
What?
What?!
Good-bye, Ma.
And so, with high spirits...>>
I boldly ventured off...>>
where no meerkat had dared to go before.
I put my past behind me-- ha!
And never looked back.
Mommy! Mommy!
Aah! Ha ha!
What am I doing?
Which way should I go?
That depends on what you think.
How convenient.
Enter omniscient monkey, right on cue.
Well, you know what they say.
When the student is ready, the teacher appears.
That's it. No more fortune cookies for you.
Hey, where'd you come from?
Oh, the better question is, where are you going?
Oh, someplace wonderful, mister, where...>>
You didn't happen to catch the song...>>
I sang a few minutes ago, did you?
I didn't have the pleasure.
To recap, I want to live in some beautiful place outside...>>
a carefree place where I don't have to hide or worry.
Whoo! Hoo hoo hoo!
Life without worry.
You seek hakuna matata.
Harpoon a tomato?
it means "No worries.">>
Perfect. Mind taking that stick of yours...>>
and drawing me a map, bub?
Ow! Hey!
To find it, you must look beyond what you see.
What the heck is that supposed to mean?
It means look beyond what you see.
Beyond what I see.
Ha. Get a load of the monkey getting all existential on me.
Hmm.
Beyond what I see.
It's kind of hard to think with all this music.
Beyond...>>
what I see.
Oh, wait a second.
It's coming to me.
It's either that slug I ate or I'm having an epiphany.
I'm going to the big pointy rock!
Right?
Who was that strange monkey?
Ah, well.
Dream home, here I come.
Ah...oh.
Hello?
Strange but wise monkey?
Oh!
-Aah! -Aah!
You know, first impressions are very important.
Oh, I thought you were a scream.
-Aah! -Aah!
Just eat me now... and please make it fast.
I got a low threshold for pain.
Easy, easy there, little guy. I'm not going to eat you.
What? You're not?
Then why were you stalking me?
Well, gee, I saw you go by...>>
and I figured a little fellow like you>>
shouIdn't be out here all alone.
Hey, what about you? You're all alone.
You are all alone, aren't you?
Yeah. Most animals give me a pretty wide berth.
They do? Even the hungry ones?
Yeah. I drive almost everyone away.
People see me coming, and they run for cover.
They can't get out of the way fast enough.
You don't say, you don't say.
Must be the gleam on those vicious tusks, huh?
Strikes fear into their hearts.
Actually, they say I wreck their appetite.
Wow. It's like you have this--this special power.
Special power?
Well, it's pretty powerful, all right.
Perfect. You're hired.
Great! For what?
To get me to a little worry-free haven...>>
out by that big pointy rock.
And you want me to come with you?
Ha ha! Do you see any other big lovable...>>
chunk of warthog here...>>
who also happens to have razor-sharp tusks...>>
and the ability to repel predators?
I'm your pig.
You and me, I can tell-- we see eye to eye.
You mean, like friends?
Whoa, easy there, big fella.
I'd say more like... acquaintances.
Oh.
Well, it's a start.
Put 'er there, acquaintance.
-I'm Timon. -Pumbaa.
No, really.
All right, then.
Let's hit the road.
You got it...>>
acquaintance.
So, clear up one thing for me.
If you weren't going to eat me...>>
what kind of a wacky, wild pig are you?
I'm an insectivore.
Oh ho! A bug eater.
Well, me, too.
I just never had a name for it.
I'm kind of partial to the crawly critters myself.
-How about you, big boy? -I prefer the ones with wings.
Pumbaa, this could be the start of a beautiful...>>
acquaintanceship.
Nants ingonyama>>
OK, so now we're back at the beginning.
Right, Timon?
Oh, you got that right, pally.
Ingonyama>>
At last, things were looking up.
I had the sun on my shoulders, the wind at my heels...>>
A song in my heart.
-Aah! -Aah!
And to protect me, a great big fat guy.
You really think I look fat?
Uhh. Pumbaa, Pumbaa, Pumbaa.
You're a pig. It's a compliment.
Oh, thank you.
It's the circle of life>>
And it moves us all>>
Whoo-hoo!
There it is-- the big pointy rock.
Oh, baby, we're almost there.
I think we're a little late.
It's a land rush.
That loudmouth monkey.
He must've blabbed it to the whole world.
What exactly did he say?
Look beyond what you see.
So maybe you're supposed to look beyond the big pointy rock.
Maybe I'm supposed to look beyond the big pointy rock.
-Hmm? -Well...>>
let's have a little look, shall we?
Beyond what I see.
Oh ho!
What do you know?
The monkey's got an eagle eye for real estate!
Timon, look!
He-he-hey! It's the monkey!
What's that he's holding up?
Aw, who cares? It's not important.
Come on! My dream home awaits.
Uh...I don't do so well in crowds.
Maybe we better go around.
Don't you know the shortest distance...>>
between me and my dream home...>>
is a straight line? Follow me!
-Oh! -Excuse me.
-Ow. -Goodness.
Make room, make room!
Watch it, twiggy.
I'm walkin' here!
Ahem. Timon!
There's something I gotta tell you.
Pumbaa, Pumbaa, Pumbaa.
We'll have plenty of time to chat once we settle in.
I could really use a rest stop.
Don't worry. You'll get your second wind.
Ohh! I got a really bad feeling!
It'll pass!
Trust me. It'll pass.
Oh, look, the rhinos are bowing.
Ooh, we'd better bow, too.
Look, sire, how they kneel before the royal son.
So, I guess that's your special power, huh?
What a weapon!
Uh, you mean, you don't mind?
Ha ha! Are you kidding?
It was a gas! Ha ha ha ha ha!
Well, I don't like to toot my own horn.
Yeah, that's probably for the best.
Let's go, Pumbaa!
Lead the way!
This is it, buddy boy.
Home, sweet home.
And I don't gotta share it with anybody. Ha ha!
Don't you get, you know, lonely out here?
Lonely? Try commitment-free.
The elbow-to-elbow life reminds me...>>
a little too much of home.
cool refreshments, cozy little hammock...>>
a lovely water feature, and it's all mine.
Oh.
Well, it's really coming together, Timon, so, uh...>>
so, I guess I'll just be going.
Wait a minute, now. Wa-wa-wait.
There's no law that says you have to go.
Great! I already made up two beds!
One for you, and one for me.
Ohh!
Gee, all this construction work has me bushed.
Think I'll turn in early.
Ahh!
Yeah.
Ahh.
Good night!
Sleep tight.
Dream of bedbugs tonight.
Ahh.
Home, sweet home indeed.
Uhh.
Hey, keep it down up there!
We have neighbors? We should go say hello.
Noisy neighbors.
There go the property values.
Let's hear it in the herd and on the wing>>
Oh-oh>>
It's gonna be King Simba's finest fling>>
Oh, I just can't wait to be king>>
Oh, perfect. We moved to the theater district.
Get a load of these guys.
Knock it off!
Just can't wait>>
Timon, look out!
To be king>>
Aah!
I'm OK.
Oy. Phew.
Show people.
Chin up, Pumbaa.
Whoa!
Our dream home's around here somewhere.
You know, Timon, I once came across a place...>>
that might be just what you're looking for.
Spectacular waterfalls...>>
set in a lush tropicaI oasis...>>
Hey, hey. Forget it, Pumbaa.
I'm a realist, and I'm not gonna go chasing after some fantasy.
I'm going beyond what I see.
But if you always go beyond what you see...>>
how do you know when you're there?
Oh, I'll tell you how I know.
We're there!
This is a lovely spot.
Lovely, rustic, picturesque.
Home, sweet home, Pumbaa. Mm-hmm.
Aah!
Whoop! Ah ha ha ha!
I--I mean, sure, it needs a little work...>>
but it's got good bones.
Ha ha ha! After all, this is an elephant graveyard...>>
and who would ever come to an elephant graveyard?
Aah!
Sire, the hyenas are after the children!
I see carnivores.
Beyond what you see.
Beyond what you see. Ha ha ha ha ha!
Beyond what you see!
Uh, Timon? Would this be a bad time...>>
to bring up that little place I told you about?
Hey! This is home, sweet home, baby!
Home--aaaah!
Ow! Ha ha!
Steam! Ha ha! Steam is good.
Steam is--is--is water. Whoo! Gotta have water.
You know, for the dream home.
Steam home, dream home.
Steam, steam, steam.
I am perfectly happy right here!
It's remote, private...>>
no unexpected visitors.
Somethin' tells me this ain't...>>
the traveling company of "Riverdance.">>
Beyond what you see.
Hey, how am I supposed...>>
to look beyond what I see beyond that?
Huh?
Oh, sorry.
What this place lacks in water and shade...>>
it makes up for with searing heat and blinding sunshine.
Home, sweet home, Pumbaa.
Uhh...>>
Shall we run for our lives?
Oh, yes, let's.
-Aah! -Aah!
Hang on, Timon!
This is it!
Good-bye, cruel world!
Aaaaaaah!
Uhh!
That's it?
That wasn't so bad.
You can't knock old Timon down that easy!
Yeah! Bring it on!
Uh, Pumbaa?
is it possible to fall off the edge of the earth?
Uh, technically, no.
The earth is round like a sphere, Timon...>>
so it doesn't actually have an edge.
-Aaaaaah! -Aaaaaah!
You mind if I pause it for a second?
Sure, go ahead.
Be right back.
Uhh!
It's a small world after all>>
It's a small, small world>>
Everybody>>
It's a small world after all>>
Da da da da da da da>>
OK, I got the jumbo so we could share.
Were you just picking your nose?
No, I had an itch on the inside.
-Aaaaaah! -Aaaaaah!
Ooh!
Ohh.
Timon, you OK?
Uhh. I give up.
Uh, but you can't give up.
We still haven't found our dream home.
Forget it, Pumbaa.
I've been dragging you down long enough.
I'm going home, and I suggest you do the same.
Oh, I--I would if I could, but I can't.
Oh, sure you can, buddy. I won't stop you.
No, I mean...>>
I don't have a home.
You don't? What happened? Are you lost?
No place good enough for you?
What, you're all alone in this big empty world?
Oh.
The truth is...>>
I'm all alone, too.
Pumbaa, you're the only friend I've ever had.
Y-you mean...>>
Yeah, Pumbaa...and friends stick together to the end.
Timon, are you crying?
I'm fine.
I--I just have something in my eye.
Here, blow.
Ohh!
Here, Pumbaa.
Gee, thanks.
OK, I'm better.
Uhh!
Uhh! Ooh!
Aw, well.
It's too bad we never found that perfect place.
Why'd we ever listen to that stupid monkey?
I think maybe you're giving up too soon, Timon.
Beyond what you see.
Huh?
Remember that place I told you about?
Forget about your place.
Get a load of what I found.
Talk about beyond what you see.
Pumbaa, this is our dream home.
Dramatic views.
Your very own porch swing.
Hot tub and spa.
Well stocked cupboard.
Let's celebrate!
The monkey was right.
We found it-- the perfect life.
I'll just whip up a little something.
He had the perfect name for it, too.
Come and get it.
Such a wonderful phrase. It had this rhythm.
Laduda Ladada.
Try this-- hot tuna frittata.
Hmm. No, that's not it.
The spinach armada.
Quiet, Pumbaa. I'm trying to think.
A spoon of ricotta.
Two words.
A wormy piccata.
Six syllables.
Kahuna colada.
Twelve letters.
A blue enchilada.
-Legumes on a platter. -Think.
This ought to be hotter.
-I forget. -I got to lambada!
Hey, how can you dance at a time like this?
I'm dying here.
Ooh, sorry about that, pal.
Hakuna matata.
Wahh-ahh-ahh... come again?
Hakuna matata-- it means "No worries.">>
Uh--oh.
Hey, Timon, I got an idea.
Let's do a sing-along.
Oh, you tease.
I Iove karaoke. I'm there.
Wait a second.
Pumbaa, where's the grub?
Puhh.
Oh, you just can't help yourself, can you?
Sorry.
OK, but this time, show a little self-control.
Ha ha!
Hahuna ma-what-a?
Oh ho ho ho ho!
It means "No worries.">>
I see.
So, I told the boy to find hakuna matata...>>
you must look beyond what you see.
Oh, a metaphor.
Well, actually, it's not a meta--aah!
You used a metaphor on Timon?
He takes things literally.
That's it. He's starving out there.
I just know it.
Max, Timon's out there chasing metaphors.
I've got to go find him.
Are you nuts?
Nice to have a supportive family, isn't it?
Well, here I go.
Remember, the journey of a thousand miles...>>
begins with the first step.
Thanks. Here's my first step.
Yeow!
Ay!
This bowling for porcupines...>>
wasn't the best idea, huh?
Yeah. Got to be right up there...>>
with bobbing for snapping turtles.
Aah ha ha!
Oh, that's going to leave a little mark.
Hey, look, Timon, buzzards.
What do you say, one more round?
Oh, sure. There must be some part of me...>>
we haven't injured yet.
Oh, please?
Oh, please, oh, please, oh, please, oh, please?
Nah, Pumbaa, I'm beat.
You go ahead. I'm calling it a day.
But it's no fun alone.
Aw, why not?
One more run won't change our lives.
-Yaah! -Yaah!
Who knows why fate led us...>>
to little Simba that day.
Maybe it was just my love of adventure...>>
or my innate courage...>>
OK, who's in charge of the freeze frames?
Sorry.
Anywho...>>
rescuing Simba was a cinch.
parenthood.
In the jungIe, the mighty jungle>>
The lion sleeps tonight>>
In the jungle, the mighty jungle...>>
Timon. Timon.
Timon!
Oh. Ohh.
-I got to go. -Go?
Go where?
You know, go--bad.
Oh, go. Why didn't you say so? Come on, let's go.
When you got to go, you got to go.
Young lion, get down from there.
Whoo-hoo! All right!
Man, you guys look like ants down there.
I'm counting to three.
Yahoo!
Uh-oh.
Three.
In the jungle, the mighty jungle>>
Timon.
Oh! Again?
No. I'm thirsty.
You know this means you'll be up again...>>
about two hours from now.
Jungle boogie>>
Jungle boogie, get it on>>
Hang on, Simba! I'll save you!
Yahoo!
Whoa!
Timon?
The mighty jungle...>>
We're going to get old walking across this thing.
- Jungle boogie -Whoa!
-Timon? -Aah!
What have you got against the concept...>>
of a good night's sleep, huh?
Actually, I, uh...>>
I had a bad dream.
Oh, well...>>
Uhh! It wasn't me.
Junior had a bad dream.
Ohh.
Why don't you sleep over here with us?
Mi Pumbaa, su Pumbaa.
All right!
The lion sIeeps tonight>>
Good night.
Sleep tight.
Dream of bedbugs tonight.
Uyy!
My little darling>>
Don't fear, my little darling>>
Hey-a, oh, my little darling>>
Oh, don't fear, my little darling>>
Don't fear, my little darling>>
Hey-a, oh, my little darling>>
Whoa. Watch where you aim that morning breath.
That should come with a warning label.
Whoo, what a wake-up call.
Heh heh heh. Looks like someone woke up...>>
on the wrong side of the warthog.
What's the matter, pops?
Had a little too much hakuna matata?
Ooh. Sonny boy, I invented hakuna matata.
Oh, yeah? Well, I perfected it.
Sure you did, sure you did.
Pumbaa, who holds the record for the world's longest bug belch?
Uh, that would be Simba.
All righty, then.
Who's the champion at slug swallowing?
Simba again.
-Cricket crunching? -Simba.
-Grub gulping? -Simba.
-Maggot munching? -Still Simba.
Snail slurping?
Oh, uh, nobody.
We never had a snail eating contest before.
I don't think this is such a good idea.
Uhh...>>
I told you this wasn't such a good idea.
Thus did the pupil surpass the teacher.
You've been hanging around...>>
with the monkey again, haven't you?
Uhh.
Our Simba is growing up.
Is this the littIe boy I carried?
When did he grow to be so tall?
Wasn't it yesterday>>
When he was small?
Sunrise, sunset>>
SwiftIy fly the years>>
One season following another>>
Laden with happiness>>
And tears>>
So, you see, that's why they call it a dung beetle.
Ew. You don't say.
And yet still so tasty.
Oh, yeah, and they're my favorite, too.
Ooh!
Ah. Ahh.
Just what the doctor ordered.
Yep. After a long day of doing nothing...>>
it's good to kick back.
Three pals and no worries.
What more could you want?
Ahh.
I'm bushed.
Think I'll turn in for the night.
I'm out.
Right behind you.
-Oh! -Ah ha ha!
You're killing me.
Ha ha!
Timon, it's your turn to say good night.
Good night.
Sleep tight.
Dream of bedbugs tonight.
Ahh. You got to admit...>>
we had a pretty good thing going there.
We couId've gone on like that forever.
Except for one teeny weeny little thing...>>
we forgot to count on.
Nala?
-Waah! -Waah!
This is a disaster, Pumbaa-- a disaster, I tell you.
You mean because they've finally found each other...>>
like two soul mates joined across the years...>>
by the bonds of true love?
Sweet, innocent little Pumbaa.
She's going to put a stake right through the heart...>>
of our hakuna matata.
Oh, then I guess we ought to do something.
And I know just what it is.
Pumbaa, we can't let them feel the love tonight.
Ow!
Aah!
Can you feel the love tonight?
That's so romantic.
Uhh.
Can you feel the love tonight?
Aah!
Whoa! Oh!
-Waah! -Waah!
-Aah! -Aah!
Can you feel the love tonight?
The peace the evening brings?
-Aah! Oof! -Aah! Oof!
Well, that worked like a dream.
It did?
Sarcasm is a foreign language to you, isn't it?
Look!
Can you feel the love tonight?
She's making those eyes.
He's smiling that smile.
They're laughing...>>
and hugging...>>
and--and...>>
And if he falls in love tonight>>
It can be assumed>>
His carefree days>>
With us are history>>
In short, our pal is doomed>>
Ah, that's it, buddy.
We gave it our best shot, but he's a goner.
Maybe not.
You never give up, do you?
Look.
You don't even know what I've been through.
-I would if you'd just tell me. -Forget it.
Fine!
Pumbaa, do you know what this means?
Uh, he can't express his feelings...>>
and she has commitment issues?
We won. Ya ha ha!
We split them up.
And, uh, that's a good thing?
Uh, he seems to be taking it kind of hard.
Yeah, I know. Look, I...>>
But it's the best thing for us.
I mean for him. Ooh, let's go, Pumbaa.
I think this storm's coming to a head.
Hakuna matata is safe at last, pal...>>
because nothing's going to take our boy away now.
He's gone? What do you mean, he's gone?
It's just like the baboon said.
The king has returned.
Ohh. You want me to go over it again?
Yes, please, but be a dear...>>
not that your childhood wasn't fascinating.
OK, look, Simba's the rightful king...>>
but after he disappeared...>>
Scar proclaimed himself the king...>>
and formed an alliance with the hyenas.
the treachery, the villainy...>>
the sheer indescribabIe horror.
Blah, blah, blah.
Why is she toying with us?
Oh, this crazy chick is going to eat us.
Simba has to go home to challenge his uncle...>>
and reclaim his rightful place as king.
Ooh, don't you get it?
Simba needs us--now!
He needs us?
Then he shouldn't have left us!
If he wants to run off to be "His Highness"...>>
well, I say don't let the branches hit you...>>
on the way out.
Leave hakuna matata to someone who appreciates it.
But, Timon, it's not really hakuna matata without Simba.
What's gotten into you? Not hakuna matata?
That's crazy talk-- crazy talk, I tell you.
Nothing's changed here.
We had hakuna matata before Simba...>>
and we've still got it now.
We got to go help our friend, Timon.
Et tu, Pumbaa?
You're just going to walk away, give up on all this?
What happened to "friends stick together to the end"?
Huh, huh, huh?
I was about to ask you the same thing.
I got everything I ever wanted right here.
Elbow room.
Uhh.
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy.
Hakuna matata>>
What a wonderfuI phrase>>
Ain't no passing craze>>
It means...>>
Uhh.
No worries.
Hoo hoo hoo hoo hoo hoo hoo!
Ha ha!
You. No, no. Don't say a word.
I know what you're going to say.
Did you find hakuna matata?
Well, yes, I did.
Thank you very much.
And I am happy.
Happy, happy, deliriously happy.
Ho ha ha! I see.
Happy, is it?
So, if you're so happy, why do you look so miserable?
MiserabIe, you say?
Why should I be miserable?
Oh, I don't know. Maybe my two best pals...>>
in the world deserted me.
Heh. They've--they've headed off on some heroic mission.
My friends are gone.
And my hakuna matata went with them.
Would you mind?
Ay!
Thanks. I'm glad we had this talk.
My work here is done.
Friends stick together to the end.
What was with the running? If you can call that running.
I was giving you time to catch up.
Aw, you big lug.
Hop on, buddy.
We got a fight to catch.
Let's whip some grass.
This is the stuff of legends--an epic struggle...>>
the place where heroes are born.
Pumbaa, this couId be our finest hour.
Luau!
If you're hungry for a hunk of fat and juicy meat>>
Heh heh. Let's just cut to the chase, shall we?
Oh, sure.
-Aah! -Aah!
I love the smell of Pumbaa in the morning.
Hey, hey, hey, move your tush, honey.
Ma? Uncle Max?
-Oh, Timmy! -Timon?
What are you doing here?
Looking for you. Aw. Mommy's here.
Well, let me introduce you to my best friend.
Pumbaa, Ma, Uncle Max.
Ma, Uncle Max, Pumbaa.
Aah!
Look, there's Simba, and that must be his uncle Scar.
Oh, good, they're talking things out...>>
which is how it should be.
You know, I have a feeling...>>
everything's going to be just fine.
Ohh!
On the other hand...>>
the hyenas are up there protecting Scar.
What do we do?
Well, I've got a plan.
How can we help?
Ma, Uncle Max, you're going to dig a trap.
We're going to need...>>
dare I say it?
Tunnels--lots and lots of tunnels.
And, Pumbaa, you and me...>>
we've got to get those hyenas away from Simba.
Ooh, ooh! And lure them into the trap?
Ho ho! Nothing gets past you.
Come on, Pumbaa, let's ride.
Something's different about Timon.
You think? He's wearing a dress!
Hey, Pumbaa.
What do you call a hyena with half a brain?
Ha ha ha! Beats me, Timon. What?
Gifted.
Ha ha--ooh!
They're talking about us.
For your last meal, you're going to eat those words.
-Yaah! -Yaah!
-Uhh! -Ooh!
Ma, I think we got their attention.
Not yet. Keep stalling.
OK.
You got to be kidding me.
Now, Ma?
Need more time, honey.
Uh, freestyle.
Ooh, encore, encore.
No, no, no. You mean entree, entree.
No, you right. Let's just eat them.
Is it ready yet, Ma?
Not yet. Keep stalling.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Hold on a second.
Uh, Timon? What are you doing?
Shenzi Marie Predatora Veldetta Jacquelina Hyena...>>
would you do me the honor of becoming my bride?
I don't think so.
Shenzi Marie, please. I know what you're thinking.
We're too different. It'll never work.
What will the children look like?
Ooh, that violates so many laws of nature.
Listen to me. The problems of a couple of wacky kids...>>
like us don't amount to a hill of termites...>>
in this nutty circle of Iife thing.
And so I ask you-- if not now, when?
If not me, who?
I'm lonely.
Can I be your best man?
I say we skip the wedding and go straight to the buffet.
Now?
Sure, if you're ready.
Oh.
Now, Max, now!
Hyenas in the hole!
-Huh? -Huh?
Aah!
I need help. It didn't work.
Hey, it works for me.
What are we going to do?
What?
Timon, no!
Let's get 'em.
I'd say Scar is down and out.
We did it! We did it!
Where's Timon? Where's my baby?
He's hurt! Oh, no! Oh, no! He's dead! Or worse!
We got to find him. We've got to find him.
It's OK, Ma.
Oh, please. It is not OK!
Don't you tell me it's OK!
Timmy!
-Mmm-mm! -Ooh!
My son...>>
the hero.
You missed a spot.
That's so beautiful.
Choking. Not breathing.
I couldn't have done it without you guys.
That's our boy.
Ohh, I promised myself I wasn't going to cry.
You've really come a long way, Timon.
Did you find what you were looking for?
I found a place that was beyond my wildest dreams...>>
but it still wasn't home.
Let's go home, Ma.
Oh!
a predator-free environment.
I got to hand it to you, Timon. This place has everything.
Well, now that we're all here, it does.
Crane...>>
spreads its wings, turns with dainty hands.
Dig a tunnel, dig, dig a tunnel>>
We're never gonna dig another tunnel>>
Never gonna hyena come>>
Sing the praises of great Timon>>
The greatest meerkat we've ever known>>
Never dreamed he'd heIp Simba shine>>
Proved it's cool to hang out with swine>>
Accidentally saved the day>>
Planned it so it wouId look that way>>
Brought us out of the dirt and sand>>
Brought his famiIy to the promised land>>
Sing the praises of great Timon>>
Greatest meerkat we've ever known>>
the big wrap-up, the happy ending...>>
the grand finale.
It's over already?
Well, Pumbaa, that's the thing about endings.
They come at the end.
Ooh, can we watch it again?
Pumbaa, we just saw it. Maybe tomorrow.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
You didn't tell me you were watching the movie.
I want to watch, too.
Ma, we just finished. Show's over.
Well, you're just going to have to rewind it.
Ma!
Uncle Max, we're going to watch the movie.
Oh, no!
Hey, I brought extra butter.
Hey, you guys are watching the movie?
Hoo hoo hoo hoo hoo hoo hoo!
Any story worth telling is worth telling twice.
-What the-- -Oh, excuse me.
-Excuse me. -Excuse me.
-Excuse me. -Get out of the way.
Who is this crowd?
Hey, down in front!
Aha!
Gawrsh!
Aloha!
Watch it!
Unh!
Ohh!
Ow!
OK, buddy, you win.
Sure you don't mind?
Hakuna matata.
-Shh. -Sorry.
Timon...>>
I still don't do so well in crowds.
Quick before the hyena come>>
All we do is dig...>>
so we can hide and hide so we can dig.
Dig>>
All we do is dig...>>
so we can hide and hide so we can dig.
Dig>>
Dig a tunnel, dig, dig a tunnel>>
Keep a-digging, never get done>>
Quick, before the hyena come>>
Dig a tunnel, dig, dig a tunnel>>
Keep a-digging, never get done>>
Quick, before the hyena come>>
Hakuna matata.
All we do is dig...>>
so we can hide and hide so we can dig.
Dig>>
Hakuna matata.
Quick, before the hyena, hyena, hyena come>>
Dig a tunnel, dig, dig a tunnel>>
Keep a-digging, never get done>>
Quick, before the hyena come>>
Can you dig it?
I can dig it>>
Whoo!
Oh, yeah>>
Oh whoa whoa whoa>>
Sure is memories living in the grass>>
Grazing in the grass, it's a gas>>
Baby, can't you dig it?
What a trip just watching as the world goes past>>
Grazing in the grass, it's a gas>>
Baby, can't you dig it?
There are so many groovy things to see>>
While grazing in the grass>>
Grazing in the grass, it's a gas>>
Baby, can't you dig it?
Flowers with colors>>
Making everything out of sight in the grass>>
Grazing in the grass, it's a gas>>
Here we go>>
The sun beaming down between the leaves>>
Grazing in the grass, it's a gas>>
Baby, can't you dig it?
And the birds>>
Darting in and out of the trees>>
Grazing in the grass, it's a gas>>
Yeah, yeah>>
And everything here is so clear>>
You can see it>>
And everything here is so near>>
You can feel it>>
And it's real>>
So real, so real>>
So real, so real, so real>>
Can you dig it?
I can dig it, he can dig it, she can dig it>>
We can dig it, they can dig it, you can dig it>>
Oh, let's dig it>>
Can you dig it, baby?
I can dig it, he can dig it, she can dig it>>
We can dig it, they can dig it, you can dig it>>
Oh, let's dig it>>
Can you dig it, baby?
We, let's dig it>>
I can dig it, he can dig it, she can dig it>>
We can dig it, baby, everybody, let's dig it>>
Can you dig it, baby?
The sun beaming down between the leaves>>
Ooh>>
And the birds>>
Darting in and out of the trees>>
Everything here is so clear>>
You can see it>>
And everything here is so near>>
You can feel it>>
And it's real>>
So real, so real>>
So real, so real, so real>>
Can you dig it?
Oh, yeah>>
I can dig it, he can dig it, she can dig it>>
We can dig it, they can dig it, you can dig it>>
Oh, let's dig it>>
Can you dig it, baby?
I can dig it, he can dig it, she can dig it>>
We can dig it, they can dig it, you can dig it>>
Oh, let's dig it>>
Can you dig it, baby?
I can dig it, he can dig it, she can dig it>>
We can dig it, they can dig it, you can dig it>>
Oh, let's dig it>>
Baby>>
I can dig it, he can dig it, she can dig it>>
We can dig it, they can dig it, you can dig it>>
Oh, Iet's dig it>>
Everything here is so cIear>>
You can feeI it>>
I can dig it, he can dig it, she can dig it>>
We can dig it, baby, everybody dig it>>
It's Timon-a-rama time!
I've never been the type>>
You'll have a perfect home>>
To form a hole and hide>>
When old hyenas come>>
Above the meerkat role>>
Where it's a shooting scene>>
In some organic hole>>
Then you won't have to fear>>
And all that circle rot>>
Is just a cunning plot>>
For comin' to the crunch>>
I ain't nobody's lunch>>
Get on the roundabout>>
This isn't a diversion, it's a monkeyshine>>
I ain't asking for a lot>>
But what is mine is mine>>
You never want to argue with a chorus line>>
That's all I need>>
That is all he needs>>
Whoa, whoa, I'm begging pIease>>
Whoa, begging pIease>>
That is all>>
I>>
Need>>
That is all I need>>