I'm sorry... Sorry.
No, Stay.
What's your name?
Andrew Neyman.
What year are you?
I'm... a first year
You know who I am?
Yes sir.
So you know I'm looking for players?
Then why did you stop playing?
Did I ask you to start playing again?
-Ugh, I'm sorry... -I asked you
why did you stop playing and
your version of an answer was
to turn into a wind-up monkey
-I'm... I'm sorry.  -Show me your rudiments.
Yes sir.
Double time swing.
No double time, double it.
Faster.
Faster!
Woopsy-daisy, forgot my jacket.
No Swedish Fish?
Not today.
Thanks.
-You ok?  -Yeah
Yeah, I don't know. He saw me play today.
And?
You got plenty of options still.
What does that mean? Other options?
Just.. You know.
It's just life.
You get to be my age, you get perspective.
I don't want perspective
Sorry.
I don't want raisin in it.
Why didn't you say that?
I just eat around them.
I don't understand you.
My man Ryan, yo shit!
How you feeling man?
Things were hurting with
Neyman on the kits.
Hey what's up bro. Had a good weekend?
Yeah real good. Lot of fun.
Hey, don't worry about Greg. He's a dick.
No big deal.
Good morning everybody.
Morning.
Alright. Let's do Billy's
Ann, from the top, yes?
One Two Three
Alright let's do... Reese
Yo Ryan
Alright alright.
That's enough for that, just
back to the core drummer please.
Core players, let's go.
Dude, what've you been practicing?
May I?
Cute.
Down the line, trumpets, bar 78.
Three Four
Ok, alright.
the bar 24, the end of two.
Maybe not.
Let's pick up on 211, Three Four.
Same spot, three four.
Alright.
You're in the first chair, let's see
if it's just because you are cute.
Three Four.
Yeah, that's why.
Drums, let's hear a
little double-time swing.
Behind?
Same thing.
Bass, five bars down the lead
Alright.
Drums, with me.
Thank you Joe
No no no, other drums.
Room B16, tomorrow morning 6am
Don't be late.
Alright everybody, from the top.
One Two Three
Hey  How are you?
Good, how are you?
I'm good, thanks.
The usual?
Ugh... Nah, Look I don't know how...
I see you here a lot,
and I think you are...
really pretty.
Would you want go out with me... ever?
Please go away.
Oh my god. I'm so sorry, I'm so sorry.
I'm just messing with you.
I'm messing with you.
Oh my god.
I'm sorry.
That's actually pretty mean
-I'm sorry, I didn't mean to..
what's your name? -No big deal.
-Oh I'm Andrew.   -Andrew
I'm Nicole
Nice to meet you Nicole.
Nice to meet you too.
So you wanna take me out?
I'd... love to take you out.
-Where you wanna go?  -Pizza.
-Pizza. I like pizza. -Yeah
I know a great pizza place.
Cool, well...
I get off at 7 on Monday.
Okay?
-You wanna meet here..
-Oh ok, yeah, I will.
Great
-Ok. Seven o'clock?
-Here   -7pm
-Monday   -Alright, bye.
-You are the new alternate?
-Yeah, I'm Andrew Neyman.
-Tune the set to a B-flat and
turn my pages during rehearsal
Sure
Excuse me, can you give me a B-flat?
Thank you.
Sorry, can you... just one more time?
It's a great kit.
Milk the cunt!
We got a squeaker today people.
Neyman, 19 years old
isn't he cute?
Alright gang, "Whiplash"
Page.
Page!
Barker, that is not your boyfriend's
dick, do not come early.
Bar 93
Five Six and..
Stop!
Now this one really upsets me. We
have an out-of-tone player here.
Before I continue, would that
player care to identify himself?
No? Ok, maybe a bug flew in my ear.
Five Six and..
No, my ears are fine, we definitely
have an out-of-tone player.
Whoever it is, this is your last chance.
And there it went.
Now either you are deliberately playing
out-of-tone and sabotaging my band
Or you don't know you are out-of-tone
which I'm afraid is even worse.
Five Six and..
Bones
He's here.
Tell me it's not you, Elmer Fudd.
It's ok. Play.
Do you think you are out of tone?
What're you... There's no fucking Mars
bar down there, what are you looking at?
Look up here, look at me.
Do you think, you are out of tone?
Yes.
Then why the fuck didn't you say so?!
I carried your fat ass for too long Metz
I'm not gonna have you cost
us a competition because
your mind's on a fucking Happy
Meal instead of on pitch.
Jackson congratulations,
you are fourth chair.
Mets why are you still sitting
there, get the fuck out!
For the record, Mets wasn't out of tone
You were, Ericson
But he didn't know.
And that's bad enough.
Alright take 10, when we get
back the squeaker is on.
Andrew
Parents are musicians?
No
What do they do?
My dad's a writer.
Oh what's he written
I guess he's more of a teacher. Really.
Oh. College?
Pennington High School.
What about your mother? What does she do?
I don't know. She left when I was a baby.
So no musicians in the family?
Well you just gotta listen
to the greats then.
Buddy Rich, Jo Jones
You know Charlie Parker became Bird
because Jo threw a cymbal at his head
See what I'm saying?
Listen, the key is to just... relax.
Don't worry about the numbers, don't worry
about what the other guys are thinking.
You are here for a reason.
You believe that right?
Yeah.
Say it.
I'm here for a reason.
Cool
Alright man, have fun.
Alright gang, Whiplash
A little under tempo ok? Neyman.
Just do your best.
There you go.
Five Six and...
Let's hear some feels.
We got Buddy Rich here.
A little trouble there.
Pick it up on 17
Five Six and
Not quite my tempo.
Here we go. Five Six and..
Down beat on 18. Here we go.
Five Six and...
Bar 17 the end of four.
Five Six Seven...
Not quite my tempo.
It's all good, no worries, here we go.
Five Six Seven
You're rushing. Here we go.
Ready?
Ok. Five Six and...
Dragging. Just here.
Wait for my cue.
Five Six Seven..
Rushing.
Five Six and..
Dragging.
Five Six and...
Why do you suppose I just hurled
a chair at your head, Neyman?
I.. I don't know.
Sure you do.
The tempo?
Were you rushing or were you dragging?
I... I don't know.
Start counting.
-Five Six..  -In 4 damnit! Look at me!
One two three four One two
three four One two three four
Now, was I rushing or was I dragging?
I don't know.
Count again.
One two three four One two
three four One two three four
-Rushing or dragging?  -Rushing.
So you do know the difference!
If you deliberately sabotage my
band, I'll fuck you like a pig.
Now are you a rusher, or are you a dragger
Or are you gonna be on my fucking time?!
I'll be on your time.
What does that say?
-Quarter note equals 215   -Count me a 215.
One two three four One two three four
Jesus fucking Christ, I don't know
they allow retards into Shaffer.
Am I to understand you cannot read tempo?
Can you even fucking read music?
What is that?
Yes, what is that?
A dotted sixteenth
Sing me a measure 101
What are you, in a fucking acapella group?
Play the goddamn kit!
Stop!
Now answer my question.
Were you rushing, or were you dragging?
Answer!
Rushing.
Oh my dear god.
Are you one of those single tear people?
Do I look like a double
fucking rainbow to you?
-You must be upset. Are you upset?   -No
No. So you just don't give
a shit about any of this?
-I do give a shit... -So are
you upset, yes or fucking no?
-Yes -You are upset.
Yeah
Say it.
I'm upset.
Say it to the whole band can hear you.
Louder.
I'm upset.
Louder!
I'm upset!
You are a worthless friendless
faggot-lipped little piece of shit
Whose mommy left daddy, when she
figured out he wasn't Eugene O'neil
And who's now weeping and
slobbering all over my drum set
like a fucking nine-year-old girl
So for the final father fucking time...
Say it louder!!!
I'm upset!!
Carl.
Start practicing harder Neyman
Whiplash, bar 125.
Big boy tempo
Five six and...
This place is nice.
Yeah
I really liked the music that they play.
I mean the food is good too, but...
The pizza is really good.
When I wake.
What?
That's the name of the song.
Jacky Hill, July 17th, 1938
Bob Ellis on the drums.
You know every time I
saw you at the theater
Your eyes were glued to the floor.
Really?
My dad says that I have
trouble making eye contact.
My parents like to criticize me too.
When I was growing up my mom said
that I had a really big chin.
And that's why guys don't like me
-Really?   -Yeah.
-You don't. -Well she said
my dad curse me with one.
-No it's not.   -Yeah it is.
I don't... I don't think so at all.
Your chin is very... nice.
Very nice.
Your mom sounds insane.
Well she did want to be an
actress when she was my age.
What about you?
What about me?
What do you do?
I go to Fordham.
What do you study?
I don't... have a major yet.
...like what do you want to study?
I don't really know.
I don't know yet.
So Fordham was just like a random school?
No I've applied a bunch of
schools, Fordham let me in.
Why do you go to Shaffer?
It's the best music school in the country.
Well Fordham is Fordham.
I don't love there to be honest.
-No?  -No.
I don't know... I guess it's just
people there don't like me very much.
I'm from Arizona, and I think they can...
see it.
I kinda feel the same way
about people in Shaffer.
Yeah I don't think they like me too much.
But I don't...
I don't care too much.
I think it's just... it changes.
You know people change, things work out.
Yeah I know I know I know.
I just...
I feel like homesick sometimes.
I don't know.
Kind pissed me off when people
pretend like they are not.
In college, you know.
Maybe I'm literally the
only one, I don't know.
I still go to the movies with my dad.
Hey how are you man.
Good.
Is this really Eva?
Wow, last time I saw you
you were very tiny.
Are you playing an instrument yet?
She started piano last week.
Hey when you are a big college kid
Will you come and play in my band?
-Do you like that? -Would
you be my piano player?
Excellent, give me five
-Alright, great seeing you.
-Great seeing you.
See you after the show. Alright cheers.
Listen up cocksuckers!
Hurry the fuck up.
Get your music.
Rhythm Section out first
Tanner, the kit is a
fucking tonal catastrohpy
Get it in tone alright?
Rhythm and soloists, bar 45
we gonna pick up the tempo there alright?
Bar 106, brass, do not
forget we sharp that knife.
Everybody remember, Lincoln Center
and its ilk use these competitions
to decide who they are interested
in and who they are not
And I am not gonna have my reputation
in that department tarnished
by a bunch of fucking
limp-dick, sour-note, flattered
on their girlfriend's
flexible tempo dipshits.
Got it?
One more thing. Eugene give me that.
If I ever find another one
of these lying around again
I swear to fucking god I
will stop being so polite.
Get fuck out of my sight
before I demolish you.
Stage right, in order, now.
I can still fucking see you, Mini-Me!
Let's go, hurry the fuck up. Let's go.
Shaffer Conservatory, Studio Band.
Hold onto this for the second set.
I think he wants a career
But as long as Fletcher is here, Fudd
don't have a chance get back in..
I need to look at the music.
Oh yeah it's right here.
Why isn't it on you?
Where's the folder?
-You're joking right? -I have no..
No I literally
No.. I swear I just had
it here two seconds ago
It's gotta be around here.
-How could you be so fucking stupid?
-I don't
know, maybe a janitor
came bay or something..
-A janitor?  -Yeah
-Find the fucking folder!
A fucking janitor?!
You are done! Fuck!
I'm done! Fuck!
-Find the folder!  -I'm sorry.
Tanner!
Jesus fucking Christ, where have you been??
We have an issue..
Ok, now is not the time.
I gave... Neyman the
folder and Neyman lost it.
Neyman lost it?
Yes.
The folder is your fucking
responsibility, Tanner
Why would you give it to Neymon, right?
You gave a calculator to a fucking retard
he's gonna try turn on the TV with it.
Now get your stick and get
your ass on the stage
I... I can't
You.. can't?
I can't go on stage, I don't
know the charts.. by heart.
Are you fucking kidding me?
I.. you know this.
I need the music, it's my
memory, I need visual cues.
-Visual cues?  -It's a medical condition..
Medical condition? What are
you, fucking Sunjay Gupta?
Play the goddamn music!
-I can't -I can.
You know Whiplash by heart?
Yes sir, every measure.
Alright. You better fucking hope
your memory doesn't fail you
And and you can play a whole lot better
than you did last month at the rehearsal
Because I do not intend start losing now.
Get your stick and get your
fucking ass on the stage.
On stage!
And first place
Shaffer Conservatory
Don't touch my folder man.
Do not touch this kit.
Alright let's get to work ladies.
Tanner what are you doing? It's core only
today, I don't have time for alternates.
Cherokee, from the top.
Tanner are you a fucking statue? Let's go!
Get off the stool.
Don't forget to turn Neyman's pages.
Here we go, one two three
four two two three four
So how's everything going
with the Studio Band?
Good. I think he likes me more now.
And his opinion means a
lot to you, doesn't it?
Yeah
overcooked.
can barely chew this
He just left.
So how's drumming going Andy?
Yeah it's going really well.
I'm the new core drummer...
-Did you hear yet?  -No, what happened?
Travis just got MVP
That's fantastic!
Dustin is heading up Model UN,
soon-to-be-Rhodes-Scholar
and who knows what
And Jim, teacher of the year
I mean, come on, the talent of
this table, that is stunning.
And Andy, with your drumming.
It's going ok, Andy?
Yeah I mean it's going really, really well.
Actually I'm part of
Shaffer's top Jazz orchestra
Which means I'm.. it's
the best in the country.
And.. I'm a core member, so I
just started playing competitions
Actually I just found out I'm the
youngest person in the entire band.
How do you know wins or not..
a music competition?
Isn't it subjective?
No.
Does the studio get you a job?
No it's not an actual studio, it's
just the name of the ensemble
but yeah it's a big step for my career.
Well I'm so glad you figured it out,
it's a nasty business I am sure.
Oh are you gonna tell them
about your game this week?
Lived up to your title
I scored 93 yard touchdown
School record, school record!
It's division III.
It's Carleton football, it's not
even division II, it's division III
You got any friends Andy?
-No. -Why's that?
I don't know, I just never
really saw the use.
Well, who are you going
to play with otherwise?
Lennon and McCartney, they were
school friends, am I right?
Charlie Parker didn't know anybody 'til
Joe Jones threw a cymbal at his head.
So that's your idea of success, huh?
I think being the greatest musician of the
20th century is anybody's idea of success.
Dying broke and drunk and
full of heroin at the
age of 34 is not exactly
my idea of success.
I'd rather die drunk, broke at 34 and have
people at a dinner table talk about me
than live to be rich and sober at
90 and nobody remembered who I was.
Ah, but your friends will
remember you, that's the point.
None of us were friends
with Charlie Parker.
That's the point.
Travis and Dustin? They have plenty
of friends and plenty of purpose.
I'm sure they'll make great
school board presidents someday.
Oh, that's what this is all about?
You think you're better than us?
You catch on quick. Are you in Model UN?
I got a reply for you, Andrew. You
think Carleton football's a joke?
Come play with us.
Four words you will never
hear from the NFL.
Who wants dessert?
And from Lincoln Center?
Alright guys, get out of here.
Pick up the new chart by
the door on your way out.
Rehearsal 9PM sharp tonight, that's how
long you have till then to learn it.
Neyman, just come over here.
See the tempo marking on there?
Quarter note equals 330
That is a double-time swing.
That's what got you in here right?
Oh yeah.
I recently stumbled across another kid
In the practice room working
on his double time swing.
So I'm gonna give him another shot.
Am I late?
Perfect timing.
Come on in Connelly
You two know each other right?
Yeah, yeah, Nassau band.
Hey, what's up Andrew.
Now Connelly I've made
Neyman a temporary core.
But with this competition
coming up I just wannna make
very sure this chart's in
the best shape it can be.
Yeah it's the one right here right?
I gave Connelly the chart this morning.
All you need to do now is to just give
both of you a crack at it, alright?
So Neyman go ahead jump on the
kit we'll take it from the top.
Ok.
I don't want you to worry about
the hits right now, just tempo.
Ok?
All set?
Not quite my tempo.
-Connelly? -Ok, I'll take.. from the top.
-I can do... -No, we'll
go with Connelly now.
Hey do you mind?
-Ok? -Yeah
Perfect Connelly
See this to me is the
beauty of Studio Band.
You walk in here an alternate, who
knows you could be the new core.
Oh my god, are you serious?
That shit?
Fletcher.
Thanks man.
Don't worry about Fletcher,
he's more bark than bite.
-Hey look, I can play these charts.
-Now's not the time.
-I can play. -I said not now!
If you want the fucking part, earn it.
I'm just gonna lay it out there.
This is why I don't think that
we shouldn't be together.
And I thought about it a lot.
And this is what's gonna happen, ok?
I'm gonna keep pursuing what I'm pursuing
And because I'm doing that it's
gonna take more and more of my time
And I'm not gonna be able to
spend so much time with you.
And when I do spend time with you,
I'll be thinking about drumming.
I'll be thinking about Jazz
and my charts and all that.
And because of that you're
gonna start to resent me.
And you're gonna tell me to ease up
drumming, spend more time with you
because you're not feeling importrant
And I'm not gonna be able to do that.
And I'll just start to resent you for
even asking me to stop drumming.
And we'll just start to hate each other.
And it's gonna get very...
it's gonna be ugly.
And so... for those reasons, I'd
rather just break it off clean.
Cuz I wanna be great.
And you're not?
I wanna be one of the greats.
And I'll stop you from doing that?
Yeah.
You know I'll stop you from doing that.
You know that for a fact.
Yes.
And I barely see you anyway
-Yeah -And when I did see you
you treated me like shit
because I'm just some girl who
doesn't know what she wants
And you have a path, and you're going
to be great, and I'm gonna be forgotten
And therefore, you won't be able
to give me the time and day
because you have bigger things to pursue.
That's exactly my point.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You're right, we should not be dating.
I'm ok, thanks.
Fuck! Fuck!
Fucking piece of shit!
Fuck you! Fuck!
Sorry we have a new player
Ryan Connelly
I'm sorry.
Can you just... put your
instruments down, for a minute?
Just listen for a minute.
Six years ago
I came across a kid in the practice
room working on his scales
He was early second year
and he started in Shaffer
with a lot of hope
Like all you guys.
but the truth was... He barely
squeezed in to begin with and..
He was really struggling.
The faculty were all telling
him, maybe this isn't for you.
But they didn't see what I saw.
That scared, skinny kid,
cursing himself because he
couldn't get the scales right.
I saw a drive in him.
And I put him in Studio Band.
When he graduated
made him the third trumpet
in Lincoln Center.
A year later he was the first.
And that's what you're listening to now.
His name was Sean Casey.
I found out this morning that... Sean
died yesterday.
in a car accident.
And I just...
want you guys to know he
was a beautiful player.
I just thought you should know.
I'm sorry.
Ok.
Let's get to work, how about...
Caravan, bar 105
One and two and
It's not... not quite right Connelly
I'd like to try Neyman on this.
Maybe now is the time for
Neyman to earn the part
One and two and
No, I guess not.
Tanner
One and two and
Motherfucker!
Connelly get your ass back on the kit
We'll stay here for as long as it takes
till one of faggots can play in time.
One and two and
looks like it'll be all night. Neyman.
Not my fucking tempo!
Sorry guys, hate to put you through this
If you need to fucking take a
dump or get a coffee whatever
now might be a good time
because we're gonna stay here until I find
a drummer who can fucking play in time
I apologize to the musicians.
Seriously, take ten, twenty, a fucking hour
You hear me cocksuckers?
You better start shitting me perfect 400
Connelly get your fucking
ass back on the kit
This is really the fastest you can
play, you worthless himey fuck?
No wonder mommy ran out on you.
Get off the fucking kit.
And here comes Mr. Gay pride of
the Upper Western side himself
Unfortunately this is not
a Bette Midler Concert,
we'll not be serving
Cosmopolitan and Baked Alaska
So just play faster than you give
fucking hand jobs, will you please?
One two one two
Not even fucking close
Let's go with the Irish mick
fucking paddy-cracker now
You... you actually do look
quite a bit like a leprechaun
I'll start calling you Flannery
Get off!
What the fuck you looking... there's
not a pot of gold down there
Oh adjusting the seat, really?!
That's been your fucking problem
the whole time? The seat height?
So now you have it right?
Go.
Bullshit! Fuck you!
Neyman.
Maybe, it's time to finally bring
this home, what do you say?
Show me.
Don't slow down!
Pick it up!
Faster!
Keep playing!
Neyman
You earned the part.
Alternates, you wanna clean
the blood off my drum set?
Ok, we can start now.
5pm call tomorrow, in Dunnellen
Give yourself at least two hours to get
there from the city this time alright?
Save your travel receipts.
Or no, I don't give a shit.
Excuse me, do you know where the cabs are?
-You have to call the cabs. -I konw, they
say the cabs suppose to be right here?
No you gotta call them, it'll take forever.
Ok how do I get the Hardrove?
Come on please, come on, you're still open!
You're still open!
Come on, come on!
-Yeah hello? -Where the fuck are you man?
Call time is 5
I know, I know, I'm almost there. I'm
almost there man. I'm right there.
-We're on stage in 20 -I
know we're on stage in 20
-Fletcher got Connelly warming up...
-God fucking damnit!
You just tell that little fucking
redhead I'm gonna be there ok?
Fuck
Hey, Sorry I'm late.
Glad you finished on your
busy schedule, darling.
I know. Look, I'm sorry, but
I'm here man, ready to go.
Connelly's playing the part.
Like fucking hell he's playing my part.
What the fuck did you just say to me?
It's my part.
It's my part, and I
decide who to lend it to.
Usually to somebody that
has fucking sticks.
I left in the car, I'll be right back
-Take me 5 minutes. -I'm
warming up the band now.
-Look I can use Ryan's sticks
-Neyman you lost the fucking part
No I didn't, look you can't
fucking do this to me!
-Can't?! -Yeah!
When did you become a fucking
expert on what I can or cannot do?
You fucking weepy-willow shit sack?
I earned that part.
You never earned anything. God
you're a self-righteous prick
The only reason you are a fucking
core is because you misplaced folder.
The only reason you're in Studio Band
to begin with is because I told you
exactly what I'd be asking for in Nassau
-Am I wrong?  -Yeah
-I'm in Studio Band, cause I'm the..
-Why don't you just back off?!
Hey you, fuck off Johnny
Utah, turn my pages bitch!
Hey, I can cut you any fucking time I want.
You wouldn't cut me by now.
Try me you fucking weasel!
At 5.30, that's exactly 11
minutes, my band is on stage.
If your ass is not on that stool
with your own fucking sticks in hand
Or you make one fucking mistake
One
I'll drum your ass back
to Nassau where you can
turn pages untill you
graduate or fucking drop off.
By the time you are done
at Shaffer, you're gonna
make daddy look like a
fucking successful story
Got it?
Or, we can let Johnny Utah play the part.
You choose.
It's my part, I'll be on your stage.
Fuck... you got ten minutes you
fucking pathetic pansy-ass fruit-fuck
-Hey tell Fletcher I'm coming.
-What took you
so long man, we're moving
on stage right now.
I know I got locked in my car.
It's fine, I'm coming.
"Left turn, 200 feet"
Are you driving man?
-No -What the hell is that noise?
Ok look why don't you just tell Fletcher,
that I am coming you motherfucker!
Are you ok?
-Are you ok? -Yeah I gotta get my sticks.
No no no no, stay away from the car.
-I'm calling 911, it's ok.
-Just a couple more blocks.
Sir, you don't have to...
Shaffer Conservatory, Studio Band.
Neyman, what the fuck?
Neyman
You're done.
Gentlemen and ladies, I apologize
on behalf of Shaffer Conservatory.
I'm gonna fucking kill you!
Get off me!
Fuck you!
Fuck you Fletcher Fuck you!
You fuck... piece of shit!
Fuck you!
When did you start talking to her?
Your father got contacted this week.
Does the name Sean Casey
mean anything to you?
Do you know about his death?
Last month he hung himself
in his apartment.
What's that have to do with me?
Sean suffered from anxiety and depression.
His mother claimed this started during
his time as Fletcher's student.
Now Caseys aren't wealthy,
they don't wanna file suit
So... what do they want?
To make sure that Terrance Fletcher's never
allowed to do this to another student
He didn't do anything.
What's wrong with you? It's over ok?
He's out of your life, why would you let
him get away with what he did to you?
Would you characterize his
conduct as extreme Andrew?
Did he ever intentionally
inflict emotional distress?
This will not be a public
hearing, you know?
Fletcher will never know
it was you who spoke up.
Why would you do this to me?
Do you think that I would let
him put my son through hell
And just walk away scot-free?
Don't you know I would
never let that happen?
That there is nothing in the world
more important to me than you?
Don't you know that?
Andrew?
Just tell me what to say.
-Hi, and... I loaded your pantry
with Gushers. -I saw that.
Thanks
Andrew
Hey
Don't know if you heard...
I'm not in Shaffer any more.
Yeah I did hear that.
Did you quit?
Not exactly.
Some parents got a kid from
Sean Casey's year I think
to say somethings about me.
Although why anybody would
have anything other than
peaches and cream to say
about me is a mystery.
That's a good laugh right?
-I'm sorry. -No I get it.
I know I've made enemies.
I'm conducting though
They brought back JVC fest this year
They got me opening in a couple
of weeks with a pro band.
That's great.
It's alright.
Truth is, I don't think people...
understood what it was I
was doing at Shaffer.
I wasn't there to conduct.
Any fucking moron can wave his
arms and keep people in tempo.
I was there to push people
beyond what's expected of them
I believe that is...
an absolute necessity.
otherwise we're depriving the
world the next Louie Armstrong
the next Charlie Parker.
I told that story about how Charlie
Parker became Charlie Parker
-Jo Jones threw a cymbal at his head.
-Exactly.
Parker was a young kid.
Pretty good on the sax.
Gets up to play in the cutting session
And he fucks it up.
And Jones nearly decapitates him for it.
and he's laughed off-stage
crie himself to sleep that night, but
the next moring, what does he do?
he practices.
and he practices and he
practices, with one goal in mind
never to be laughed at again.
And a year later he goes back to the Reno.
And he steps up on that
stage and he plays the
best motherfucking solo
the world has ever heard.
So imagine if Jones just said.
"Well that's ok Charlie"
"That was alright, good job."
and Charlie thinks to himself
"Well, shit, I did a pretty good job."
End of story.
No bird.
That to me is an absolute tragedy.
But that's just what the world wants now.
People wonder why Jazz is dying
I tell you man
Every Starbucks' Jazz album
just proved my point, really.
There are no two words in English language
more harmful than "good job".
But is there a line?
You know maybe... you go to
far, you discourage next
Charlie Parker from ever
becoming Charlie Parker?
No man, no.
Because the next Charlie Parker
would never be discouraged.
Yeah.
The truth is, Andrew
I never really had a Charlie Parker.
But I tried.
I actually fucking tried.
And that's  more than most people ever do.
and I'll never apologize for how I tried.
Alright, see you later.
Hey Andrew
Listen I have no idea how
you gonna take this, but...
the band I'm leading for JVC
The drummer's not cutting it.
You understand what I'm saying?
-No. -I'm using the Studio Band playlist.
Caravan Whiplash
I need somebody who really
knows these charts.
What about Ryan Connelly?
Ryan Connelly ever was to
me is an incentive for you.
Tanner?
Tanner switched to premed
Guess he got discouraged.
Hey, take the weekend, think about it.
-Hello? -Hey Nicole, it's Andrew.
-Hi -Hey
Been a while since...
I talked to you
Look...
I'm really sorry
about everything, I know that's not...
You know, enough, but... I'm just...
really sorry.
But anyway I got... I actually
have this show this weekend
It's a... JVC thing, I don't
know maybe if you wanna go
it's in Carnegie Hall and.. we.. maybe
get some like.. pizza afterwards
like.. complain about our schools.. again.
What... is that JV?
No, it's JVC, it's like a..
it's Jazz... thing.
Ugh... I don't know if I can come.
I have to check with my boyfriend.
Ok
Yeah
I'll check, but I don't know.
I don't think he likes jazz music.
Yeah, I mean, not for everybody.
Ok, well I guess maybe
I'll see you guys there.
Ok.
Ok, bye.
Alright gangs, listen up.
Now for those of you who are new with this
which looks like might
be everybody except Karl
Tonight can change your life.
The folks out there make a phone call
You can be a blue note signee
An EMC client
A Lincoln Center core
On the other hand, if you drop the ball
you might be looking for a
new line of work because
the other thing about these cats is
they never forget.
We all set?
Alright, let's have fun.
You think I'm fucking stupid?
What?
I know it was you.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen
We're very excited to be here kicking
off the JVC festival this year
I'm Terrance Fletcher, and these are
some of the best musicans in New York
which means some of the best
musicians in the world.
And we're gonna do some old
standard for you but first
we're gonna start out with
a new tone By Tim Simonec
called Upswinging
What the fuck are you doing?!
Come on!
Yeah I guess maybe you don't have it.
Come on, let's go home.
What are you doing?
I'll cue you in!
Caravan.
Three Four!
"FUCK YOU!"
I'll gouge out your motherfucking eye.
Andrew, what're you doing man?
I'll cue you!